<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>regenerative medicine on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/regenerative-medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in regenerative medicine on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 10:44:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/regenerative-medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Liver&#39;s Remarkable Regenerative Prowess</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-the-livers-remarkable-regenerative-prowess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 10:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-the-livers-remarkable-regenerative-prowess/</guid>
      <description>The liver&amp;rsquo;s inherent regenerative capacity is crucial, given its strategic physiological role. After digestion, a mix of nutrients, toxins, and bacterial products is transported to the liver via the portal vein . Essential for detoxifying, metabolizing, and synthesizing, the liver maintains systemic balance. Its ability to regenerate underscores the need for a minimal functional mass for these activities. Studying liver regeneration typically involves surgically removing two-thirds of its mass, triggering its natural repair mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the potential of exosomes for targeted drug delivery and regenerative therapies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/harnessing-potential-exosomes-targeted-drug-delivery-regenerative-therapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/harnessing-potential-exosomes-targeted-drug-delivery-regenerative-therapies/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Harvard University have made groundbreaking strides in the field of regenerative medicine by harnessing the potential of exosomes, tiny vesicles produced by cells, as vehicles for targeted drug delivery and regenerative therapies. Exosomes are known to contain a wide variety of biomolecules, such as proteins and nucleic acids, that can be transferred between cells and help regulate various cellular processes. However, until now, their potential as therapeutic agents has been largely untapped.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
