<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Single Guide Rna Crispr on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/single-guide-rna-crispr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Single Guide Rna Crispr on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:21:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/single-guide-rna-crispr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing Bioengineered Organs-On-Chips For Personalized Drug Testing and Disease Modeling</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/developing-bioengineered-organs-on-chips-for-personalized-drug-testing-and-disease-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/developing-bioengineered-organs-on-chips-for-personalized-drug-testing-and-disease-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Developing bioengineered organs-on-chips for personalized drug testing and disease modeling is a breakthrough discovery that will revolutionize the medical and pharmaceutical industries. Researchers from the University of Melbourne have successfully developed a technique to create miniature organs-on-chips that mimic the functions of real human organs. This innovation can help in the testing of new drugs and treatments, as well as in understanding the mechanisms of different diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The organs-on-chips technology involves creating tiny, engineered devices that replicate the structure and function of human organs on a microscale. These chips are usually made of clear polymer and consist of channels and chambers that mimic the complex 3D structure of the original organ. The channels are lined with human cells and are designed to simulate the physiological conditions of the specific organ. By using microfluidics technology, researchers can precisely control the flow of fluids and nutrients to these chips, which enables them to carry out experiments that would not be feasible in the human body.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
