<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archaeology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/archaeology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archaeology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 09:57:50 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/archaeology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Oldest Realistic Plans of Archaeological Mega-Traps Found in South-East Jordan and Northern Saudi Arabia</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/oldest-realistic-plans-archaeological-mega-traps-found-south-east-jordan-northern-saudi-arabia/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 09:57:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/oldest-realistic-plans-archaeological-mega-traps-found-south-east-jordan-northern-saudi-arabia/</guid>
      <description>El Reyad University in Saudi Arabia, has unveiled the discovery of the oldest realistic plans of archaeological mega-traps for hunting wild animals. The plans, which were engraved on stones, were discovered in south-eastern Jordan and northern Saudi Arabia and date back to around 9,000 years ago making them the oldest of their kind to ever be discovered. These engravings are an extremely precise depiction of neighboring desert kite structures that were dated to the Neolithic era.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strange Relic Excavated in Sumerian City Uruk Depicts Alien Astronauts</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/strange-relic-sumerian-city-uruk-alien-astronauts-2023-jan-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 18:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/strange-relic-sumerian-city-uruk-alien-astronauts-2023-jan-18/</guid>
      <description>Exciting news in the world of archaeology! A strange relic has been excavated in the Sumerian city of Uruk, and it has depictions that strongly resemble alien astronauts. This discovery has once again raised theories of extraterrestrial visits to Earth. The relic was uncovered during a routine dig in the ancient city, and it has caused quite a buzz in the scientific community.
Space ships visits?
Experts have been studying the relic, and they are amazed at the depictions of what they believe to be alien visitors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sumerian Clay Tablet Deciphered Using Specially Trained Chat GPT Model</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/sumerian-clay-tablet-deciphered-using-specially-trained-chat-gpt-model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 21:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/sumerian-clay-tablet-deciphered-using-specially-trained-chat-gpt-model/</guid>
      <description>On January 8, 2023, researchers at Cairo University in Egypt successfully deciphered a Sumerian clay tablet by using a specially trained chat GPT model. The tablet dates back over 4,000 years and contains inscriptions written in cuneiform script, a system of writing used by ancient civilizations in Mesopotamia.
The deciphering process involved inputting the inscriptions into the GPT model, which uses machine learning algorithms to understand and process human language. The GPT model was specifically trained to recognize the unique grammar and syntax of Sumerian cuneiform, making it possible to accurately translate the text.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
