<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chia Seeds on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chia-seeds/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chia Seeds on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:47:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chia-seeds/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The effects of chia seed consumption on reducing mild psoriasis symptoms</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effects-of-chia-seed-consumption-on-reducing-mild-psoriasis-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effects-of-chia-seed-consumption-on-reducing-mild-psoriasis-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psoriasis, a chronic inflammatory skin condition, affects millions of individuals worldwide. While conventional treatments aim to control symptoms, natural dietary supplements are gaining attention for their potential therapeutic effects. This study investigates the impact of chia seed consumption on mild psoriasis symptoms over a 12-week period. Participants consuming chia seeds exhibited a significant reduction in &lt;strong&gt;Psoriasis Area and Severity Index (PASI)&lt;/strong&gt; scores, inflammation markers, and improvements in skin hydration. These findings suggest that chia seeds may serve as a natural, complementary therapy for managing psoriasis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia vs Hemp Seeds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-vs-hemp-seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-vs-hemp-seeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving quest for optimal health and wellness, the spotlight often falls on superfoods, celebrated for their dense nutritional profiles and myriad health benefits. Among the stars of this category, hemp and chia seeds stand out, each boasting a unique array of nutrients that cater to various dietary needs and health objectives. This article delves into a comprehensive comparison of hemp and chia seeds, pitting these nutritional powerhouses against each other to explore their vitamin and mineral content, protein quality, omega-3 fatty acid ratios, and fiber levels. By examining the nuanced differences and similarities between these seeds, we aim to provide a clearer understanding of their individual benefits, helping readers make informed choices about incorporating these superfoods into their daily diets for maximum health impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia seeds vs. Flax seeds: Who wins?</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-seed-v-flax-seeds-who-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-seed-v-flax-seeds-who-wins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- &lt;video width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; controls&gt;&#xA;  &lt;source src=&#34;https://www.ScienceChronicle.org//video/universe.webm&#34; type=&#34;video/webm&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Your browser does not support the video tag.&#xA;&lt;/video&gt;&#xA; --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an ongoing debate online about which seeds are healthier: flax or chia. However, this debate somewhat misses the point, as the concept of &amp;ldquo;healthier&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t one-size-fits-all. For instance, individuals recovering from a marathon and looking to replenish their carbohydrate stores might opt for seeds with a higher calorie content. Conversely, those aiming to lose weight might prefer seeds with fewer calories. Therefore, determining which seed is &amp;ldquo;healthier&amp;rdquo; depends on the intended use of the seeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidation of Estroflavinol&#39;s Mechanism in Estrogen Biosynthesis: A Novel Flavonoid from Chia Seeds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-estroflavinol-estrogen-biosynthesis-tokio-university-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 22:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-estroflavinol-estrogen-biosynthesis-tokio-university-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent discoveries at [Tokio University]9https://www.u-tokyo.ac.jp/en/ have identified a novel flavonoid, Estroflavinol, derived from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chia_seed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;chia seeds&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; (Salvia hispanica L.), which exhibits a direct activation effect on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precursor_%28chemistry%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;precursor molecules&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estrogen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;estrogen&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; hormones. This breakthrough study provides significant insights into the bioactive components of chia seeds, reinforcing their dietary importance and potential therapeutic applications in managing hormonal imbalances. Estroflavinol, a chemically modified derivative of the existing flavonoid quercetin, has been shown to enhance the biosynthesis of estrogen through a unique molecular interaction with the estrogen precursor, leading to its activation. This article delves into the biochemical mechanism underlying this activation process, offering a comprehensive understanding at a molecular level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Oil: A functional food with notable cardiovascular benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chia-oil-and-cardiovascular-health&#34;&gt;Chia Oil and Cardiovascular Health&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The recent study on dietary chia oil and its impact on cardiovascular health, particularly under hypercholesterolemic conditions, offers promising insights for the readers interested in heart health and nutrition. Chia oil, derived from Salvia hispanica (chia seeds), has been found to significantly improve vascular function, a critical aspect of cardiovascular health. This improvement is particularly notable in individuals with high cholesterol levels, a common health concern in today&amp;rsquo;s society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Nutritional Ally in the Fight Against Heart Disease</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the bustling health-food markets of New York, a tiny contender has been making waves: chia seeds. Once known primarily as a staple in ancient diets, recent studies, including a notable one published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Functional Foods,&amp;rdquo; highlight their impressive benefits, especially in cardiovascular health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds are rich in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Omega-3_fatty_acid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;omega-3 fatty acids&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, fibers, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antioxidant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;antioxidants&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. These components play a pivotal role in managing heart health, particularly for women. Post-menopausal women often face increased risks of heart diseases, partly due to changes in lipid metabolism. Incorporating chia seeds into one&amp;rsquo;s diet could be a simple yet effective strategy in this demographic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Found to Contain Compounds Similar to Nootropic Racetams</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-compounds-nootropic-racetams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-compounds-nootropic-racetams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.su.se/cmlink/stockholm-university&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stockholm University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have found that chia seeds contain compounds structurally similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racetam&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;racetams&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, a class of drugs known for their cognitive-enhancing effects. These compounds, when consumed, are believed to act as nootropic agents, potentially improving memory and cognitive function.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, conducted by a team of Swedish researchers, analyzed the chemical composition of chia seeds and found several compounds with similar structures to racetams. These compounds are believed to have potential cognitive-enhancing effects due to their ability to increase blood flow and oxygen uptake in the brain, leading to improved cognitive function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: The Nutritional Powerhouse and Future of Food Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, derived from the plant Salvia hispanica L., have emerged as a significant player in the realm of plant-based nutrition. Their protein, characterized by a well-balanced amino acid profile, stands out not only for its health benefits but also for its environmental sustainability. This balance in amino acids is vital as it closely aligns with human nutritional needs, making chia protein a robust alternative to traditional animal-based proteins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The significance of chia protein extends beyond its nutritional value. In an era where environmental consciousness is paramount, chia cultivation presents a more sustainable option compared to many animal protein sources. Chia plants typically require less water and land resources and have a lower carbon footprint. This environmental efficiency coupled with the health benefits makes chia an attractive ingredient in the plant-based food industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Effects of Chia Seeds on Human Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The exploration of chia seeds&amp;rsquo; influence on diet and health has gained momentum due to their rich nutritional profile. Embedded within this trend is a growing interest in understanding how the incorporation of chia seeds into common foods affects human appetite and blood sugar levels. The specific focus on chia seeds is due to their composition, which includes a high concentration of dietary fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and antioxidants. These components are thought to potentially modulate satiety and glycemic response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Structural Complexity and Biological Potentials of Chia Seed Polysaccharides</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-structural-complexity-and-biological-potentials-of-chia-seed-polysaccharides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-structural-complexity-and-biological-potentials-of-chia-seed-polysaccharides/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The humble chia seed, a product of &lt;em&gt;Salvia hispanica L.&lt;/em&gt;, has long been valued for its rich nutritional profile. In recent scientific advancements, focus has shifted to exploring the intricate structures and potential health benefits of chia seed polysaccharides (CSPs). A detailed study by Zhijun Xiao and all has shed light on one such polysaccharide, CSP-A, revealing its structural intricacies and examining its antioxidant and immunomodulatory activities. This editorial delves deeper into these findings, elucidating the scientific and health implications of CSPs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Bacterial Sinusitis can be Prevented by Daily Nasal Rinsing with Saline Solution, Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chronic bacterial sinusitis is a condition that affects millions of people worldwide, causing discomfort, pain, and other unpleasant symptoms. Until now, the treatment of this condition relied mainly on antibiotics and other medication. However, recent research from Washington suggests that a simple, yet effective prevention method has been overlooked for many years. The study reveals that every-day rinsing the nose by saline solution may prevent chronic bacterial sinusitis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of nasal rinsing using saline solution is not new. It has been used for centuries in Ayurvedic medicine and was popular in Europe during the early 20th century. However, it fell out of favor once antibiotics became widely available. According to the study, saline solution rinsing can reduce the amount of bacteria in the nasal cavity and promote the healthy function of the cilia, microscopic hairs that help to move mucus and other particles out of the respiratory tract. The researchers found that people who rinsed their nose daily with saline had significantly fewer sinus infections and other respiratory problems than those who didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Inflammatory Effect of Chia Seeds Enhanced by Cucumber Juice, Large-Scale Test Reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Canberra, 1st April 2023 - A recent large-scale study conducted by the Australian National University has found that consuming cucumber juice while eating chia seeds enhances the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anti-inflammatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;anti-inflammatory effects&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; of the seeds. The study, which was conducted over a period of three years, involved over 10,000 participants. The results were published in the latest issue of the prestigious &lt;a href=&#34;https://jn.nutrition.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Nutrition&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, which are rich in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webmd.com/healthy-aging/omega-3-fatty-acids-fact-sheet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;omega-3 fatty acids&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, have been lauded for their anti-inflammatory properties. However, until now, their effect had only been studied in isolation. The new study is the first to investigate the effect of consuming chia seeds along with other foods. The researchers found that when chia seeds were consumed together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cucumber_juice&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cucumber juice&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, the anti-inflammatory effect was potentiated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
