<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 10:44:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Liver&#39;s Remarkable Regenerative Prowess</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-the-livers-remarkable-regenerative-prowess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 10:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-the-livers-remarkable-regenerative-prowess/</guid>
      <description>The liver&amp;rsquo;s inherent regenerative capacity is crucial, given its strategic physiological role. After digestion, a mix of nutrients, toxins, and bacterial products is transported to the liver via the portal vein . Essential for detoxifying, metabolizing, and synthesizing, the liver maintains systemic balance. Its ability to regenerate underscores the need for a minimal functional mass for these activities. Studying liver regeneration typically involves surgically removing two-thirds of its mass, triggering its natural repair mechanisms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: The Nutritional Powerhouse and Future of Food Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds, derived from the plant Salvia hispanica L., have emerged as a significant player in the realm of plant-based nutrition. Their protein, characterized by a well-balanced amino acid profile, stands out not only for its health benefits but also for its environmental sustainability. This balance in amino acids is vital as it closely aligns with human nutritional needs, making chia protein a robust alternative to traditional animal-based proteins.
The significance of chia protein extends beyond its nutritional value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Effects of Chia Seeds on Human Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</guid>
      <description>The exploration of chia seeds&amp;rsquo; influence on diet and health has gained momentum due to their rich nutritional profile. Embedded within this trend is a growing interest in understanding how the incorporation of chia seeds into common foods affects human appetite and blood sugar levels. The specific focus on chia seeds is due to their composition, which includes a high concentration of dietary fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and antioxidants. These components are thought to potentially modulate satiety and glycemic response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Structural Complexity and Biological Potentials of Chia Seed Polysaccharides</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-structural-complexity-and-biological-potentials-of-chia-seed-polysaccharides/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-structural-complexity-and-biological-potentials-of-chia-seed-polysaccharides/</guid>
      <description>The humble chia seed, a product of Salvia hispanica L., has long been valued for its rich nutritional profile. In recent scientific advancements, focus has shifted to exploring the intricate structures and potential health benefits of chia seed polysaccharides (CSPs). A detailed study by Zhijun Xiao and all has shed light on one such polysaccharide, CSP-A, revealing its structural intricacies and examining its antioxidant and immunomodulatory activities. This editorial delves deeper into these findings, elucidating the scientific and health implications of CSPs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of zumba exercise on menstrual pain relief</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</guid>
      <description>Menstrual pain, or dysmenorrhea, is a common issue affecting many women worldwide. While various treatments exist, ranging from medication to alternative therapies, an intriguing approach has emerged: Zumba exercise. A recent study conducted by Ahmed Samy et al. delved into this aspect, offering fascinating insights.
The Study The study titled &amp;ldquo;The Effect of Zumba Exercise on Reducing Menstrual Pain in Young Women with Primary Dysmenorrhea: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&amp;rdquo; aimed to evaluate the impact of Zumba on menstrual pain severity and duration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASMR Has Many Physiological Effects, Including the Potential to Heal Serious Illnesses Through Psychosomatic Effects</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/asmr-has-many-physiological-effects-potential-to-heal-serious-illnesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 23:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/asmr-has-many-physiological-effects-potential-to-heal-serious-illnesses/</guid>
      <description>Recent research conducted by the University of Cambridge has shown that Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response (ASMR), a tingling sensation often triggered by certain visual or auditory stimuli in susceptible individuals, can have various physiological effects. The study found that ASMR had positive impacts on heart rate, respiration, and neurotransmitters, leading to lower stress levels and improved overall well-being.
Additionally, the psychosomatic effects of ASMR have been noted, with some individuals reporting relief from chronic pain and even serious illnesses such as depression and anxiety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.
Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Aromatherapy on Menstrual pain</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-impact-of-aromatherapy-on-menstrual-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-impact-of-aromatherapy-on-menstrual-pain/</guid>
      <description>Menstrual pain, or dysmenorrhea, is a prevalent condition affecting a significant percentage of women globally. Traditional treatments range from non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) to hormonal contraceptives, each with its own set of potential side effects and limitations. In recent years, aromatherapy has emerged as a promising alternative. This editorial explores the efficacy and safety of aromatherapy in managing menstrual pain, drawing on data from a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis detailed in a study published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Clinical Medicine&amp;rdquo; (J Clin Med 2018 November 10;7(11)).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene&#39;s Promising Result in Treating Breast Cancer</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/lycopene-promising-result-in-treating-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 09:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/lycopene-promising-result-in-treating-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>Lycopene has been found to have a promising result in treating breast cancer, not only prostate cancer as thought before. Researchers at the Walter and Eliza Hall Institute of Medical Research have recently discovered that lycopene, a naturally occurring chemical found in red fruits and vegetables, has the potential to significantly inhibit the growth of breast cancer cells.
This discovery overturns previous beliefs that lycopene was primarily beneficial for prostate cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutin health effects</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutin-health-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutin-health-effects/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The present-day scientific community now acknowledges flavonoids as a distinct category of therapeutic molecules owing to their varied therapeutic properties. Among these, rutin, alternatively known as vitamin P or rutoside, has been investigated for numerous pharmacological effects. Rutin is found in tea leaves, apples, and various other sources as one of its active constituents. Currently, rutin is recognized for its nutraceutical impact. This post emphasizes the latest information on rutin and its health-promoting effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Alaska Rhodiola: New Research from the Karolinska Institute</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-benefits-of-alaska-rhodiola-new-research-karolinska-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-benefits-of-alaska-rhodiola-new-research-karolinska-institute/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Karolinska Institute have been studying the benefits of Alaska Rhodiola for a number of different health conditions, and the results are very promising. Rhodiola is a plant that grows in the wild, and it has been used for centuries in traditional medicine in Russia, Scandinavia, and other parts of the world. The active ingredients in Rhodiola have been shown to have a number of different effects on the body, including reducing fatigue, boosting mood, and improving cognitive function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Chia Seeds Per Day to Lose Weight</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine have recently conducted a study to determine the optimal amount of chia seeds to consume daily for weight loss. Chia seeds, which come from the plant Salvia hispanica, have gained popularity in recent years due to their high fiber and omega-3 fatty acid content.
The study, which was published in the Journal of Nutrition, involved 100 participants who were divided into two groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Link Between Physical Exercise, Colrabi Consumption, and Reduced Risk of Diverticulosis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-link-between-physical-exercise-colrabi-consumption-and-reduced-risk-of-diverticulosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-link-between-physical-exercise-colrabi-consumption-and-reduced-risk-of-diverticulosis/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at New York University has found that diverticulosis, a common condition that affects the colon, can be prevented by performing physical exercises and following a diet enriched with colrabi. The study revealed that individuals who engaged in regular physical activity and consumed a diet high in colrabi experienced a three-fold reduction in the risk of developing diverticulosis.
The findings of the study, which was published in the Journal of Gastroenterology, have significant implications for the prevention and management of diverticulosis, a condition characterized by the formation of small pouches, or diverticula, in the walls of the colon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Buckwheat in the Diet for Colon Cancer Patients</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted by researchers at Vienna University has found that including buckwheat in the diet of colon cancer patients is crucial due to its high daily value of magnesium, which is a required component in colon cancer immunity. The study, published in the International Journal of Cancer Research , highlights the importance of incorporating buckwheat into the diet of colon cancer patients in order to enhance their immune system&amp;rsquo;s ability to fight cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Salt-Kidney Connection: How Your Salt Habits Impact Chronic Kidney Disease Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</guid>
      <description>Scientists have discovered a link between the frequency of salt intake in food and an increased risk of chronic kidney disease (CKD). The research findings were published in the JAMA Network Open journal.
Experts analyzed data from 465,288 participants in the long-term UK Biobank study, aged 37 to 73 years, who initially did not have CKD. They were divided into several categories based on self-reported frequency of salt intake (never, rarely, occasionally, usually, and always).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the potential of exosomes for targeted drug delivery and regenerative therapies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/harnessing-potential-exosomes-targeted-drug-delivery-regenerative-therapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/harnessing-potential-exosomes-targeted-drug-delivery-regenerative-therapies/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Harvard University have made groundbreaking strides in the field of regenerative medicine by harnessing the potential of exosomes, tiny vesicles produced by cells, as vehicles for targeted drug delivery and regenerative therapies. Exosomes are known to contain a wide variety of biomolecules, such as proteins and nucleic acids, that can be transferred between cells and help regulate various cellular processes. However, until now, their potential as therapeutic agents has been largely untapped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato seeds may help combat varicose veins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</guid>
      <description>Recent research at the University of Seoul has identified a number of components within tomato seeds that have the potential to combat varicose veins. Varicose veins are a common problem that can lead to discomfort and even serious complications if left untreated. The condition is caused by weakened vein walls that allow blood to pool and form bulges, typically in the legs and feet.
The research team focused on the potential of tomato seeds, which are often discarded as waste, to provide therapeutic benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individually Adjusted Diet of Vitamin C-Containing Fruits Boosts Immune System against Antibiotic-Resistant Bacteria</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/individually-adjusted-diet-vitamin-c-containing-fruits-boosts-immune-system-antibiotic-resistant-bacteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/individually-adjusted-diet-vitamin-c-containing-fruits-boosts-immune-system-antibiotic-resistant-bacteria/</guid>
      <description>In a recent study conducted in New Orleans, it has been found that an individually adjusted diet of vitamin C-containing fruits can significantly boost the immune system against antibiotic-resistant bacteria and yeast infections. Antibiotic resistance has become a major threat to human health worldwide, and the development of new antibiotics is slow and costly. Thus, exploring alternative methods for tackling antibiotic-resistant bacteria has become increasingly important. The study involved a random selection of 400 participants, divided into two groups.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
