<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Bone Health on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/bone-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Bone Health on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:17:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/bone-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Master Your Vitamin Knowledge: Essential Nutrients Unveiled</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/master-your-vitamin-knowledge-essential-nutrients-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/master-your-vitamin-knowledge-essential-nutrients-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embark on a journey through the vibrant and essential universe of vitamins with our comprehensive quiz. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a nutrition enthusiast, a health professional, or simply curious about how vitamins influence bodily functions, this quiz is designed to enrich your understanding and test your knowledge. From the roles of vitamins in energy metabolism and immune support to their importance in preventing deficiency diseases, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover fascinating facts and gain insights into maintaining optimal health through nutrition. Ready to challenge yourself and become a vitamin virtuoso? Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What is worse, osteoarthritis or osteoporosis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/what-is-worse-osteoarthritis-or-osteoporosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 13:15:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/what-is-worse-osteoarthritis-or-osteoporosis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Determining which condition is worse between osteoarthritis and osteoporosis involves delving into the complexities of both diseases, their impact on individuals&amp;rsquo; health, quality of life, and the broader implications for public health. This comprehensive analysis aims to explore the pathological differences, symptomatic burdens, and societal impacts of osteoarthritis and osteoporosis, shedding light on the nuanced debate of which condition could be deemed &amp;ldquo;worse.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;understanding-osteoarthritis-and-osteoporosis&#34;&gt;Understanding Osteoarthritis and Osteoporosis&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis is a degenerative joint disorder characterized by the breakdown of cartilage, the rubbery material that cushions the ends of bones within joints. This degeneration leads to pain, stiffness, swelling, and reduced mobility in affected joints, most commonly affecting the knees, hips, hands, and spine. The primary symptoms are joint pain and stiffness, especially after periods of rest or physical activity, which can progressively worsen, leading to significant discomfort and functional limitations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bone Health and Disorders Related to Bone Metabolism</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/bone-health-and-disorders-related-to-bone-metabolism/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 01:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/bone-health-and-disorders-related-to-bone-metabolism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;fundamental-aspects-of-bone-function&#34;&gt;Fundamental Aspects of Bone Function&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The dynamic nature of bone is characterized by ongoing cycles of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bone_resorption&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bone breakdown&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Osteoclast&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;osteoclasts&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ossification&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bone formation&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; by &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Osteoblast&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;osteoblasts&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; within specific &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bone_remodeling&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bone remodelling&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; compartments. Annually, approximately 10% of an adult&amp;rsquo;s bone mass undergoes this remodelling, which is crucial for both preserving bone strength and managing the body&amp;rsquo;s calcium levels.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;table&gt;&#xA;  &lt;thead&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;th&gt;Calcium homeostasis and bone formation / resorption&lt;/th&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/thead&gt;&#xA;  &lt;tbody&gt;&#xA;      &lt;tr&gt;&#xA;          &lt;td&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/bone-health-and-disorders-related-to-bone-metabolism/ca.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;calcium&#34;&gt;&lt;/td&gt;&#xA;      &lt;/tr&gt;&#xA;  &lt;/tbody&gt;&#xA;&lt;/table&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This remodelling process is a balanced sequence where bone resorption precedes bone formation. The regulation of osteoclastic activity, and thereby bone remodelling, is influenced by various systemic hormones and inflammatory substances, which operate through the synthesis of both &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RANKL&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;bone-resorbing RANK‐ligand (RANKL)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and bone-protecting &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Osteoprotegerin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;osteoprotegerin&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; by bone cells like osteocytes and osteoblasts. Discoveries in the regulatory mechanisms of osteoblasts are advancing, highlighting the significance of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wnt_signaling_pathway&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Wnt signaling pathway&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and its inhibitors, such as sclerostin, which hold potential for developing new treatment strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Osteoarthritis vs. Rheumatoid Arthritis: Understanding the Key Differences</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/osteoarthritis-vs-rheumatoid-arthritis-understanding-the-key-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 14:36:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/osteoarthritis-vs-rheumatoid-arthritis-understanding-the-key-differences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) and Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA) are two of the most common forms of arthritis that affect millions worldwide. While both conditions share the symptom of joint pain, their causes, affected populations, disease progression, and treatments differ significantly. Understanding these differences is crucial for diagnosis, management, and improving patients&amp;rsquo; quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;etiology-and-pathophysiology&#34;&gt;Etiology and Pathophysiology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Osteoarthritis&lt;/strong&gt; is primarily a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Osteoarthritis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;degenerative joint disease&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; characterized by the breakdown of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cartilage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cartilage&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, the tough but flexible tissue that cushions the ends of bones within joints. Over time, the wear and tear on cartilage can result in bone grinding directly on bone, leading to pain and restricted movement. OA is often considered a disease of aging, with the majority of cases occurring in individuals over the age of 65. However, younger people can develop osteoarthritis from joint injuries or repeated stress on certain joints, obesity being a notable risk factor due to increased mechanical stress on the joints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Small Seed with Big Health Implications</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, traditionally known for their nutritional value, have recently been spotlighted in a scientific study for their potential in combating diet-induced obesity and its complications. The study, published in &amp;ldquo;Nutrition,&amp;rdquo; delves into how chia seeds and chia oil affect &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_shock_protein&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;heat shock proteins (HSP)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and related parameters in obese rats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study&amp;rsquo;s objective was to investigate chia&amp;rsquo;s effects on HSP and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glucose_tolerance_test&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;glucose tolerance&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in obese rats. It was observed that a diet high in fat and fructose, mimicking human obesity, adversely affected glucose tolerance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insulin_resistance&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;insulin resistance&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, and induced oxidative stress. Interestingly, the inclusion of chia seeds and chia oil in this diet led to significant health improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://einsteinmed.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Albert Einstein College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
