<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:49:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Much Chia Seeds Per Day to Lose Weight</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine have recently conducted a study to determine the optimal amount of chia seeds to consume daily for weight loss. Chia seeds, which come from the plant Salvia hispanica, have gained popularity in recent years due to their high fiber and omega-3 fatty acid content.
The study, which was published in the Journal of Nutrition, involved 100 participants who were divided into two groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Approach to Health Problems and Life Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/scientific-approach-to-health-problems-and-life-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/scientific-approach-to-health-problems-and-life-extension/</guid>
      <description>A scientific approach to health problems gives a huge advantage in managing lifestyle which finally leads to life extension of those who adhere to the approach. A recent study conducted at the University of Manchester&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Biology, Medicine, and Health has revealed the significant impact that a scientific approach to health can have on life expectancy.
The study, led by Dr. Elizabeth Johnson, focused on the relationship between adherence to a scientific approach to health and longevity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy Simulated Without Complex Machinery</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy-simulated-without-complex-machinery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 01:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy-simulated-without-complex-machinery/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at The Johns Hopkins Hospital have made a groundbreaking discovery in the field of hyperbaric oxygen therapy . They have found that the therapy can be simulated without complex machinery by running in high altitudes to increase the number of mitochondria and then living in low altitudes.
The study, published in the Journal of Experimental Biology , found that running in high altitudes can increase the number of mitochondria in the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Salt-Kidney Connection: How Your Salt Habits Impact Chronic Kidney Disease Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</guid>
      <description>Scientists have discovered a link between the frequency of salt intake in food and an increased risk of chronic kidney disease (CKD). The research findings were published in the JAMA Network Open journal.
Experts analyzed data from 465,288 participants in the long-term UK Biobank study, aged 37 to 73 years, who initially did not have CKD. They were divided into several categories based on self-reported frequency of salt intake (never, rarely, occasionally, usually, and always).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.
Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Calorie Intake Reduces Risk of Cancer and Metabolic Syndrome, MIT Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/reducing-calorie-intake-reduces-risk-cancer-metabolic-syndrome-mit-study-finds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/reducing-calorie-intake-reduces-risk-cancer-metabolic-syndrome-mit-study-finds/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have found that reducing the calorie intake to the level of calorie restriction significantly reduces the risk of cancer and metabolic syndrome. The study, which was conducted on mice, showed that mice on a calorie-restricted diet had less inflammation and oxidative stress within their bodies, which are known to be markers of disease. The findings were published today in the journal Nature Communications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bees Social Interaction: Revealing the Social Engineering Techniques</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/bees-social-interaction-revealing-the-social-engineering-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/bees-social-interaction-revealing-the-social-engineering-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Bees are known for their complex social interactions that includes social engineering techniques. A new study conducted at Seoul University has shed light on some of the ways in which bees use social engineering to maintain their hives and ensure the survival of their colonies. The findings of the study were published in the Journal of Insect Behaviour on 12th May 2023.
The study was conducted by a team of researchers led by Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato seeds may help combat varicose veins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</guid>
      <description>Recent research at the University of Seoul has identified a number of components within tomato seeds that have the potential to combat varicose veins. Varicose veins are a common problem that can lead to discomfort and even serious complications if left untreated. The condition is caused by weakened vein walls that allow blood to pool and form bulges, typically in the legs and feet.
The research team focused on the potential of tomato seeds, which are often discarded as waste, to provide therapeutic benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Epigenetic Evolution is a Main Evolutionary Mechanism in Water Bears, According to Recent study at University of Tokyo</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/epigenetic-evolution-main-mechanism-water-bears-university-tokyo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:44:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/epigenetic-evolution-main-mechanism-water-bears-university-tokyo/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at the University of Tokyo has indicated that epigenetic evolution plays a crucial role in water bear&amp;rsquo;s evolutionary mechanisms. Water bears, also known as tardigrades, are microscopic animals that have the ability to survive in extreme environments, including high temperatures, pressure, and radiation. This study reveals that water bears have a unique way to alter their gene expression in response to environmental changes, and that such changes can be passed on to future generations without altering the DNA sequence.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Antiaging Drug Modifying TOR Pathway of Immuno System Stem Cells Significantly Increases Lifespan of Mice and Rabbits, with a Promise for Human Aging Treatment</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-antiaging-drug-modifying-tor-pathway-immuno-system-stem-cells-increases-lifespan-mice-rabbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-antiaging-drug-modifying-tor-pathway-immuno-system-stem-cells-increases-lifespan-mice-rabbits/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at Ottawa University reveals a promising new anti-aging drug that modifies the TOR pathway of immunosystem stem cells, leading to a significant increase in the lifespan of mice and rabbits. The study shows that stem cells&amp;rsquo; unique ability to regenerate different types of cells in the body plays a critical role in aging. While stem cells can divide indefinitely, they also have a limited lifespan, leading to a decline in cellular function and ultimately, death.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Groundbreaking Discovery: Ottawa Scientists Unearth New Soil Microbe Species Thriving 3 Kilometers Below Earth&#39;s Surface</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/ottawa-scientists-discover-new-soil-microbe-species-3-kilometers-below-surface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:36:37 +0300</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/ottawa-scientists-discover-new-soil-microbe-species-3-kilometers-below-surface/</guid>
      <description>Ottawa, May 16, 2023 - In a groundbreaking scientific breakthrough, researchers from Ottawa have announced the discovery of a previously unknown soil microbe species that exists in the extreme depths of the Earth. Thriving an astonishing 3 kilometers below the surface, this newly identified microbe has been named &amp;ldquo;Subterraneus ottawensis&amp;rdquo; in honor of its subterranean habitat and the diligent researchers who unveiled its existence.
This extraordinary finding comes as a result of an extensive scientific expedition led by a team of microbiologists and geologists from Ottawa University.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
