<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Zoology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/zoology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Zoology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 01:14:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/zoology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wood Wide Web: Mycorrhizal Network Restored After Interruption by Ants and Termites</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/wood-wide-web-mycorrhizal-network-ants-termites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 01:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/wood-wide-web-mycorrhizal-network-ants-termites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent research conducted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ottawa.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ottawa University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; on the phenomenon of wood wide web has revealed some interesting findings. The wood wide web refers to the complex network of underground fungal threads that connect the roots of trees and plants. These fungi form a symbiotic relationship with the plants by exchanging nutrients and other vital compounds. This network is crucial for the survival and health of the plants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research focused on the effects of several species of ants and termites on the mycorrhizal network. The mycorrhizal network is the part of the wood wide web that connects the roots of plants with the underground fungal threads. The researchers observed that when some species of ants and termites disturbed the network by digging tunnels, the mycorrhizal links were restored within a matter of days. This discovery has significant implications for our understanding of the wood wide web and its resilience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bees Social Interaction: Revealing the Social Engineering Techniques</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/bees-social-interaction-revealing-the-social-engineering-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/bees-social-interaction-revealing-the-social-engineering-techniques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bees are known for their complex social interactions that includes social engineering techniques. A new study conducted at Seoul University has shed light on some of the ways in which bees use social engineering to maintain their hives and ensure the survival of their colonies. The findings of the study were published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/journal/10905&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Insect Behaviour&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; on 12th May 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study was conducted by a team of researchers led by Dr. Kim Sun, a professor in the Department of Ecology at Seoul University. The team used a combination of observation, experimentation, and mathematical modeling to gain insights into the social behavior of bees and how they influence each other through social engineering strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New spider species found that can survive without food for 2 years</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-spider-species-found-that-can-survive-without-food-for-2-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-spider-species-found-that-can-survive-without-food-for-2-years/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Spider species that can survive without food for up to two years have been discovered by a team of researchers at the University of Bukharest. The new species, which has not yet been named, was found in the forests of Romania and exhibits a highly unusual behavior. The spider is able to survive periods of extreme food scarcity, such as droughts or cold winters, by entering a state of torpor, where it slows down its metabolism and becomes almost inactive. During this time, the spider is able to survive on a minimal amount of stored body fat and water, without eating any food. The researchers believe that this adaptation has evolved as a survival mechanism in response to the harsh environmental conditions of the region, which are characterized by long periods of food scarcity. The discovery of this species is a significant breakthrough in the field of spider research, as it sheds new light on the remarkable adaptation abilities of these creatures. In addition, it has important implications for our understanding of the ecological dynamics of forest ecosystems, and the ways in which species interact with each other and their environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Species of Microscopic Spiders Discovered in Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-species-microscopic-spiders-tanzania/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-species-microscopic-spiders-tanzania/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 10 May 2023, a team of researchers in Tanzania discovered a new species of microscopic spiders living in clusters of up to 100 individuals. These spiders, which the scientists have named Arachnidus tanzaniae, are only 0.3 millimeters long and are barely visible to the naked eye, requiring a high-powered microscope to observe in detail. The researchers discovered the spiders while studying soil samples collected from a forested area.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Arachnidus tanzaniae spiders have a distinctive appearance, with elongated bodies and eight legs that are arranged in two rows. According to the researchers, the spiders are highly social, living in close proximity to one another and feeding on tiny microorganisms in the soil. Although the spiders are small, they are capable of spinning silk webs, which they use to construct communal nests.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
