<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>zoology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/zoology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in zoology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 01:14:16 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/zoology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Wood Wide Web: Mycorrhizal Network Restored After Interruption by Ants and Termites</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/wood-wide-web-mycorrhizal-network-ants-termites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 01:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/wood-wide-web-mycorrhizal-network-ants-termites/</guid>
      <description>A recent research conducted by Ottawa University on the phenomenon of wood wide web has revealed some interesting findings. The wood wide web refers to the complex network of underground fungal threads that connect the roots of trees and plants. These fungi form a symbiotic relationship with the plants by exchanging nutrients and other vital compounds. This network is crucial for the survival and health of the plants.
The research focused on the effects of several species of ants and termites on the mycorrhizal network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bees Social Interaction: Revealing the Social Engineering Techniques</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/bees-social-interaction-revealing-the-social-engineering-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/bees-social-interaction-revealing-the-social-engineering-techniques/</guid>
      <description>Bees are known for their complex social interactions that includes social engineering techniques. A new study conducted at Seoul University has shed light on some of the ways in which bees use social engineering to maintain their hives and ensure the survival of their colonies. The findings of the study were published in the Journal of Insect Behaviour on 12th May 2023.
The study was conducted by a team of researchers led by Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New spider species found that can survive without food for 2 years</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-spider-species-found-that-can-survive-without-food-for-2-years/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:45:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-spider-species-found-that-can-survive-without-food-for-2-years/</guid>
      <description>Spider species that can survive without food for up to two years have been discovered by a team of researchers at the University of Bukharest. The new species, which has not yet been named, was found in the forests of Romania and exhibits a highly unusual behavior. The spider is able to survive periods of extreme food scarcity, such as droughts or cold winters, by entering a state of torpor, where it slows down its metabolism and becomes almost inactive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Species of Microscopic Spiders Discovered in Tanzania</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-species-microscopic-spiders-tanzania/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:45:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-species-microscopic-spiders-tanzania/</guid>
      <description>On 10 May 2023, a team of researchers in Tanzania discovered a new species of microscopic spiders living in clusters of up to 100 individuals. These spiders, which the scientists have named Arachnidus tanzaniae, are only 0.3 millimeters long and are barely visible to the naked eye, requiring a high-powered microscope to observe in detail. The researchers discovered the spiders while studying soil samples collected from a forested area.
The Arachnidus tanzaniae spiders have a distinctive appearance, with elongated bodies and eight legs that are arranged in two rows.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
