<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:31:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Psychosomatic Reason for Psoriasis: Emotional Coldness of Parents</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/psychosomatic-reason-for-psoriasis-emotional-coldness-of-parents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2024 16:31:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/psychosomatic-reason-for-psoriasis-emotional-coldness-of-parents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking study conducted by researchers at Oslo University has revealed a potential psychosomatic reason for the development of psoriasis. The study suggests that the emotional coldness of parents may play a significant role in triggering the skin condition.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research, led by Dr. Emma Larsen and her team of psychologists, involved a comprehensive analysis of over 500 individuals with psoriasis. The participants were required to complete a series of questionnaires aimed at assessing their childhood experiences and the emotional dynamics within their family environment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Warm and Cold Spectrum Colors on Emotional Responses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/the-impact-of-warm-and-cold-spectrum-colors-on-emotional-responses/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 20:18:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/the-impact-of-warm-and-cold-spectrum-colors-on-emotional-responses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uchicago.edu/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Chicago University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has revealed that filling coloring books with saturated colors in the warm spectrum has a stronger calming effect on individuals with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Social_anxiety_disorder&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;social phobia&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, while using colors in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_temperature&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cold spectrum&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has a stronger effect on impulsive individuals. The research, led by Dr. Elizabeth Rodriguez and her team, aimed to explore the impact of color choices on the emotional responses of people with different psychological profiles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The form of a woman&#39;sbreast can be a defining factor in chosing a future wife </title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/form-of-woman-breast-can-be-a-defining-factor-in-choosing-a-wife-the-decision-may-be-defined-on-the-basis-of-mother-breast-of-a-man/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/form-of-woman-breast-can-be-a-defining-factor-in-choosing-a-wife-the-decision-may-be-defined-on-the-basis-of-mother-breast-of-a-man/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study conducted by Dublin University has revealed that the form of a woman&amp;rsquo;s breast can be a defining factor in choosing a future wife for men. The researchers found that men tend to prefer women whose breast shape resembles that of their own mother&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, which was published in the Journal of Evolutionary Psychology, surveyed 1,000 men on their breast shape preferences in potential partners. It found that 65% of men preferred women with breasts that were the same shape as their mother&amp;rsquo;s, while the remaining 35% did not have a preference.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With prolonged, focused and life-devotion training any pain can be controlled by consciousness mind</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/with-prolonged-focused-and-life-devotion-training-any-pain-can-be-controlled-by-conciousness-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/with-prolonged-focused-and-life-devotion-training-any-pain-can-be-controlled-by-conciousness-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dublin University&amp;rsquo;s latest research has shown that with prolonged, focused and life-devotion training, any pain can be controlled by the conscious mind. This ground-breaking discovery has implications for the medical world, psychology, and philosophy.&#xA;The study was initiated by the University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Psychology, and the results were published today in the prestigious scientific journal, Nature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The researchers worked with a group of volunteers who had undergone an intensive course of meditation and mindfulness. Their results show that the volunteers had developed an incredible ability to control their own pain levels through the use of their minds alone. This ability was measured scientifically using brain scans, which showed a significant difference in the way the brain responded to pain stimuli compared to the control group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Masturbation and Subsequent Sperm Eating Prone Among Lonely, Highly Intelligent, and Unsafe Persons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/masturbation-and-subsequent-sperm-eating-prone-among-lonely-highly-intelligent-and-unsafe-persons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 23:16:15 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/masturbation-and-subsequent-sperm-eating-prone-among-lonely-highly-intelligent-and-unsafe-persons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent research conducted in Atlanta, USA, has revealed a major concern regarding masturbation and subsequent sperm eating that is prone among lonely, highly intelligent, and unsafe individuals. According to the study, people who have high levels of intelligence and feel deprived of social interactions tend to indulge in this act on a regular basis. Such behavior puts them at risk of developing severe emotional and psychological disorders.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This research involved more than 1,000 individuals from different backgrounds, age groups, and gender ratios. It was found that those who engaged in masturbation and sperm eating were more likely to experience feelings of loneliness, anxiety, and depression, as well as an increased risk of developing psychological disorders, including bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, and borderline personality disorder. Furthermore, these individuals often failed to establish meaningful relationships, which further contributed to their loneliness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychosomatic Effect Can Help Correct Physical Impairments, Say Researchers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/psychosomatic-effect-physical-impairment-research-vilnus-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/psychosomatic-effect-physical-impairment-research-vilnus-university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking research conducted at Vilnus University has found that the psychosomatic effect can be used to correct any physiological impairment. According to the study, our thoughts and emotions can have a profound effect on our physical well-being. The researchers believe that this discovery could pave the way for new and innovative therapies for a range of conditions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, which was published in the International Journal of Psychosomatics, involved a series of experiments that examined the link between the mind and the body. The researchers found that participants who received positive feedback and believed in the power of their own bodies were able to improve their physical health in a significant way.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Positive Thinking Has a Real Healing Effect on the Body, Study Finds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/positive-thinking-healing-effect-study-finds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:36:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/positive-thinking-healing-effect-study-finds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Positive thinking has always been considered an essential aspect of personal development. However, recent studies conducted by researchers at the University of Vancouver have shown that it can also have a real healing effect on the body, allowing people suffering from various diseases to find relief by simply thinking positively.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research team studied a group of volunteers suffering from chronic back pain, and found that those who were instructed to practice positive thinking techniques experienced a significant reduction in their symptoms. By using techniques such as cognitive restructuring, visualization and positive affirmations, the volunteers were able to not only find relief from their physical pain, but also improve their mental health and overall quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puzzles Increase Cognitive Abilities in All Ages</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/puzzles-increase-cognitive-abilities-in-all-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/puzzles-increase-cognitive-abilities-in-all-ages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cognitive abilities are gaining more attention due to the rapid growth of knowledge and technology that requires a high level of problem-solving skills, creative thinking, and decision-making. Puzzles are one of the most effective and enjoyable ways to enhance cognitive abilities. This research aimed to investigate the impact of puzzles on cognitive abilities across different ages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research was carried out at Cairo University, Egypt, during March 2023. The sample size included 100 subjects of different ages and backgrounds. The participants were divided into four groups based on their ages; children (6-12), teens (13-18), adults (19-60), and seniors (above 60). Each group was exposed to a series of puzzle-solving activities for one month, three times per week, and one hour each session. The puzzles varied in their types, such as jigsaw, crossword, riddles, and logic puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Being Calm Can Never Harm Person Effectiveness in Mental Job Performance</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/being-calm-never-harm-person-effectiveness-mental-job-performance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 01:42:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/being-calm-never-harm-person-effectiveness-mental-job-performance/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study published in Nature Communications on December 17th, 2022 shows that being calm can never harm one&amp;rsquo;s effectiveness in mental job performance. The study was conducted on a diverse group of individuals, including executives, scientists, and academics to determine whether remaining calm under pressure can lead to better mental job performance. Participants in the study were assessed on their ability to solve complex problems, recall information and think creatively while remaining calm under pressure. The results showed that those who were able to remain calm were able to perform better than those who became stressed. Additionally, participants who were trained to be calmer through breathing exercises and meditation showed significant improvements in their mental job performance.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
