<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mulberry Extract for Skin on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/mulberry-extract-for-skin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mulberry Extract for Skin on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 02:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/mulberry-extract-for-skin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Mulberry Fruit Extracts on Skin Aging: Comprehensive Assessments of Their Role in Hindering Glycation and Enhancing Antioxidant Functions, Both in Lab Tests and Real-World Applications.</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/mulberry-extracts-anti-aging-antiglycation-antioxidant-evaluations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/mulberry-extracts-anti-aging-antiglycation-antioxidant-evaluations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Mulberry, a versatile agricultural product, is recognized for its health-promoting qualities and is a subject of extensive research as a beneficial health food. This fruit, along with its leaves, twigs, and roots, is packed with active compounds. Analysis has revealed that mulberry fruit primarily comprises two key functional components: polyphenols and polysaccharides, known for their antioxidant, anti-inflammatory, anti-cancer, memory-enhancing, and neuroprotective effects. Mulberry fruit extracts are particularly noted for their phenolic substances, which boost antioxidant enzyme activity and help slow down memory loss in aging by aiding the removal of amyloid-β. Moreover, mulberries are abundant in water-soluble bioactive components known as anthocyanins, which have been shown to decelerate aging and mitigate age-related conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
