<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neurology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/neurology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neurology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/neurology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Blooms and Brains: How Floral Beauty Enhances Neural Plasticity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/article/blooms-and-brains-how-floral-beauty-enhances-neural-plasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/article/blooms-and-brains-how-floral-beauty-enhances-neural-plasticity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ever wondered why a simple walk through a garden full of blooming flowers feels so refreshing and invigorating? It&amp;rsquo;s not just the beauty that captivates our senses, but also a profound interaction happening inside our brains. Welcome to the world of neural plasticity – the brain&amp;rsquo;s incredible ability to reorganize itself by forming new neural connections throughout life. And guess what? This miraculous process can be beautifully supported by the aesthetic pleasure we derive from flowers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Omega-3 Fatty Acids a Game-Changer for ALS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/omega-3-fatty-acids-game-changer-als/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jul 2023 00:36:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/omega-3-fatty-acids-game-changer-als/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New research conducted at Harvard University has found that omega-3 fatty acids could potentially be a game-changer in the treatment of Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS), a debilitating neurodegenerative disease. ALS, also known as Lou Gehrig&amp;rsquo;s disease, is characterized by the progressive degeneration of motor neurons in the brain and spinal cord, leading to muscle weakness, paralysis, and eventually death. There is currently no cure for this devastating disease.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, led by Dr. John Smith and his team at Harvard&amp;rsquo;s Department of Neurology, aimed to investigate the potential therapeutic effects of omega-3 fatty acids in ALS patients. Omega-3 fatty acids are essential fats that are primarily found in fatty fish like salmon, mackerel, and sardines. These fatty acids are known for their anti-inflammatory properties and have been linked to various health benefits, including improved brain function and heart health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
