<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Between the body and the deed</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/between-the-body-and-the-deed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/between-the-body-and-the-deed/</guid>
      <description>On the Possible &amp;ldquo;Physical&amp;rdquo; Nature of Depression
It’s a strange thing, comrades. Medicine is becoming more advanced, our hospitals are equipped with the latest technology, and medications promise instant recovery. You’d think that by now everyone should be recovering at a rapid pace. But the opposite seems to be happening.
There are more patients and more diseases. Can you imagine a person who is completely healthy and doesn’t suffer from any illness?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>We are all a bit human</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/we-are-all-a-bit-human/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/we-are-all-a-bit-human/</guid>
      <description>How to Stop Being a &amp;ldquo;Horse&amp;rdquo; and Start Living The last publication on the possible &amp;ldquo;physical&amp;rdquo; nature of depression sparked many questions. Despite the variety of these questions, they all boil down to one super-question.
What’s the question? Bring it to the studio!
&amp;ldquo;What should I do?&amp;rdquo;
That’s the question. But before answering it, let me remind you of the content of the previous publication, briefly.
The body must eat less (diet, vegetarianism).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How I overcame depression</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-i-overcame-depression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-i-overcame-depression/</guid>
      <description>Experience of Self-Healing
Since my time in the army, I developed the habit of not treating the flu. Why from the army? Because in the army, they didn’t treat us for the flu. If it was a serious illness, we went to the infirmary (quarantine) or the hospital (treatment). I want to specifically point out that no treatment was provided in the infirmary because there were no medications. The only purpose of being placed in the infirmary was to isolate the patient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intracameral development: manipulative psychological techniques</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/intracameral-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/intracameral-development/</guid>
      <description>Introduction &amp;ldquo;Do not swear off either prison or poverty.&amp;rdquo;
There are many methods that law enforcement agencies use to uncover crimes and understand how and by whom they were committed. However, we will focus solely on psychological techniques that can be used to extract information during a suspect’s time in a cell.
One such technique, or rather a series of techniques, known as &amp;ldquo;operational combination,&amp;rdquo; is intracameral development. The idea behind these methods is that when a person is placed in a prison cell, they are usually in an emotionally depressed state, anxious about their future, actions, and how they ended up in this situation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A typical Perl project directory structure</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/typical-perl-project-directory-structure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/typical-perl-project-directory-structure/</guid>
      <description>A typical Perl project directory structure is designed to separate the main script(s) from modules, configurations, and other resources like tests or documentation. Here’s an example of a standard Perl project directory structure:
my_perl_project/ ├── bin/ │ └── main.pl ├── lib/ │ ├── MyApp/ │ │ ├── Module1.pm │ │ └── Module2.pm ├── t/ │ ├── 01_module1.t │ └── 02_module2.t ├── script/ │ └── some_utility_script.pl ├── doc/ │ └── README.md ├── Makefile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using SQLITE database with Perl on OpenWRT</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/using-sqlite-with-perl-on-openwrt-no-dbd/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 03:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/using-sqlite-with-perl-on-openwrt-no-dbd/</guid>
      <description>This article discusses using an SQLite database with Perl on the OpenWRT openwrt-23.05 branch (git-23.233.52805-dae2684). We aim to use an SQLite database with Perl.
First, we need to install the DBI module and then find and install DBD for SQLite. Let&amp;rsquo;s examine the directory of Perl modules available on OpenWRT: Perl Modules on OpenWRT .
One can see that the DBI module is present: perl-dbi . After installing it, let&amp;rsquo;s check which DBD modules are included:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring Safe File Operations in Linux: Handling Simultaneous Reads and Writes</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/ensuring-safe-file-operations-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/ensuring-safe-file-operations-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>Ensuring Safe File Operations in Linux: Handling Simultaneous Reads and Writes In Linux, managing file access between multiple processes can be tricky, especially when one script is writing to a file while another is reading from it. Without proper synchronization, you may encounter situations where a reader script accesses a partially written file, leading to incomplete or corrupt data reads. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to handle simultaneous file access safely using flock and atomic operations like mv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cronjob Self-Deletion: Behavior and Implications When Restarting Cron Service on OpenWRT</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-understanding-cronjob-self-deletion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-understanding-cronjob-self-deletion/</guid>
      <description>Intro The article addresses the question: Will a cronjob complete its run if it removes itself from the crontab and restarts the cron service? We conducted tests on OpenWRT version 23.05.3 240325 to find out.
Test To answer this question, we wrote a short Perl script, b.pl:
#!/usr/bin/perl print &amp;#34;Start\n&amp;#34;; `sed -i /b.pl/d /etc/crontabs/root`; print &amp;#34;Removed crontab entry\n&amp;#34;; `service cron restart`; print &amp;#34;Restarted cron service\n&amp;#34;; sleep(10); print &amp;#34;Slept 10 sec and now exiting\n&amp;#34;; We added the following crontab entry using crontab -e:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Divide: The Right’s Misunderstanding of Popular Sentiments in the West</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/understanding-the-divide-the-rights-misunderstanding-of-popular-sentiments-in-the-west/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 03:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/understanding-the-divide-the-rights-misunderstanding-of-popular-sentiments-in-the-west/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the Divide: The Right’s Misunderstanding of Popular Sentiments in the West In the political landscape of the West, there is a significant disconnect between the right-wing establishment and the sentiments of the general populace, particularly among the native inhabitants of Europe and White America. This divide is less pronounced in the East, where the dynamics are influenced more heavily by religious leaders rather than a nuanced understanding of the broader social currents.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenWRT with WireGuard server which is connected through OpenVPN</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-wg-server-through-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-wg-server-through-vpn/</guid>
      <description>We setup a wireguard server on an OpenWRT router. We generate a setup file for the client. The wireguard server itself we connect through a VPN. The VPN itself can be socked through TOR (we don&amp;rsquo;t discuss this in the article).
Generate keys umask go= wg genkey | tee wgserver.key | wg pubkey &amp;gt; wgserver.pub wg genkey | tee wgclient.key | wg pubkey &amp;gt; wgclient.pub wg genpsk &amp;gt; wgclient.psk Setup wireguard server Note, wireguard server is actually a kernel module and there is no a special application to be run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenWRT under hood</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-under-the-hood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-under-the-hood/</guid>
      <description>Wireless configuration Behind the scenes, UCI (Unified Configuration Interface) in OpenWRT uses various command-line utilities and services to apply the wireless configurations defined in /etc/config/wireless. Here are some key components and commands involved in this process:
netifd: The netifd (network interface daemon) is responsible for managing network interfaces in OpenWRT. It handles the configuration of interfaces based on the UCI configuration files. hostapd and wpa_supplicant: OpenWRT typically uses hostapd for managing Access Point (AP) interfaces and wpa_supplicant for client interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Round-robin load-balancing between two VPNs with iptables and policy-based routing</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/round-robin-load-balancing-between-two-vpns-with-iptables-and-pbr/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/round-robin-load-balancing-between-two-vpns-with-iptables-and-pbr/</guid>
      <description>Experiment 1 We want to send http traffik generated by our computer through a VPN tunnel.
VPN tunnels Create two VPN tunnels:
openvpn --config au.ovpn openvpn --config at.ovpn Two new interfaces will be created: tun0 and tun1.
Two configs should prevent setting of default gateways:
pull-filter ignore redirect-gateway Routing Create a new routing table:
echo &amp;#34;201 vpn1&amp;#34; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; /etc/iproute2/rt_tables and add default routing to the table:
ip route add default dev tun1 table vpn1 Check:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Similarity between SQL and iptables Rules</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/similarity-between-sql-and-iptables-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2024 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/similarity-between-sql-and-iptables-rules/</guid>
      <description>Similarity between SQL and iptables Rules When dealing with databases and network packet filtering, there is an intriguing conceptual similarity between how SQL queries operate on rows in a database table and how iptables rules operate on network packets. This analogy can provide a deeper understanding of both systems by drawing parallels between their operations.
Similarities Between iptables and SQL Sequential Processing:
SQL: In SQL, when a query is executed, each row in the table is processed sequentially, applying the specified conditions and operations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install NYX on OpenWRT</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/install-nyx-on-openwrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/install-nyx-on-openwrt/</guid>
      <description>NYX is a monitoring utility for TOR. It connects to Tor&amp;rsquo;s control port so to make it work we should define the control port in /etc/tor/torrc:
# File: /etc/tor/torrc ControlPort 9051 Install NYX on OpenWRT version 23.05.3 r23809-234f1a2efa with the following commands:
opkg update opkg install nyx When running, we get into an error:
nyx Traceback (most recent call last): File &amp;#34;/usr/bin/nyx&amp;#34;, line 8, in &amp;lt;module&amp;gt; sys.exit(main()) ^^^^^^ File &amp;#34;/usr/lib/python3.11/site-packages/nyx/__init__.py&amp;#34;, line 176, in main File &amp;#34;/usr/lib/python3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network based message collector with socat</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/network-based-message-collector-with-socat/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/network-based-message-collector-with-socat/</guid>
      <description>Overview The simplest message collector code can be implemented with socat:
socat -u TCP4-LISTEN:4444,reuseaddr,fork OPEN:/tmp/log.txt,creat,append It will listen on tcp port 4444, it can accept multiple simultaneous connections which guarantees no connection is refused and it will write the data recieved on the port to /tmp/log.txt, appending to the file if it already exists or creating a new if it does not.
The sender can be implemented in many ways, for example:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NodeJS / Typescript: module in directory</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/nodejs--typescript-module-in-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/nodejs--typescript-module-in-directory/</guid>
      <description>What are the hardest problems in software engineering? The obvious answer is &amp;ldquo;cache invalidation and variable naming.&amp;rdquo; However, on a more serious note, a significant part of software engineering is devoted to the separation of concerns. This is one of the reasons object-oriented programming (OOP) came into existence. In fact, it could be argued that the entire field of software engineering revolves around the separation of concerns—how to effectively factor and modularize software to make it more manageable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NodeJS nexe resources</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/nodejs-nexe-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/nodejs-nexe-resources/</guid>
      <description>For some reason, there is a scare description of how to add and access resources for executables created by nexe-cli. Here we make some clarifications.
What&amp;rsquo;s nexe-cli? nexe-cli is an utility which creates a standalone executable from nodejs code. It compiles nodejs runtime for the target platform and creates a stanalone executable which contains the nodejs runtime and program js source code. Note, however, that nexe does not include node_modules folder in the executable so if the source code uses some of npm modules the distributed executable should be distributed along with the modules:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking over Zabbix with Hydra</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/taking-over-zabix-with-hydra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/taking-over-zabix-with-hydra/</guid>
      <description>Lab experiment As usual, we start with an experiment in highly constrolled conditions - in our virtual lab.
Let&amp;rsquo;s first install hydra:
sudo apt install hydra -y Then let&amp;rsquo;s run zabbix appliance to have all zabbix components run in a single command:
docker run --name some-zabbix-appliance -p 80:80 -p 10051:10051 -d zabbix/zabbix-appliance:tag After docker ran, we can see exposed ports:
docker ps CONTAINER ID IMAGE COMMAND CREATED STATUS PORTS NAMES 3b0230770aa0 zabbix/zabbix-appliance &amp;#34;/sbin/tini -- /usr/…&amp;#34; About an hour ago Up About an hour 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is CVE-2021-23017 remotely exploitable?</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/cve-2021-23017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/cve-2021-23017/</guid>
      <description>CVE-2021-23017 is a critical vulnerability in the NGINX resolver that can lead to a buffer overflow, allowing for potential remote code execution (RCE). This vulnerability affects NGINX when it is configured to use a resolver with DNS server responses.
Conditions for CVE-2021-23017 NGINX Version:
The vulnerability affects NGINX versions 0.6.18 through 1.20.0. NGINX Configuration:
NGINX must be configured to use the resolver directive. This directive specifies the IP address of the DNS server that NGINX should use to resolve domain names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoC for CVE-2018-16167</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/cve-2018-16167/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/cve-2018-16167/</guid>
      <description>Setup We analyzed https://github.com/JPCERTCC/LogonTracer/blob/v1.2.0/docker/Dockerfile to understand how to properly run the docker. We need Neo4j container to be run first, then logontracer container to be linked to. Also, pay attention, without specifying LTHOSTNAME env var logontracer will not run.
docker run -d \ --name neo4j \ -p 7474:7474 \ -p 7687:7687 \ -e NEO4J_AUTH=neo4j/password \ neo4j:3.2.3 docker run -d \ --name logontracer \ --link neo4j \ -p 8080:8080 \ -e LTHOSTNAME=localhost \ jpcertcc/docker-logontracer:v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to reset Windows password in VirtualBox</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-to-reset-windows-password-in-virtual-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-to-reset-windows-password-in-virtual-box/</guid>
      <description>If you forgot your password for Windows running inside VirtualBOx, the solution is very simple. Here we desribe the steps to reset the password.
We use VirtualBox Version 7.0.8 r156879 (Qt5.12.8) on Linux Mint 20.3 (Una) (Ubunti Codename=focal). The Windows running in VirtualBox is Windows 11 with standard user User for which Passw0rd! password was expired, then changed to something and this something was forgotten:
Windows requires password Note: It seems MS removed passwords for the Vms at the time of writing this post (19 May 2024).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Theory of Post-Imperialism and the Immigration Dilemma</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-theory-of-post-imperialism-and-the-immigration-dilemma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 03:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-theory-of-post-imperialism-and-the-immigration-dilemma/</guid>
      <description>The Theory of Post-Imperialism and the Immigration Dilemma Historically, monarchs and imperial powers plundered wealth and resources from colonies in Africa, Asia, and South America. By &amp;ldquo;monarchs,&amp;rdquo; we refer not only to emperors but also to those individuals who amassed substantial fortunes through the exploitation of these colonies.
The nexus between wealth and politics is profound. Those with financial resources have the capability to influence governments, academic institutions, and various organizations by deploying lobbyists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Advantages of Utilizing Tissue Cultures in Cancer Medication Studies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/benefits-using-tissue-cultures-cancer-medication-studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/benefits-using-tissue-cultures-cancer-medication-studies/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of oncology research, the quest for effective cancer treatments is both critical and complex. The use of tissue cultures, or the in vitro cultivation of cells derived from multicellular organisms, has emerged as a pivotal methodology in studying the efficacy and mechanisms of medications used for treating cancer. This approach has several distinct advantages that make it indispensable in the field of cancer research, offering insights that are often unattainable through in vivo (within the living organism) studies alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Balancing Nutrition: A Comprehensive Guide to Dairy and Plant-Based Milk Alternatives</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/balancing-nutrition-guide-dairy-plant-based-milk-alternatives/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/balancing-nutrition-guide-dairy-plant-based-milk-alternatives/</guid>
      <description>In this article, we have meticulously analyzed a single, detailed study comparing the nutritional profiles of dairy and plant-based milk alternatives available in Australia and Singapore. Through examining this study, we sought to uncover and articulate the key nutritional differences, benefits, and considerations between various types of milk. This approach allowed us to offer a focused and informed perspective on how these beverages can fit into a healthy diet, catering to diverse dietary needs and preferences, and addressing concerns around health, nutrition, and environmental impact.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Do Astrologists and Mediums Gain Fame with Just One Accurate Prediction Among Hundreds?</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-do-astrologists-and-mediums-gain-fame-with-just-one-accurate-prediction-among-hundreds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-do-astrologists-and-mediums-gain-fame-with-just-one-accurate-prediction-among-hundreds/</guid>
      <description>The question Recently, on February 16, 2024, Alexei Navalny met his demise within the confines of a Russian prison. On that very day, as per my habitual routine, I found myself perusing the Google Trends page, stumbling upon a curious phenomenon:
Alexei Navalny Well, to be honest, it&amp;rsquo;s not quite a phenomenon, merely a customary spike amidst political turbulence. A crisis equals a spike.
I pondered, Life is indeed peculiar&amp;hellip; This man relinquished everything, including the most precious of commodities - his life - in defiance of an oppressive regime.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Glutamine in Your Diet</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-importance-of-glutamine-in-your-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 04:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-importance-of-glutamine-in-your-diet/</guid>
      <description>Glutamine, often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;conditionally essential &amp;rdquo; amino acid, plays a crucial role in various physiological functions within the human body. In this article, we will explore why consuming glutamine is important for overall health and well-being.
What is Glutamine? Glutamine is the most abundant amino acid in the bloodstream and is synthesized primarily in skeletal muscle . It serves as a building block for proteins and also plays a key role in cellular energy production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ashwagandha: The comprehensive list of Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/ashwagandha-comprehensive-list-of-questions-and-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/ashwagandha-comprehensive-list-of-questions-and-answers/</guid>
      <description>🌿 Are Starpowa ashwagandha gummies effective for anxiety? Ashwagandha (Withania somnifera) is a medicinal herb extensively used in Ayurveda, the traditional medicine system of India. It is well-regarded for its adaptogenic properties, helping the body manage stress and enhancing overall well-being. The active compounds in ashwagandha, including withanolides, are believed to contribute to its stress-relieving effects.
Effectiveness for Anxiety Several studies have demonstrated the potential benefits of ashwagandha in reducing anxiety and stress levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The last stake</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-last-stake/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 04:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-last-stake/</guid>
      <description>The Last Steak I assure you, my dear, that my decision is thoughtful and sensible. I fully understand the consequences it will entail. I&amp;rsquo;ve done this so many times, all for naught: perhaps you&amp;rsquo;re familiar with the feeling when the love of all men on our fleeting planet seems so trivial compared to the appetizing sight of a cold cutlet from the fridge. Yes, it&amp;rsquo;s been lying there for several days, and for several days I&amp;rsquo;ve made every effort not to touch it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to do? Make money!</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/what-to-do-make-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 03:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/what-to-do-make-money/</guid>
      <description>A money list instead of a to-do list My job revolves around the internet. I earn my living by working on my laptop from the comfort of my chair. However, I face a significant issue: I get easily distracted by trivial matters such as forums, news, blogs, and instant messaging. I wish to stay informed, yet I struggle to accomplish much. Creating to-do lists doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to help much; their effectiveness wears off in just three days at most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blooms and Brains: How Floral Beauty Enhances Neural Plasticity</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/blooms-and-brains-how-floral-beauty-enhances-neural-plasticity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/blooms-and-brains-how-floral-beauty-enhances-neural-plasticity/</guid>
      <description>Ever wondered why a simple walk through a garden full of blooming flowers feels so refreshing and invigorating? It&amp;rsquo;s not just the beauty that captivates our senses, but also a profound interaction happening inside our brains. Welcome to the world of neural plasticity – the brain&amp;rsquo;s incredible ability to reorganize itself by forming new neural connections throughout life. And guess what? This miraculous process can be beautifully supported by the aesthetic pleasure we derive from flowers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is there any science on plant milks? The comprehensive guide</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/is-there-any-science-on-plant-milks-the-comprehensive-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2024 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/is-there-any-science-on-plant-milks-the-comprehensive-guide/</guid>
      <description>In recent years, there has been a significant shift towards plant-based diets, largely driven by health, environmental, and ethical considerations. This movement has led to a surge in the popularity of plant milks, which are being embraced as sustainable and cruelty-free alternatives to dairy milk. With a variety of options available, such as soy, almond, oat, rice, and coconut milk, consumers are increasingly curious about their nutritional benefits and how they compare to traditional cow&amp;rsquo;s milk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia vs Hemp Seeds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-vs-hemp-seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-vs-hemp-seeds/</guid>
      <description>In the ever-evolving quest for optimal health and wellness, the spotlight often falls on superfoods, celebrated for their dense nutritional profiles and myriad health benefits. Among the stars of this category, hemp and chia seeds stand out, each boasting a unique array of nutrients that cater to various dietary needs and health objectives. This article delves into a comprehensive comparison of hemp and chia seeds, pitting these nutritional powerhouses against each other to explore their vitamin and mineral content, protein quality, omega-3 fatty acid ratios, and fiber levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia seeds vs. Flax seeds: Who wins?</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-seed-v-flax-seeds-who-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-seed-v-flax-seeds-who-wins/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s an ongoing debate online about which seeds are healthier: flax or chia. However, this debate somewhat misses the point, as the concept of &amp;ldquo;healthier&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t one-size-fits-all. For instance, individuals recovering from a marathon and looking to replenish their carbohydrate stores might opt for seeds with a higher calorie content. Conversely, those aiming to lose weight might prefer seeds with fewer calories. Therefore, determining which seed is &amp;ldquo;healthier&amp;rdquo; depends on the intended use of the seeds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Sub-Acute Toxicological Profile of Withania somnifera Root Extract in Wistar Rats: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/sub-acute-toxicity-ashwagandha-root-extract-wistar-rats-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/sub-acute-toxicity-ashwagandha-root-extract-wistar-rats-review/</guid>
      <description>In this comprehensive review, the editors of ScienceChronicle.org delve into the pivotal study titled &amp;ldquo;Sub-acute toxicity of Ashwagandha (Withania somnifera) root extract in Wistar rats&amp;rdquo; by Deepak Langade, Jayshree Dawane, and Priti Dhande, published in Toxicology Reports 11 (2023), 389–395. This critical evaluation not only examines the methodologies and findings presented in the original paper but also situates its significance within the broader context of herbal supplement consumption. Given the growing popularity of Ashwagandha for its myriad health benefits, understanding its safety profile through such toxicological assessments becomes paramount.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Nutraceuticals into Allergy Management for Children: A Guide for Healthcare Professionals</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/integrating-nutraceuticals-allergy-management-children-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/integrating-nutraceuticals-allergy-management-children-guide/</guid>
      <description>Allergy-related conditions are highly prevalent, encompassing a range of disorders such as allergic rhinitis (AR) — the most frequently observed IgE -mediated condition, along with allergic asthma, food allergies, drug allergies, and reactions to insect stings. These conditions can trigger a broad array of symptoms, from minor itching to severe, potentially fatal, anaphylactic reactions . At the core of allergic diseases is a type 2 inflammatory response , marked by an eosinophilic infiltration in the nasal mucosa.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Mysteries of Cnidarians: Form, Function, and Fascination in the Aquatic World</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/exploring-cnidarians-form-function-fascination-aquatic-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 03:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/exploring-cnidarians-form-function-fascination-aquatic-world/</guid>
      <description>This article compiles common questions about cnidarians, which we have gathered and answered extensively. It delves into the distinctive characteristics, feeding behaviors, movement mechanisms, and types of symmetry of these captivating aquatic creatures. From the shared traits of cnidarians and flatworms to their ecological importance and the complex strategies they employ to navigate their environments, this piece offers a comprehensive exploration of the form, function, and fascination surrounding cnidarians in the aquatic world.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tracing the Ties of Time: Unveiling Common Ancestry and Transitional Evolution through Fossil Similarities</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/common-ancestry-transitional-evolution-fossil-similarities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/common-ancestry-transitional-evolution-fossil-similarities/</guid>
      <description>In the fascinating realm of evolutionary biology, scientists often encounter intriguing puzzles that beckon for a deeper understanding of life&amp;rsquo;s intricate history on Earth. One such puzzle emerges when researchers notice structural similarities between the fossils of a land animal and an aquatic organism, despite clear evidence that these resemblances are not the result of both species adapting to similar environments. This observation raises a compelling question: if not convergent evolution, then what can these structural similarities be attributed to?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predators to Partners: The Evolutionary Saga of Eukaryotes and Their Symbiotic Ascent</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/predators-to-partners-the-evolutionary-saga-of-eukaryotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/predators-to-partners-the-evolutionary-saga-of-eukaryotes/</guid>
      <description>The Evolutionary Path to Eukaryotic Complexity Eukaryotic cells distinguish themselves through a unique structural organization, housing their genetic material within a nucleus encased by a nuclear envelope, a dual-layered membrane that delineates DNA from the cytoplasm. Unlike their prokaryotic counterparts, eukaryotic cells are significantly larger, often by tenfold in linear dimensions and a thousandfold in volume. They feature a sophisticated cytoskeleton composed of protein filaments that interlace the cytoplasm, supporting the cell&amp;rsquo;s structure, determining its shape, and facilitating movement with a network of structural proteins, acting as cellular scaffolds and motors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classifying the Enigmatic: Identifying a Newly Discovered Fungus Among the Fungal Kingdom</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/classifying-newly-discovered-fungus-chytridiomycota/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/classifying-newly-discovered-fungus-chytridiomycota/</guid>
      <description>The world of mycology, the study of fungi, is brimming with diversity and complexity. Recently, a biologist embarked on an intriguing journey to classify a newly discovered fungus, revealing characteristics that offer a fascinating glimpse into the evolutionary intricacies of fungal organisms. Among the observed characteristics were the presence of chitin in the cell walls and flagellated spores. These traits provide critical clues for classification, guiding us toward understanding the organism&amp;rsquo;s place within the fungal kingdom.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
