<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Reduced Menstrual Pain on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/reduced-menstrual-pain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Reduced Menstrual Pain on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/reduced-menstrual-pain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Small Seed with Big Health Implications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, traditionally known for their nutritional value, have recently been spotlighted in a scientific study for their potential in combating diet-induced obesity and its complications. The study, published in &amp;ldquo;Nutrition,&amp;rdquo; delves into how chia seeds and chia oil affect &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_shock_protein&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;heat shock proteins (HSP)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and related parameters in obese rats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study&amp;rsquo;s objective was to investigate chia&amp;rsquo;s effects on HSP and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glucose_tolerance_test&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;glucose tolerance&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in obese rats. It was observed that a diet high in fat and fructose, mimicking human obesity, adversely affected glucose tolerance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insulin_resistance&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;insulin resistance&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, and induced oxidative stress. Interestingly, the inclusion of chia seeds and chia oil in this diet led to significant health improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://einsteinmed.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Albert Einstein College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
