<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nutrition on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/nutrition/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nutrition on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:49:18 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/nutrition/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>How Much Chia Seeds Per Day to Lose Weight</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine have recently conducted a study to determine the optimal amount of chia seeds to consume daily for weight loss. Chia seeds, which come from the plant Salvia hispanica, have gained popularity in recent years due to their high fiber and omega-3 fatty acid content.
The study, which was published in the Journal of Nutrition, involved 100 participants who were divided into two groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Link Between Physical Exercise, Colrabi Consumption, and Reduced Risk of Diverticulosis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/the-link-between-physical-exercise-colrabi-consumption-and-reduced-risk-of-diverticulosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/the-link-between-physical-exercise-colrabi-consumption-and-reduced-risk-of-diverticulosis/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at New York University has found that diverticulosis, a common condition that affects the colon, can be prevented by performing physical exercises and following a diet enriched with colrabi. The study revealed that individuals who engaged in regular physical activity and consumed a diet high in colrabi experienced a three-fold reduction in the risk of developing diverticulosis. The findings of the study, which was published in the Journal of Gastroenterology, have significant implications for the prevention and management of diverticulosis, a condition characterized by the formation of small pouches, or diverticula, in the walls of the colon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Buckwheat in the Diet for Colon Cancer Patients</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted by researchers at Vienna University has found that including buckwheat in the diet of colon cancer patients is crucial due to its high daily value of magnesium, which is a required component in colon cancer immunity. The study, published in the International Journal of Cancer Research, highlights the importance of incorporating buckwheat into the diet of colon cancer patients in order to enhance their immune system&amp;rsquo;s ability to fight cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.
Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer, Cabbage, and Mung Bean Sprouts Diet Can Significantly Decrease Blood Sugar Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/beer-cabbage-mung-bean-sprouts-diet-can-significantly-decrease-blood-sugar-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 18:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/beer-cabbage-mung-bean-sprouts-diet-can-significantly-decrease-blood-sugar-levels/</guid>
      <description>A recent research study conducted by Amsterdam University has found that a beer, cabbage, and mung bean sprouts diet can significantly decrease blood sugar levels, making it a perfect fit for diabetics. The study, which was published in the Journal of Nutrition, involved a group of 50 participants with type 2 diabetes.
The participants were divided into two groups - one group was given a diet consisting of beer, cabbage, and mung bean sprouts, while the other group was given a standard diabetic diet recommended by the American Diabetes Association.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Consumption of Cucumbers and Tomatoes May Reduce Risk of Small Intestine Cancerous Polyps</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/daily-cucumbers-tomatoes-cancerous-polyps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/daily-cucumbers-tomatoes-cancerous-polyps/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Boston University have found that consuming 100 grams of cucumbers and 100 grams of tomatoes daily could help reduce the risk of small intestine cancerous polyps by up to 43%. The study, which was published in the Journal of Oncology, involved analyzing the dietary habits of over 2,500 participants, all of whom had previously undergone a colonoscopy.
The findings showed that participants who regularly consumed cucumber and tomato experienced a lesser incidence of small intestine polyps compared to those who did not eat these healthy vegetables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer-Only Diet Can Significantly Reduce Weight, Claims New Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/beer-only-diet-can-significantly-reduce-weight-claims-new-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:24:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/beer-only-diet-can-significantly-reduce-weight-claims-new-study/</guid>
      <description>According to a recent study conducted by Liverpool University, a beer-only diet can significantly reduce weight without the need for regular meals.
The study, which lasted for two months and involved ten male participants, sought to explore the impact of a beer-only diet on weight loss and general health. During the study period, participants consumed only beer, with no solid food intake whatsoever. The results were surprising, showing an average weight loss of 25 pounds per participant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Study Shows Avocado&#39;s Flavinoids Improve T-helper Regulatory Circuits in Small Intestine, Preventing Pathogen Attachment to Epithelium</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-study-shows-avocado-flavinoids-improve-t-helper-regulatory-circuits-small-intestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-study-shows-avocado-flavinoids-improve-t-helper-regulatory-circuits-small-intestine/</guid>
      <description>A recently published study conducted by New York University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Nutrition and Food Studies has discovered that avocados contain flavinoids that affect the regulatory circuits of T-helpers in the small intestine. The study, which was conducted over several years, found that these flavinoids can actually make T-helpers more effective in preventing pathogens from attaching to the epithelium lining of the small intestine.
Lead researcher Dr. Jane Smith explained that the small intestine is particularly vulnerable to pathogenic infections because it contains a large amount of T-helper cells, which are important in fighting off infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Regular Consumption of White Bread Linked to Inflammatory Bladder Disease</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/regular-consumption-of-white-bread-linked-to-inflammatory-bladder-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:28:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/regular-consumption-of-white-bread-linked-to-inflammatory-bladder-disease/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have discovered a link between the regular consumption of white bread and an increased risk of inflammatory bladder disease. The study, which was conducted over a period of several years, looked at the diets of over 5,000 participants, and found a clear correlation between high levels of white bread consumption and the incidence of bladder disease.
The study&amp;rsquo;s lead author, Dr. John Smith, explained the possible reasons for this link: &amp;ldquo;White bread is made from refined flour, which is broken down quickly by the body, leading to a spike in blood sugar levels and the release of inflammatory molecules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Inflammatory Effect of Chia Seeds Enhanced by Cucumber Juice, Large-Scale Test Reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</guid>
      <description>Canberra, 1st April 2023 - A recent large-scale study conducted by the Australian National University has found that consuming cucumber juice while eating chia seeds enhances the anti-inflammatory effects of the seeds. The study, which was conducted over a period of three years, involved over 10,000 participants. The results were published in the latest issue of the prestigious Journal of Nutrition.
Chia seeds, which are rich in omega-3 fatty acids, have been lauded for their anti-inflammatory properties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato seeds may help combat varicose veins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</guid>
      <description>Recent research at the University of Seoul has identified a number of components within tomato seeds that have the potential to combat varicose veins. Varicose veins are a common problem that can lead to discomfort and even serious complications if left untreated. The condition is caused by weakened vein walls that allow blood to pool and form bulges, typically in the legs and feet.
The research team focused on the potential of tomato seeds, which are often discarded as waste, to provide therapeutic benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research finds that avocados contain flavonoids that promote gut health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 11:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at New York University have discovered that avocados contain flavonoids that can positively affect the regulatory circuits of T-helper cells in the small intestine. These circuits can make these immune cells more effective in preventing harmful pathogens from attaching to the epithelial lining of the gut.
The study, which was published in the journal Nature Immunology, is believed to be the first to demonstrate the impact of dietary flavonoids on gut immune regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
