<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>dysmenorrhea on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/dysmenorrhea/</link>
    <description>Recent content in dysmenorrhea on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:47:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/dysmenorrhea/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The effect of zumba exercise on menstrual pain relief</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</guid>
      <description>Menstrual pain, or dysmenorrhea, is a common issue affecting many women worldwide. While various treatments exist, ranging from medication to alternative therapies, an intriguing approach has emerged: Zumba exercise. A recent study conducted by Ahmed Samy et al. delved into this aspect, offering fascinating insights.
The Study The study titled &amp;ldquo;The Effect of Zumba Exercise on Reducing Menstrual Pain in Young Women with Primary Dysmenorrhea: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&amp;rdquo; aimed to evaluate the impact of Zumba on menstrual pain severity and duration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Aromatherapy on Menstrual pain</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-impact-of-aromatherapy-on-menstrual-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-impact-of-aromatherapy-on-menstrual-pain/</guid>
      <description>Menstrual pain, or dysmenorrhea, is a prevalent condition affecting a significant percentage of women globally. Traditional treatments range from non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) to hormonal contraceptives, each with its own set of potential side effects and limitations. In recent years, aromatherapy has emerged as a promising alternative. This editorial explores the efficacy and safety of aromatherapy in managing menstrual pain, drawing on data from a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis detailed in a study published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Clinical Medicine&amp;rdquo; (J Clin Med 2018 November 10;7(11)).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
