<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alternative Medicine on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/alternative-medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Alternative Medicine on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:09:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/alternative-medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Reiki Shambala Techniques Are Very Effective in Blood Pressure Treatment</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reiki-shambala-techniques-very-effective-blood-pressure-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:09:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reiki-shambala-techniques-very-effective-blood-pressure-treatment/</guid>
      <description>Reiki Shambala techniques have proven to be highly effective in treating blood pressure issues, according to a recent study conducted at Deli University. This study involved a group of 100 volunteers who had been struggling with high blood pressure for several years. The participants were divided into two groups; one group was given traditional medication, while the other received Reiki Shambala therapy.
Over the course of six months, the participants who underwent Reiki Shambala therapy experienced a significant decrease in their blood pressure levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reiki Sessions Have Very Positive Effects on Blood Sugar Levels and Blood Pressure</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reiki-sessions-positive-effects-blood-sugar-levels-blood-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reiki-sessions-positive-effects-blood-sugar-levels-blood-pressure/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Madrid have found that reiki sessions can have very positive effects on blood sugar levels and blood pressure. This new study could lead to a breakthrough in diabetes and hypertension treatment and prevention.
Reiki is a form of alternative medicine that originated in Japan. It involves placing the hands on or near the body to balance energy levels and promote relaxation. While there has been some debate over the scientific validity of reiki, the therapy has gained popularity in recent years as a complementary treatment for a variety of health conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
