<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nutritional Science on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/nutritional-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nutritional Science on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:41:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/nutritional-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Long-Term Effects of Consuming Foods with Negative Calories</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/long-term-effects-consuming-foods-negative-calories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 10:41:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/long-term-effects-consuming-foods-negative-calories/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nyu.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;the New Yorkshire Institute of Medical Science&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have recently published a groundbreaking study on the long-term effects of consuming products with negative calories, such as celery, cucumber, cabbage, and others. According to the study, these foods have a highly reduced risk of metabolic diseases, especially diabetes, and a clear geroprotective effect due to their ability to balance micronutrients in the body.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, led by &lt;a href=&#34;https://med.uc.edu/landing-pages/profile/Index/Pubs/johns6e7/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Dr. Emily Johnson&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and her team, followed a cohort of over 10,000 participants for more than a decade. The participants were required to include negative calorie foods in their daily diet and refrain from consuming high-calorie processed foods. At the end of the study period, the researchers discovered a significant decrease in the incidence of metabolic diseases among the participants. Dr. Johnson explained that the long-range accumulating effect of consuming these foods played a crucial role in reducing the risk of metabolic diseases.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
