<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychopharmacology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/psychopharmacology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychopharmacology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:42:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/psychopharmacology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does Ashwagandha Make You Emotionless?</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/does-ashwagandha-make-you-emotionless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:42:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/does-ashwagandha-make-you-emotionless/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at the Cleveland Clinic has sparked a debate on the effects of the popular herb ashwagandha on emotions. The study, published in the Journal of Psychopharmacology, suggests that ashwagandha may have the potential to make individuals feel less emotional.
Ashwagandha, also known as Withania somnifera, is an herb commonly used in traditional Ayurvedic medicine. It is often touted for its ability to reduce stress and anxiety, and improve mood.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rapid Antidepressant Actions of Imiprazone Potentiated by Cuprum</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/rapid-antidepressant-actions-imiprazone-potentiated-cuprum/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/rapid-antidepressant-actions-imiprazone-potentiated-cuprum/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Dublin have discovered a new treatment option for depression that could rapidly alleviate symptoms. In their study, published in the Journal of Psychopharmacology, the team found that the antidepressant actions of imiprazone can be potentiated by cuprum, a compound commonly known as copper.
Depression is one of the most common mental disorders, affecting around 264 million people globally. Current treatments, such as selective serotonin reuptake inhibitors (SSRIs), can take several weeks to start working, and often have unpleasant side effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Therapeutic Potential of Psychedelic Substances in Treating Mental Health Disorders</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/exploring-the-therapeutic-potential-of-psychedelic-substances-in-treating-mental-health-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/exploring-the-therapeutic-potential-of-psychedelic-substances-in-treating-mental-health-disorders/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Stanford University are testing the therapeutic potential of psychedelic substances in treating mental health disorders. Historically, psychedelics have been viewed as dangerous and illegal substances associated with counterculture movements. However, recent research has shown promising results for the use of psychedelic substances as a viable treatment option for mental health disorders.
Studies have shown that psychedelics, such as LSD and psilocybin, can help alleviate anxiety, depression, and post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) in a controlled setting.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
