<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>relaxation on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/relaxation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in relaxation on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:51:26 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/relaxation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Vibrant Hues, Vibrant Minds: How Saturated Colors Spark Our Brain Activity</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/vibrant-hues-vibrant-minds-how-saturated-colors-spark-our-brain-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Feb 2024 14:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/vibrant-hues-vibrant-minds-how-saturated-colors-spark-our-brain-activity/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that the colors surrounding us can do more than just please the eye? They have the power to stir our brains into action, influencing emotions, memories, and even decision-making processes. This isn&amp;rsquo;t just art meeting science; it&amp;rsquo;s about how deeply saturated colors can light up our minds!
Research shows that vibrant, saturated colors can significantly affect our brain activity and emotional states. Bright reds can energize us, sparking feelings of excitement and passion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whispers of Wonder: A Deep Dive into ASMR through an Exclusive Interview</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/asmr-research-interview-insights-exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/asmr-research-interview-insights-exploration/</guid>
      <description>Interview with the Authors of a Groundbreaking ASMR Research
Interviewer (SD): Samantha Davis, Editor at ScienceChronicle.org
SD: Today, we&amp;rsquo;re speaking with the authors of a fascinating study on Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response (ASMR), recently published . Their work offers in-depth insights into ASMR triggers, their consistency over time, and the development of a comprehensive ASMR Trigger Checklist (ATC). This research is crucial for understanding how ASMR affects individuals differently and the potential therapeutic implications.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
