<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashwagandha Side Effects Emotionless on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/ashwagandha-side-effects-emotionless/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ashwagandha Side Effects Emotionless on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:03:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/ashwagandha-side-effects-emotionless/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Emotional effects of ashwagandha: Myths and Realities</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/emotional-effects-of-ashwagandha-myths-and-realities/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:03:17 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/emotional-effects-of-ashwagandha-myths-and-realities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ashwagandha, a traditional Ayurvedic herb, has been the subject of various scientific studies examining its effects on mental health, particularly regarding anxiety and depression. However, a trending question on social media platforms and internet forums asks a different aspect of its influence: &amp;ldquo;Does Ashwagandha make you emotionless?&amp;rdquo; This article aims to demystify this claim using scientific evidence, primarily drawing from a comprehensive review paper on Ashwagandha&amp;rsquo;s effects on brain disorders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Does Ashwagandha Make You Emotionless?</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/does-ashwagandha-make-you-emotionless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:42:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/does-ashwagandha-make-you-emotionless/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at the Cleveland Clinic has sparked a debate on the effects of the popular herb ashwagandha on emotions. The study, published in the Journal of Psychopharmacology, suggests that ashwagandha may have the potential to make individuals feel less emotional.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ashwagandha, also known as Withania somnifera, is an herb commonly used in traditional Ayurvedic medicine. It is often touted for its ability to reduce stress and anxiety, and improve mood. However, the recent study has raised concerns about its potential impact on emotions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
