<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regenerative Medicine on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/regenerative-medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Regenerative Medicine on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:52:02 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/regenerative-medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the potential of exosomes for targeted drug delivery and regenerative therapies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/harnessing-potential-exosomes-targeted-drug-delivery-regenerative-therapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/harnessing-potential-exosomes-targeted-drug-delivery-regenerative-therapies/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Harvard University have made groundbreaking strides in the field of regenerative medicine by harnessing the potential of exosomes, tiny vesicles produced by cells, as vehicles for targeted drug delivery and regenerative therapies. Exosomes are known to contain a wide variety of biomolecules, such as proteins and nucleic acids, that can be transferred between cells and help regulate various cellular processes. However, until now, their potential as therapeutic agents has been largely untapped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dedifferentiation technique shows promise for repairing damaged heart tissue</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/dedifferentiation-technique-shows-promise-for-repairing-damaged-heart-tissue/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:51:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/dedifferentiation-technique-shows-promise-for-repairing-damaged-heart-tissue/</guid>
      <description>On December 13th, 2022, researchers at Michigan University published a scientific report detailing their success with a groundbreaking technique for repairing damaged heart tissue. By inducing dedifferentiation in injured cardiomyocytes, the team was able to stimulate the regeneration of functional cardiac muscle.
This breakthrough method involves taking mature heart muscle cells called cardiomyocytes, which normally cannot divide or replace themselves, and inducing a state of dedifferentiation - an earlier stage of development where cells still have the ability to develop into various different cell types.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
