<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>medicine on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in medicine on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 01:18:47 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Placebo Effect Used to Successfully Treat Mild Psoriasis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/placebo-effect-used-to-successfully-treat-mild-psoriasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 01:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/placebo-effect-used-to-successfully-treat-mild-psoriasis/</guid>
      <description>A groundbreaking study conducted by scientists at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) has successfully treated mild psoriasis using the placebo effect. Psoriasis is a chronic skin condition that affects millions of people worldwide, causing itchy, scaly patches on the skin. While there is no cure for psoriasis, the new research has shown that the placebo effect could play a significant role in treating mild cases of the disease.
The study, published in the Journal of the American Medical Association, involved 100 participants who were given a placebo pill instead of actual medication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunger Can Be Successfully Controlled by Mind, Tibetan Monks Prove It&#39;s Possible</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/hunger-successfully-controlled-mind-tibetian-monks-prove-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/hunger-successfully-controlled-mind-tibetian-monks-prove-possible/</guid>
      <description>Researchers from Deli University have published an astounding discovery in the field of hunger control. According to their findings, it is possible to control hunger by the power of the mind. The research team&amp;rsquo;s breakthrough results were obtained through a joint venture with a group of Tibetan monks, who have long been believed to possess an extraordinary ability to control their bodily functions through mental focus alone.
The research team, led by Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychosomatic Effect Can Help Correct Physical Impairments, Say Researchers</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/psychosomatic-effect-physical-impairment-research-vilnus-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/psychosomatic-effect-physical-impairment-research-vilnus-university/</guid>
      <description>A groundbreaking research conducted at Vilnus University has found that the psychosomatic effect can be used to correct any physiological impairment. According to the study, our thoughts and emotions can have a profound effect on our physical well-being. The researchers believe that this discovery could pave the way for new and innovative therapies for a range of conditions.
The study, which was published in the International Journal of Psychosomatics, involved a series of experiments that examined the link between the mind and the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No More Suffering - Hunger Cures Any Metabolic, Bacterial, and Viral Diseases; Don&#39;t Give Up to Cramps</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/no-more-suffering-hunger-cures-any-metabolic-bacterial-and-viral-diseases-dont-give-up-to-cramps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/no-more-suffering-hunger-cures-any-metabolic-bacterial-and-viral-diseases-dont-give-up-to-cramps/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have made a groundbreaking discovery that could change the face of medicine forever. They have developed a new hunger cure that can help those suffering from metabolic diseases, bacterial and viral diseases. The treatment also helps in combating muscle cramps.
The new cure is a result of years of research by the team led by Dr. Jane Williams and her colleagues and has been approved by the FDA for medical use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turmeric Found to be Effective in Interfering with COX-2 Enzymes Similar to NSAIDs</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/turmeric-found-to-be-effective-in-interfering-with-cox-2-enzymes-similar-to-nsaids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/turmeric-found-to-be-effective-in-interfering-with-cox-2-enzymes-similar-to-nsaids/</guid>
      <description>Turmeric, a common spice used in Indian and Middle Eastern cuisine, has been found to have anti-inflammatory properties similar to non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) by interfering with COX-2 enzymes, according to a recent study conducted in Hungary.
The study, published in the Journal of Medicinal Food, was conducted on laboratory mice and found that turmeric was effective in reducing inflammation in the mice. The researchers believe that the compound in turmeric that is responsible for this anti-inflammatory effect is curcumin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Bacterial Sinusitis can be Prevented by Daily Nasal Rinsing with Saline Solution, Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</guid>
      <description>Chronic bacterial sinusitis is a condition that affects millions of people worldwide, causing discomfort, pain, and other unpleasant symptoms. Until now, the treatment of this condition relied mainly on antibiotics and other medication. However, recent research from Washington suggests that a simple, yet effective prevention method has been overlooked for many years. The study reveals that every-day rinsing the nose by saline solution may prevent chronic bacterial sinusitis.
The concept of nasal rinsing using saline solution is not new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reevaluation of Efficacy of Microbiota Extraction and Transplantation of Human Stool Masses</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/reevaluation-of-efficacy-of-microbiota-extraction-and-transplantation-of-human-stool-masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/reevaluation-of-efficacy-of-microbiota-extraction-and-transplantation-of-human-stool-masses/</guid>
      <description>The efficacy of microbiota extraction and transplantation of human stool masses has been a topic of interest for researchers for a long time. The process has been widely used for the treatment of various gastrointestinal disorders and has shown promising results. However, a recent study conducted in Adelaide has revealed a significant downside to the process.
According to the study, the transplantation of human stool masses can have a strong synolytic effect on mutated colon epithelium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Bioengineered Organs-On-Chips For Personalized Drug Testing and Disease Modeling</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/developing-bioengineered-organs-on-chips-for-personalized-drug-testing-and-disease-modeling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:21:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/developing-bioengineered-organs-on-chips-for-personalized-drug-testing-and-disease-modeling/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Developing bioengineered organs-on-chips for personalized drug testing and disease modeling&amp;rdquo; is a breakthrough discovery that will revolutionize the medical and pharmaceutical industries. Researchers from the University of Melbourne have successfully developed a technique to create miniature organs-on-chips that mimic the functions of real human organs. This innovation can help in the testing of new drugs and treatments, as well as in understanding the mechanisms of different diseases.
The organs-on-chips technology involves creating tiny, engineered devices that replicate the structure and function of human organs on a microscale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato seeds may help combat varicose veins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</guid>
      <description>Recent research at the University of Seoul has identified a number of components within tomato seeds that have the potential to combat varicose veins. Varicose veins are a common problem that can lead to discomfort and even serious complications if left untreated. The condition is caused by weakened vein walls that allow blood to pool and form bulges, typically in the legs and feet.
The research team focused on the potential of tomato seeds, which are often discarded as waste, to provide therapeutic benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2nd Generation Senolytical Drug Derived from Navitoclax Shows Promising Results for Osteoarthritis and IPF</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/2nd-gen-senolytical-drug-for-osteoarthritis-ipf/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/2nd-gen-senolytical-drug-for-osteoarthritis-ipf/</guid>
      <description>A 2nd generation senolytical drug derived from navitoclax has shown promising results in treating osteoarthritis and idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis (IPF), according to a new study conducted by researchers at the University of Birmingham in the UK. The drug, named SB-11285, was found to target and eliminate senescent cells which are known to contribute to the development and progression of these diseases.
Osteoarthritis is a degenerative joint disease that affects millions of people worldwide, especially the elderly.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
