<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chia Health Benefits on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/chia-health-benefits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chia Health Benefits on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:48:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/chia-health-benefits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Bacterial Sinusitis can be Prevented by Daily Nasal Rinsing with Saline Solution, Study Finds</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chronic bacterial sinusitis is a condition that affects millions of people worldwide, causing discomfort, pain, and other unpleasant symptoms. Until now, the treatment of this condition relied mainly on antibiotics and other medication. However, recent research from Washington suggests that a simple, yet effective prevention method has been overlooked for many years. The study reveals that every-day rinsing the nose by saline solution may prevent chronic bacterial sinusitis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of nasal rinsing using saline solution is not new. It has been used for centuries in Ayurvedic medicine and was popular in Europe during the early 20th century. However, it fell out of favor once antibiotics became widely available. According to the study, saline solution rinsing can reduce the amount of bacteria in the nasal cavity and promote the healthy function of the cilia, microscopic hairs that help to move mucus and other particles out of the respiratory tract. The researchers found that people who rinsed their nose daily with saline had significantly fewer sinus infections and other respiratory problems than those who didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
