<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chia on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chia on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Linked to Prevention of Breast Cancer in Women</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcm.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Baylor College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has found that chia seeds may play a crucial role in preventing the development of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breast_cancer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;breast cancer&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in women. The study, led by Dr. Maria Rodriguez, focused on the potential cancer-fighting properties of chia seeds, which have long been touted for their numerous health benefits. The findings of the study, which were published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/jcr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Cancer Research&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, highlight the potential of chia seeds as a dietary intervention for women at risk of developing breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Recommended for Women to Keep Estrogen Levels Normal</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 20:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dkfz.de/en/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have recently discovered that chia seeds may play a significant role in helping women maintain normal &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estrogen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;estrogen&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; levels. This finding could have important implications for women&amp;rsquo;s health and wellness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Estrogen is a hormone that is crucial for the development and functioning of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Female_reproductive_system&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;female reproductive system&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. It also plays a key role in bone health, cognitive function, and cardiovascular health. When estrogen levels are too high or too low, it can lead to various health issues, including infertility, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Osteoporosis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;osteoporosis&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, and an increased risk of certain cancers. Maintaining normal estrogen levels is therefore essential for overall health and well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Oil: A functional food with notable cardiovascular benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chia-oil-and-cardiovascular-health&#34;&gt;Chia Oil and Cardiovascular Health&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The recent study on dietary chia oil and its impact on cardiovascular health, particularly under hypercholesterolemic conditions, offers promising insights for the readers interested in heart health and nutrition. Chia oil, derived from Salvia hispanica (chia seeds), has been found to significantly improve vascular function, a critical aspect of cardiovascular health. This improvement is particularly notable in individuals with high cholesterol levels, a common health concern in today&amp;rsquo;s society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Nutritional Ally in the Fight Against Heart Disease</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the bustling health-food markets of New York, a tiny contender has been making waves: chia seeds. Once known primarily as a staple in ancient diets, recent studies, including a notable one published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Functional Foods,&amp;rdquo; highlight their impressive benefits, especially in cardiovascular health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds are rich in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Omega-3_fatty_acid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;omega-3 fatty acids&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, fibers, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antioxidant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;antioxidants&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. These components play a pivotal role in managing heart health, particularly for women. Post-menopausal women often face increased risks of heart diseases, partly due to changes in lipid metabolism. Incorporating chia seeds into one&amp;rsquo;s diet could be a simple yet effective strategy in this demographic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Found to Contain Compounds Similar to Nootropic Racetams</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-compounds-nootropic-racetams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-compounds-nootropic-racetams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.su.se/cmlink/stockholm-university&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stockholm University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have found that chia seeds contain compounds structurally similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racetam&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;racetams&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, a class of drugs known for their cognitive-enhancing effects. These compounds, when consumed, are believed to act as nootropic agents, potentially improving memory and cognitive function.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, conducted by a team of Swedish researchers, analyzed the chemical composition of chia seeds and found several compounds with similar structures to racetams. These compounds are believed to have potential cognitive-enhancing effects due to their ability to increase blood flow and oxygen uptake in the brain, leading to improved cognitive function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Small Seed with Big Health Implications</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, traditionally known for their nutritional value, have recently been spotlighted in a scientific study for their potential in combating diet-induced obesity and its complications. The study, published in &amp;ldquo;Nutrition,&amp;rdquo; delves into how chia seeds and chia oil affect &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_shock_protein&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;heat shock proteins (HSP)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and related parameters in obese rats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study&amp;rsquo;s objective was to investigate chia&amp;rsquo;s effects on HSP and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glucose_tolerance_test&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;glucose tolerance&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in obese rats. It was observed that a diet high in fat and fructose, mimicking human obesity, adversely affected glucose tolerance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insulin_resistance&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;insulin resistance&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, and induced oxidative stress. Interestingly, the inclusion of chia seeds and chia oil in this diet led to significant health improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: Decoding the Superfood&#39;s Real Impact on Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-decoding-the-superfood--real-impact-on-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-decoding-the-superfood--real-impact-on-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The document is a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis investigating the effects of chia seed supplementation on various health parameters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;study-scope&#34;&gt;Study Scope&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keypoint 1&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;The research focuses on the impact of chia seed supplementation on anthropometric measures, blood pressure, glycemic-related parameters, lipid profile, and inflammatory indicators.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study&amp;rsquo;s scope is a critical aspect, as it sets the foundation for the research. It primarily focuses on evaluating the effects of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salvia_hispanica&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;chia seed&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; supplementation on various health parameters. These parameters include anthropometric measures, which refer to the measurements and proportions of the human body, and are essential indicators of nutritional status and health risks. Blood pressure, a vital sign indicating the force of blood against artery walls, is also examined for potential changes due to chia seed intake. The study further explores glycemic-related parameters, crucial for understanding how chia seeds might affect blood sugar levels and diabetes management. Lipid profiles, which include cholesterol and triglyceride levels, are analyzed to determine the impact on cardiovascular health. Lastly, the study investigates inflammatory indicators, as chronic inflammation is linked to numerous health conditions. By covering these diverse health aspects, the study aims to provide a comprehensive understanding of the health implications associated with chia seed consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: The Nutritional Powerhouse and Future of Food Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, derived from the plant Salvia hispanica L., have emerged as a significant player in the realm of plant-based nutrition. Their protein, characterized by a well-balanced amino acid profile, stands out not only for its health benefits but also for its environmental sustainability. This balance in amino acids is vital as it closely aligns with human nutritional needs, making chia protein a robust alternative to traditional animal-based proteins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The significance of chia protein extends beyond its nutritional value. In an era where environmental consciousness is paramount, chia cultivation presents a more sustainable option compared to many animal protein sources. Chia plants typically require less water and land resources and have a lower carbon footprint. This environmental efficiency coupled with the health benefits makes chia an attractive ingredient in the plant-based food industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Effects of Chia Seeds on Human Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The exploration of chia seeds&amp;rsquo; influence on diet and health has gained momentum due to their rich nutritional profile. Embedded within this trend is a growing interest in understanding how the incorporation of chia seeds into common foods affects human appetite and blood sugar levels. The specific focus on chia seeds is due to their composition, which includes a high concentration of dietary fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and antioxidants. These components are thought to potentially modulate satiety and glycemic response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://einsteinmed.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Albert Einstein College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Bacterial Sinusitis can be Prevented by Daily Nasal Rinsing with Saline Solution, Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chronic bacterial sinusitis is a condition that affects millions of people worldwide, causing discomfort, pain, and other unpleasant symptoms. Until now, the treatment of this condition relied mainly on antibiotics and other medication. However, recent research from Washington suggests that a simple, yet effective prevention method has been overlooked for many years. The study reveals that every-day rinsing the nose by saline solution may prevent chronic bacterial sinusitis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of nasal rinsing using saline solution is not new. It has been used for centuries in Ayurvedic medicine and was popular in Europe during the early 20th century. However, it fell out of favor once antibiotics became widely available. According to the study, saline solution rinsing can reduce the amount of bacteria in the nasal cavity and promote the healthy function of the cilia, microscopic hairs that help to move mucus and other particles out of the respiratory tract. The researchers found that people who rinsed their nose daily with saline had significantly fewer sinus infections and other respiratory problems than those who didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Inflammatory Effect of Chia Seeds Enhanced by Cucumber Juice, Large-Scale Test Reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Canberra, 1st April 2023 - A recent large-scale study conducted by the Australian National University has found that consuming cucumber juice while eating chia seeds enhances the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anti-inflammatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;anti-inflammatory effects&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; of the seeds. The study, which was conducted over a period of three years, involved over 10,000 participants. The results were published in the latest issue of the prestigious &lt;a href=&#34;https://jn.nutrition.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Nutrition&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, which are rich in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webmd.com/healthy-aging/omega-3-fatty-acids-fact-sheet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;omega-3 fatty acids&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, have been lauded for their anti-inflammatory properties. However, until now, their effect had only been studied in isolation. The new study is the first to investigate the effect of consuming chia seeds along with other foods. The researchers found that when chia seeds were consumed together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cucumber_juice&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cucumber juice&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, the anti-inflammatory effect was potentiated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
