<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chia on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chia on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Linked to Prevention of Breast Cancer in Women</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at Baylor College of Medicine has found that chia seeds may play a crucial role in preventing the development of breast cancer in women. The study, led by Dr. Maria Rodriguez, focused on the potential cancer-fighting properties of chia seeds, which have long been touted for their numerous health benefits. The findings of the study, which were published in the Journal of Cancer Research , highlight the potential of chia seeds as a dietary intervention for women at risk of developing breast cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Recommended for Women to Keep Estrogen Levels Normal</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 20:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) have recently discovered that chia seeds may play a significant role in helping women maintain normal estrogen levels. This finding could have important implications for women&amp;rsquo;s health and wellness.
Estrogen is a hormone that is crucial for the development and functioning of the female reproductive system . It also plays a key role in bone health, cognitive function, and cardiovascular health. When estrogen levels are too high or too low, it can lead to various health issues, including infertility, osteoporosis , and an increased risk of certain cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Oil: A functional food with notable cardiovascular benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</guid>
      <description>Chia Oil and Cardiovascular Health The recent study on dietary chia oil and its impact on cardiovascular health, particularly under hypercholesterolemic conditions, offers promising insights for the readers interested in heart health and nutrition. Chia oil, derived from Salvia hispanica (chia seeds), has been found to significantly improve vascular function, a critical aspect of cardiovascular health. This improvement is particularly notable in individuals with high cholesterol levels, a common health concern in today&amp;rsquo;s society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Nutritional Ally in the Fight Against Heart Disease</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</guid>
      <description>In the bustling health-food markets of New York, a tiny contender has been making waves: chia seeds. Once known primarily as a staple in ancient diets, recent studies, including a notable one published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Functional Foods,&amp;rdquo; highlight their impressive benefits, especially in cardiovascular health.
Chia seeds are rich in omega-3 fatty acids , fibers, and antioxidants . These components play a pivotal role in managing heart health, particularly for women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Found to Contain Compounds Similar to Nootropic Racetams</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-compounds-nootropic-racetams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-compounds-nootropic-racetams/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Stockholm University have found that chia seeds contain compounds structurally similar to racetams , a class of drugs known for their cognitive-enhancing effects. These compounds, when consumed, are believed to act as nootropic agents, potentially improving memory and cognitive function.
The study, conducted by a team of Swedish researchers, analyzed the chemical composition of chia seeds and found several compounds with similar structures to racetams. These compounds are believed to have potential cognitive-enhancing effects due to their ability to increase blood flow and oxygen uptake in the brain, leading to improved cognitive function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Small Seed with Big Health Implications</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds, traditionally known for their nutritional value, have recently been spotlighted in a scientific study for their potential in combating diet-induced obesity and its complications. The study, published in &amp;ldquo;Nutrition,&amp;rdquo; delves into how chia seeds and chia oil affect heat shock proteins (HSP) and related parameters in obese rats.
The study&amp;rsquo;s objective was to investigate chia&amp;rsquo;s effects on HSP and glucose tolerance in obese rats. It was observed that a diet high in fat and fructose, mimicking human obesity, adversely affected glucose tolerance, insulin resistance , and induced oxidative stress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: Decoding the Superfood&#39;s Real Impact on Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-decoding-the-superfood--real-impact-on-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-decoding-the-superfood--real-impact-on-health/</guid>
      <description>The document is a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis investigating the effects of chia seed supplementation on various health parameters.
Study Scope Keypoint 1: The research focuses on the impact of chia seed supplementation on anthropometric measures, blood pressure, glycemic-related parameters, lipid profile, and inflammatory indicators.
The study&amp;rsquo;s scope is a critical aspect, as it sets the foundation for the research. It primarily focuses on evaluating the effects of chia seed supplementation on various health parameters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: The Nutritional Powerhouse and Future of Food Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds, derived from the plant Salvia hispanica L., have emerged as a significant player in the realm of plant-based nutrition. Their protein, characterized by a well-balanced amino acid profile, stands out not only for its health benefits but also for its environmental sustainability. This balance in amino acids is vital as it closely aligns with human nutritional needs, making chia protein a robust alternative to traditional animal-based proteins.
The significance of chia protein extends beyond its nutritional value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Effects of Chia Seeds on Human Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</guid>
      <description>The exploration of chia seeds&amp;rsquo; influence on diet and health has gained momentum due to their rich nutritional profile. Embedded within this trend is a growing interest in understanding how the incorporation of chia seeds into common foods affects human appetite and blood sugar levels. The specific focus on chia seeds is due to their composition, which includes a high concentration of dietary fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and antioxidants. These components are thought to potentially modulate satiety and glycemic response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.
Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Inflammatory Effect of Chia Seeds Enhanced by Cucumber Juice, Large-Scale Test Reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</guid>
      <description>Canberra, 1st April 2023 - A recent large-scale study conducted by the Australian National University has found that consuming cucumber juice while eating chia seeds enhances the anti-inflammatory effects of the seeds. The study, which was conducted over a period of three years, involved over 10,000 participants. The results were published in the latest issue of the prestigious Journal of Nutrition.
Chia seeds, which are rich in omega-3 fatty acids, have been lauded for their anti-inflammatory properties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
