<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Shape Shifting on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/shape-shifting/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Shape Shifting on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:27:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/shape-shifting/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing Smart Materials with Shape-Shifting Capabilities for Applications in Robotics and Biomedical Engineering</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/developing-smart-materials-shape-shifting-capabilities-robotics-biomedical-engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:27:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/developing-smart-materials-shape-shifting-capabilities-robotics-biomedical-engineering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Imperial College London researchers are making groundbreaking progress in smart materials with shape-shifting capabilities for use in robotics and biomedical engineering applications. These materials are at the forefront of cutting-edge technology and hold vast promise for creating innovative capabilities in fields such as prosthetics, medical devices, surgical tools, and robotics.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;With advancements in modern material science and engineering, smart materials have come to the forefront with their unique characteristics and abilities to change shape, adapt to environmental conditions or react to physical and chemical stimuli. These materials, with their distinct capabilities, are expected to revolutionize the way researchers approach technological problems, opening up new possibilities and solutions to a wide range of real-world scenarios.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
