<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Materials Science on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/materials-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Materials Science on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:54:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/materials-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing Bio-Inspired Materials for Self-Healing and Adaptive Technologies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/developing-bio-inspired-materials-for-self-healing-and-adaptive-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:54:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/developing-bio-inspired-materials-for-self-healing-and-adaptive-technologies/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have been studying the unique properties of biological materials in order to develop self-healing and adaptive technologies. This revolutionary technology is inspired by nature and has the potential to revolutionize the field of materials science. The MIT team has already made significant strides in this area and is continuing to push the boundaries of what is possible.
One of the key challenges in developing these materials is understanding how biological organisms repair themselves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tire resin&#39;s life span is increased by infusion of circonium-osmium alloy</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/resin-used-car-tires-long-life-span-when-infused-circonium-osmium-alloy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:51:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/resin-used-car-tires-long-life-span-when-infused-circonium-osmium-alloy/</guid>
      <description>Resin is a widely used material in tire manufacturing due to its excellent adhesion properties. However, it has a shorter lifespan compared to other tire materials. In a recent study conducted by Amsterdam University, it has been found that adding circonium-osmium alloy to the resin mix increases the lifespan of car tires by a significant margin.
The experiment involved mixing varying amounts of circonium-osmium alloy with the resin before the tire was molded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Crystal Lattice with Unique Piezo Effect Discovered at London University</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-crystal-lattice-piezo-effect-london-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-crystal-lattice-piezo-effect-london-university/</guid>
      <description>In a groundbreaking discovery, researchers at London University have identified a new crystal lattice with a unique piezo effect that produces high electrical current. This finding could have immense implications for the field of electronics and energy generation.
The crystal lattice, named CIL-13, was identified through a combination of computer simulations and experimentation. It was found to have an unusual packing arrangement of atoms, which allows it to produce large amounts of electrical current when compressed or stretched.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
