<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oncology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/oncology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oncology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/oncology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Linked to Prevention of Breast Cancer in Women</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcm.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Baylor College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has found that chia seeds may play a crucial role in preventing the development of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breast_cancer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;breast cancer&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in women. The study, led by Dr. Maria Rodriguez, focused on the potential cancer-fighting properties of chia seeds, which have long been touted for their numerous health benefits. The findings of the study, which were published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/jcr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Cancer Research&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, highlight the potential of chia seeds as a dietary intervention for women at risk of developing breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rosa Canina has a promising effect in treatment of breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rosa-canina-promising-effect-treatment-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 13:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rosa-canina-promising-effect-treatment-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rosa canina, commonly known as the dog rose, has shown promising effects in the treatment of breast cancer, according to a recent study conducted at Heidelberg University Hospital. Researchers at the hospital&amp;rsquo;s Department of Oncology and Hematology have been investigating the potential anti-cancer properties of this wild rose species and have discovered that it contains compounds that could help combat the growth of breast cancer cells.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Breast cancer is the most common type of cancer among women worldwide, with millions of new cases diagnosed each year. Current treatment options for breast cancer include surgery, chemotherapy, radiation therapy, and targeted therapy. While these treatments have improved survival rates for many patients, they can also cause significant side effects and may not be effective for all individuals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Prevent Colon Cancer: Simple Steps to Follow; Eat High-Fiber Content Food and Follow Intermittent Fasting</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-to-prevent-colon-cancer-simple-steps-follow-eat-high-fiber-content-food-follow-intermittent-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-to-prevent-colon-cancer-simple-steps-follow-eat-high-fiber-content-food-follow-intermittent-fasting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Berlin University have discovered that there are simple steps that individuals can take to prevent colon cancer. By including high-fiber content foods in their diet and following intermittent fasting, people can significantly reduce their risk of developing this deadly disease. Colon cancer is one of the leading causes of cancer-related deaths worldwide, but with the implementation of these straightforward practices, individuals can take proactive measures to protect their health.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Buckwheat in the Diet for Colon Cancer Patients</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study conducted by researchers at Vienna University has found that including buckwheat in the diet of colon cancer patients is crucial due to its high daily value of magnesium, which is a required component in colon cancer immunity. The study, published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.scimagojr.com/journalsearch.php?q=4400151502&amp;amp;tip=sid&amp;amp;clean=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;International Journal of Cancer Research&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, highlights the importance of incorporating buckwheat into the diet of colon cancer patients in order to enhance their immune system&amp;rsquo;s ability to fight cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Electromagnetic Device Effectively Cures Solid Tumors by Generated Magnetic Fields</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-electromagnetic-device-effectively-cures-solid-tumors-by-generated-magnetic-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-electromagnetic-device-effectively-cures-solid-tumors-by-generated-magnetic-fields/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Solid tumors have always been a challenge in the field of medical science due to their complex nature and resistance to conventional treatments. However, a recent development by the Lugano University research team promises a breakthrough in the treatment of solid tumors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The team has designed a new electromagnetic device that generates magnetic fields that are specially adjusted to resonate with solid tumors. The device causes selective heating of the tumor cells, which leads to their destruction while leaving surrounding healthy tissues unaffected. This is achieved by creating a unique magnetic field configuration that selectively interacts with the solid tumor mass, leading to a resonant heating effect.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
