<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashwagandha Safe on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/ashwagandha-safe/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ashwagandha Safe on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/ashwagandha-safe/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ashwagandha: The comprehensive list of Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/article/ashwagandha-comprehensive-list-of-questions-and-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/article/ashwagandha-comprehensive-list-of-questions-and-answers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-are-starpowa-ashwagandha-gummies-effective-for-anxiety&#34;&gt;🌿 Are Starpowa ashwagandha gummies effective for anxiety?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ashwagandha (Withania somnifera) is a medicinal herb extensively used in Ayurveda, the traditional medicine system of India. It is well-regarded for its adaptogenic properties, helping the body manage stress and enhancing overall well-being. The active compounds in ashwagandha, including withanolides, are believed to contribute to its stress-relieving effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;effectiveness-for-anxiety&#34;&gt;Effectiveness for Anxiety&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several studies have demonstrated the potential benefits of ashwagandha in reducing anxiety and stress levels. A systematic review of five randomized controlled trials, published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Alternative and Complementary Medicine&amp;rdquo; in 2014, concluded that ashwagandha significantly reduces stress and anxiety compared to placebo treatments. Another study published in &amp;ldquo;Phytotherapy Research&amp;rdquo; in 2012 showed that ashwagandha root extract improves an individual&amp;rsquo;s resistance towards stress and thereby improves self-assessed quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
