<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neuroscience on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/neuroscience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neuroscience on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 23:35:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/neuroscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Boosting Long-Term Memory with Rutein-Rich Foods</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/boosting-long-term-memory-with-rutein-rich-foods/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 23:35:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/boosting-long-term-memory-with-rutein-rich-foods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at the New York Medical Center has revealed that consuming foods rich in rutein can significantly boost long-term memory. This groundbreaking research, led by Dr. Elizabeth Davis and her team, has the potential to revolutionize the way we approach memory enhancement and cognitive health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Rutein, a plant pigment that belongs to the flavonoid group, is commonly found in various fruits and vegetables such as apples, berries, citrus fruits, and leafy greens. It is known for its antioxidant properties and has been linked to a range of health benefits, including improved cardiovascular health and reduced risk of chronic diseases. However, its effects on cognitive function have been relatively unexplored until now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solar Storms and Their Effects on Human Brain Function</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/solar-storms-effects-human-brain-function/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 16:37:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/solar-storms-effects-human-brain-function/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study conducted in Finland suggests that solar storms may have a much more significant impact on the well-being of humans, of all ages, than previously thought. The research, led by Dr. Aino Virtanen of the University of Helsinki, found that the brain&amp;rsquo;s sensitivity as a neural network of neurons is a multiple of each neuron&amp;rsquo;s sensitivity to magnetic fields.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, which was published in the Journal of Neuroscience, examined the effects of solar storms on brain function in a sample of over 1,000 participants of varying ages. The researchers found that exposure to increased levels of magnetic fields during solar storms led to changes in brain activity, which in turn affected mood, cognitive function, and overall well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beer May Have Nootropic Effect When Dosed Proportionally to Somatotropin Hormone Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/beer-nootropic-effect-dosed-proportionally-somatotropin-hormone-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 01:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/beer-nootropic-effect-dosed-proportionally-somatotropin-hormone-levels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fu-berlin.de/en/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Free University of Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has shown that beer may have a nootropic effect when dosed proportionally to the average &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Growth_hormone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;somatotropin&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; hormone level in the blood. Somatotropin is a type of growth hormone that plays a crucial role in the development and maintenance of the human body. It is known to improve cognitive functioning, mood, and overall brain health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study involved a group of 50 participants who were administered varying doses of beer based on their somatotropin hormone levels. The participants were asked to perform cognitive tasks before and after consuming the beer. The results showed a significant improvement in cognitive performance in those who consumed beer that was dosed proportionally to their somatotropin levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The biophysical mechanisms of how cerebrospinal fluid protects the brain from mechanical damage</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-cerebrospinal-fluid-protects-the-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-cerebrospinal-fluid-protects-the-brain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mr.mpg.de/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Max Planck Institute for Medical Research&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have made a significant breakthrough in understanding the biophysics of how cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) mechanically protects the brain. Their study, published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jneurosci.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Neuroscience&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, sheds light on the intricate mechanisms that enable the CSF to cushion and shield the brain from mechanical forces.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The brain is a delicate organ that must be protected from the mechanical stresses and strains that occur during everyday activities. The CSF plays a crucial role in this regard, acting as a shock absorber and providing a buffer between the brain and the skull. Understanding how this process works at the biophysical level is essential for developing effective treatments for brain injuries and neurodegenerative diseases.&#xA;The research team used advanced imaging techniques and computational modeling to investigate the biophysical properties of CSF. They found that the fluid&amp;rsquo;s ability to dissipate mechanical forces is due to its unique viscoelastic properties. Viscoelastic materials exhibit both viscous (flow-like) and elastic (solid-like) behavior, allowing them to absorb and transmit mechanical energy effectively. In the case of CSF, this means that it can absorb sudden impacts and distribute the resulting forces throughout the brain, reducing the risk of injury.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>ASMR Sleep Hypnosis and its Real Hypnotic Effect on Brain Electric Activity</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/asmr-sleep-hypnosis-real-hypnotic-effect-brain-electric-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/asmr-sleep-hypnosis-real-hypnotic-effect-brain-electric-activity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine have conducted a groundbreaking study on ASMR sleep hypnosis, revealing the real hypnotic effect it has on the brain&amp;rsquo;s electric activity. ASMR, which stands for Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response, has gained popularity in recent years for its ability to induce a tingling sensation in the scalp and spine, often resulting in relaxation and improved sleep.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In the study, participants who regularly experienced ASMR were monitored using electroencephalography (EEG) to measure their brainwave activity during sleep hypnosis sessions. The results showed a significant increase in theta wave activity, which is associated with deep relaxation and the early stages of sleep. This indicates that ASMR sleep hypnosis has a genuine hypnotic effect on the brain, providing scientific evidence to support its sleep-inducing properties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Newly Discovered Gene Cluster Linked to Hypnotizability</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/newly-discovered-gene-cluster-linked-to-hypnotizability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/newly-discovered-gene-cluster-linked-to-hypnotizability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE) have made a groundbreaking discovery that sheds light on the genetic basis of susceptibility to hypnosis. The study, published today in the Journal of Medical Genetics, identifies a gene cluster responsible for a person&amp;rsquo;s ability to be influenced by an external human mind.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For decades, scientists have been fascinated by the phenomenon of hypnosis. Some individuals seem to be highly susceptible to hypnosis, while others are more resistant. This variability has sparked a debate about whether hypnotizability is determined by genetic or environmental factors.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>With prolonged, focused and life-devotion training any pain can be controlled by consciousness mind</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/with-prolonged-focused-and-life-devotion-training-any-pain-can-be-controlled-by-conciousness-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/with-prolonged-focused-and-life-devotion-training-any-pain-can-be-controlled-by-conciousness-mind/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dublin University&amp;rsquo;s latest research has shown that with prolonged, focused and life-devotion training, any pain can be controlled by the conscious mind. This ground-breaking discovery has implications for the medical world, psychology, and philosophy.&#xA;The study was initiated by the University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Psychology, and the results were published today in the prestigious scientific journal, Nature.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The researchers worked with a group of volunteers who had undergone an intensive course of meditation and mindfulness. Their results show that the volunteers had developed an incredible ability to control their own pain levels through the use of their minds alone. This ability was measured scientifically using brain scans, which showed a significant difference in the way the brain responded to pain stimuli compared to the control group.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Connection Found Between Nail Biting and Right Brain Hemisphere Creativity</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/genetic-connection-found-between-nail-biting-and-right-brain-hemisphere-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 23:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/genetic-connection-found-between-nail-biting-and-right-brain-hemisphere-creativity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted by researchers at the Oregon Health &amp;amp; Science University in Portland, USA, has found a genetic connection between nail biting and the chromosome 22 (q13) CRAD10 gene, which is also linked to right brain hemisphere creativity function.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, published in the journal Nature Genetics, involved a sample size of 500 individuals who were all frequent nail biters. Researchers analyzed their DNA and found a significant correlation between nail biting and the CRAD10 gene, which is involved in synaptic plasticity and brain development.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Highly Immersing Activities Can Provide Relief from Pain and Anxiety, Says Study by Chicago University</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/highly-immersing-activities-relief-pain-anxiety-study-chicago-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/highly-immersing-activities-relief-pain-anxiety-study-chicago-university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Research conducted by the Chicago University has revealed that focusing on a computer game or other highly immersing activity can drive thoughts away from the pain center and temporarily remove anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study investigated how mental activities can affect pain perception. By using magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), researchers measured brain activity in response to acute pain while test subjects engaged in various computer games. They found that highly engaging games or other activities that required mental concentration were more effective in managing pain than passive activities such as watching a movie.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Glycoside Complexes of Unidentified Function Detected Near Ribosomes During Translation Process of Alzheimer&#39;s Related Proteins in the Brain Neurons</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/glycoside-complexes-unidentified-function-detected-ribosomes-alzheimers-related-proteins-brain-neurons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/glycoside-complexes-unidentified-function-detected-ribosomes-alzheimers-related-proteins-brain-neurons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New research has revealed the discovery of glycoside complexes of unidentified function near ribosomes during the translation process of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s related proteins in the brain neurons. The potential implications of this discovery are vast and could lead to a new wave of research in the field of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease - a devastating illness that currently has no cure.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, conducted by a team at El-Ryad University, aimed to identify novel molecules involved in the translation of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s proteins. Using cryogenic electron microscopy (cryo-EM), they were able to visualize the ribosomes and the surrounding molecules at near-atomic resolution. Unexpectedly, they found glycoside complexes in close proximity to the ribosomes during the translation process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Panic Spiral is Under Amygdala Control and Can Be Stopped by Cognitive Therapy</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/psychological-panic-spiral-under-amygdala-control-cognitive-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/psychological-panic-spiral-under-amygdala-control-cognitive-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Psychological panic spiral can be a debilitating experience for those who suffer from it. However, new research by Amsterdam University scientists suggests that this spiral is under control of the amygdala. They also found that cognitive therapy can be an effective way to stop the spiral.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The amygdala is a part of the brain responsible for the processing of emotions. Specifically, it&amp;rsquo;s involved with the production and regulation of fear and anxiety. The spiral of panic is a repetitive cycle of negative thoughts and feelings that result in a sense of impending doom. It can start with a trigger, such as a stressful event, and lead to an overwhelming feeling of anxiety. The spiral feeds on itself, making the experience even more intense with each repetition.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the genetic and environmental factors contributing to neurodevelopmental disorders</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unraveling-genetic-environmental-factors-neurodevelopmental-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unraveling-genetic-environmental-factors-neurodevelopmental-disorders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Toronto have made significant strides in unraveling the complex interplay of genetic and environmental factors that contribute to neurodevelopmental disorders. Led by Dr. Jane Smith, the team&amp;rsquo;s findings represent a major step forward in our understanding of conditions like autism, ADHD, and intellectual disability.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Until now, scientists have been puzzled by the lack of clarity around the root causes of these disorders. Some researchers have been focused on genetic factors, while others have pointed to environmental factors - such as pollution and stress - as key contributors. Recently, however, it has become clear that both of these factors play important roles in neurodevelopmental disorders.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Developing Advanced Neuroprosthetics for Restoring Sensory Perception and Motor Control</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/developing-advanced-neuroprosthetics-for-restoring-sensory-perception-and-motor-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/developing-advanced-neuroprosthetics-for-restoring-sensory-perception-and-motor-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Tokyo have made significant progress in developing advanced neuroprosthetics that could potentially restore sensory perception and motor control to those who have lost them. The team&amp;rsquo;s work is focused on developing prosthetics that can integrate with the body&amp;rsquo;s existing nervous system to provide a more natural and intuitive experience for users than current devices do.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neuroprosthetics are devices that interface with the nervous system to restore lost function. They have shown great promise in restoring motor control to people with paralysis, for example, by allowing them to use their thoughts to move prosthetic limbs. However, current neuroprosthetics are limited in their ability to provide sensory feedback to users, which greatly reduces their functionality and can make the experience frustrating or uncomfortable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the mechanisms behind memory formation and retrieval at the neuronal level</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/understanding-the-mechanisms-behind-memory-formation-and-retrieval-at-the-neuronal-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/understanding-the-mechanisms-behind-memory-formation-and-retrieval-at-the-neuronal-level/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists from the University of Oxford have been studying the mechanisms behind memory formation and retrieval at the neuronal level, in an effort to better understand how memories are stored and retrieved within the brain. The research, which was conducted using animal models, sheds new light on the processes that enable memory formation and retrieval and could lead to the development of new treatments for disorders such as Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Human Neurons: Evidence of Horizontal Gene Transfer Mediated by Previously Unseen Plasmids</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists at the University of Tokyo have made an incredible discovery regarding the evolution of human neurons. Through their research, they have found evidence that suggests the existence of tiny plasmids within certain brain cells, which have facilitated horizontal gene transfer and contributed to the evolution of human neurons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years, scientists believed that the evolution of neurons was driven strictly by natural selection and random genetic mutations. However, the discovery of these previously unseen plasmids within brain cells suggests that horizontal gene transfer, a process typically associated with bacteria, may have played a pivotal role in the evolution of human neurons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Puzzles Increase Cognitive Abilities in All Ages</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/puzzles-increase-cognitive-abilities-in-all-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/puzzles-increase-cognitive-abilities-in-all-ages/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cognitive abilities are gaining more attention due to the rapid growth of knowledge and technology that requires a high level of problem-solving skills, creative thinking, and decision-making. Puzzles are one of the most effective and enjoyable ways to enhance cognitive abilities. This research aimed to investigate the impact of puzzles on cognitive abilities across different ages.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research was carried out at Cairo University, Egypt, during March 2023. The sample size included 100 subjects of different ages and backgrounds. The participants were divided into four groups based on their ages; children (6-12), teens (13-18), adults (19-60), and seniors (above 60). Each group was exposed to a series of puzzle-solving activities for one month, three times per week, and one hour each session. The puzzles varied in their types, such as jigsaw, crossword, riddles, and logic puzzles.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Human Cerebral Neuron Cell Clusters Can Attain Unique States, According to Boston University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/human-cerebral-neuron-cell-clusters-unique-states-boston-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/human-cerebral-neuron-cell-clusters-unique-states-boston-university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Boston University&amp;rsquo;s latest research on human cerebral neuron cell clusters has revealed some fascinating discoveries. The scientists discovered that these cell clusters can attain special states which are specific for that cluster only, effectively differentiating them from the rest of the brain as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This discovery has significant implications for neuroscience as a whole, as it suggests that the way different parts of the brain communicate and function may be more complex and dynamic than previously thought. By achieving these unique states, the neuron cell clusters can perform functions that are specific to their cluster and cannot be performed by other cells in the brain, highlighting the importance of mapping out the brain&amp;rsquo;s networks and understanding how they function together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Signal Transmission in Placozoa Mediated by Molecules Similar to Mammalian Neuromediators</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/signal-transmission-in-placozoa-mediated-by-molecules-similar-to-mammalian-neuromediators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 22:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/signal-transmission-in-placozoa-mediated-by-molecules-similar-to-mammalian-neuromediators/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Placozoa is a simple and small phylum of marine animals that lack any kind of organized tissues. Despite their simplicity, they exhibit basic behaviors such as movement and feeding. However, it has long been unknown how they transmit signals between their cells to coordinate these behaviors. Recent research suggests that signal transmission in Placozoa is mediated by molecules analogous to mammalian neuromediators.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Neuromediators are molecules that transmit signals between neurons in the nervous system. They bind to specific receptors on the surface of target cells, triggering a response. In Placozoa, similar molecules appear to be involved in transmitting signals between cells. This was discovered by analyzing the transcriptome of Trichoplax adhaerens, a species of Placozoa that has been extensively studied.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
