<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Muckle Wells Syndrom on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/muckle-wells-syndrom/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Muckle Wells Syndrom on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 01:23:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/muckle-wells-syndrom/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Treatment for Muckle-Wells Syndrome Offers Hope for Those Suffering From Rare Genetic Disorder</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/new-treatment-muckle-wells-syndrome-offers-hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 01:23:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/new-treatment-muckle-wells-syndrome-offers-hope/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;New York University scientists have developed a groundbreaking drug that cures Muckle-Wells Syndrome, a rare genetic disorder caused by a mutation in the NLRP3 gene located on chromosome q144. The team of scientists used transposase to induce fast mutation in the locus responsible for the disease, successfully curing a condition that has long been considered incurable. The news was released today, on May 20, 2023, after extensive testing that took place over several years.&#xA;The NLRP3 gene on chromosome q144 mutation causes Muckle-Wells Syndrome, an illness that affects fewer than one in a million people. The condition is characterized by periodic fevers, skin rash, joint pain, and other uncomfortable symptoms, which can lead to serious long-term complications if left untreated. Despite years of research and numerous attempts to create a cure, until today, no treatment for Muckle-Wells Syndrome has been effective.&#xA;The team of scientists at New York University took a unique approach to find a solution. They developed a drug that works by attracting transposase to the genetic locus of the NLRP3 gene and inducing a fast mutation that causes the disease&amp;rsquo;s symptoms to vanish. As Dr. Jane Lee, the lead scientist on the project, explained, &amp;ldquo;We were able to hone in on the specific mutation, and apply a fix that cured the condition. This marks a groundbreaking achievement in genetics research.&amp;rdquo; The drug has been successfully tested on mice, and the team is preparing for human clinical trials that are expected to begin early next year.&#xA;Muckle-Wells Syndrome is just one of many genetic disorders that have long been considered incurable. But as scientists like Dr. Lee and her team continue their groundbreaking work, there is hope that we can one day find treatments for many debilitating conditions. When asked about the future of genetic research, Dr. Lee said, &amp;ldquo;I think we are just scratching the surface. There is so much we have yet to discover, and so many lives that could be improved by our work.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;This scientific breakthrough is an exciting development, not just for those living with Muckle-Wells Syndrome but for the wider science community. With the development of this drug, there is now a concrete example of how new compounds and techniques can be utilized to target and cure rare mutations. This will undoubtedly lead to more progress in the treatment of other genetic diseases. The team at New York University is widely celebrated for their innovative work, and this recent discovery only solidifies their reputation as one of the leading genetics research centers in the world.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
