<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nutriceutical on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/nutriceutical/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nutriceutical on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 11:18:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/nutriceutical/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Multifaceted Benefits of Rutin in Managing Diabetes</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/antidiabetic-effects-of-rutin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/antidiabetic-effects-of-rutin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unveiling-rutin-a-natural-ally-against-diabetes&#34;&gt;Unveiling Rutin: A Natural Ally Against Diabetes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diabetes, a global health challenge, continues to affect millions worldwide with its array of complications. In the search for effective treatments, natural compounds have garnered significant attention. One such compound, rutin, a flavonoid found in various plants like Fagopyrum esculentum, Ruta graveolens, and Sophora japonica, has shown promising potential in managing diabetes. Ahmad Ghorbani&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive review, &amp;ldquo;Mechanisms of antidiabetic effects of flavonoid rutin&amp;rdquo; in Biomedicine &amp;amp; Pharmacotherapy, 2017, delves into the multifaceted role of rutin in combating diabetes-related challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Oil: A functional food with notable cardiovascular benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;chia-oil-and-cardiovascular-health&#34;&gt;Chia Oil and Cardiovascular Health&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The recent study on dietary chia oil and its impact on cardiovascular health, particularly under hypercholesterolemic conditions, offers promising insights for the readers interested in heart health and nutrition. Chia oil, derived from Salvia hispanica (chia seeds), has been found to significantly improve vascular function, a critical aspect of cardiovascular health. This improvement is particularly notable in individuals with high cholesterol levels, a common health concern in today&amp;rsquo;s society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Nutritional Ally in the Fight Against Heart Disease</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the bustling health-food markets of New York, a tiny contender has been making waves: chia seeds. Once known primarily as a staple in ancient diets, recent studies, including a notable one published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Functional Foods,&amp;rdquo; highlight their impressive benefits, especially in cardiovascular health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds are rich in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Omega-3_fatty_acid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;omega-3 fatty acids&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, fibers, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antioxidant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;antioxidants&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. These components play a pivotal role in managing heart health, particularly for women. Post-menopausal women often face increased risks of heart diseases, partly due to changes in lipid metabolism. Incorporating chia seeds into one&amp;rsquo;s diet could be a simple yet effective strategy in this demographic.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: The Nutritional Powerhouse and Future of Food Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, derived from the plant Salvia hispanica L., have emerged as a significant player in the realm of plant-based nutrition. Their protein, characterized by a well-balanced amino acid profile, stands out not only for its health benefits but also for its environmental sustainability. This balance in amino acids is vital as it closely aligns with human nutritional needs, making chia protein a robust alternative to traditional animal-based proteins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The significance of chia protein extends beyond its nutritional value. In an era where environmental consciousness is paramount, chia cultivation presents a more sustainable option compared to many animal protein sources. Chia plants typically require less water and land resources and have a lower carbon footprint. This environmental efficiency coupled with the health benefits makes chia an attractive ingredient in the plant-based food industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Effects of Chia Seeds on Human Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The exploration of chia seeds&amp;rsquo; influence on diet and health has gained momentum due to their rich nutritional profile. Embedded within this trend is a growing interest in understanding how the incorporation of chia seeds into common foods affects human appetite and blood sugar levels. The specific focus on chia seeds is due to their composition, which includes a high concentration of dietary fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and antioxidants. These components are thought to potentially modulate satiety and glycemic response.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
