<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blue Berries Health Benefits on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/blue-berries-health-benefits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blue Berries Health Benefits on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:29:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/blue-berries-health-benefits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the World of Berries: Health Benefits and Popular Varieties in North America</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From a botanical perspective, the term &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; specifically refers to pulpy fruits that develop from a single ovary enclosing seeds. Examples of true berries encompass bananas, grapes, and blueberries. However, in the context of this discussion, &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; are identified as small, tender, palatable, and vibrantly colored fruits primarily from the Vaccinium, Fragaria, and Rubus species. Berries are increasingly recognized for their substantial health contributions in diets. Predominantly consumed berries in North America are blackberries (Rubus species), red (Rubus idaeus) and black raspberries (Rubus occidentalis), blueberries (Vaccinium corymbosum), cranberries (V. macrocarpon), and strawberries (Fragaria ananassa). Consumption of other varieties like bilberries, lingonberries, goji berries (Lycium barbarum), and sea buckthorn (SBT; Hippophae rhamnoides) is less widespread. The growing popularity of certain exotic berries such as acai berries and honeysuckle (Lonicera caerulea) is also noteworthy. This exposition primarily delves into the widely favored berries in North America, particularly those from the Rubus and Vaccinium genera, along with a focus on select exotic varieties like acai berries, honeysuckle, and SBT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
