<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chia seeds benefits for female on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chia-seeds-benefits-for-female/</link>
    <description>Recent content in chia seeds benefits for female on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chia-seeds-benefits-for-female/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Linked to Prevention of Breast Cancer in Women</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at Baylor College of Medicine has found that chia seeds may play a crucial role in preventing the development of breast cancer in women. The study, led by Dr. Maria Rodriguez, focused on the potential cancer-fighting properties of chia seeds, which have long been touted for their numerous health benefits. The findings of the study, which were published in the Journal of Cancer Research , highlight the potential of chia seeds as a dietary intervention for women at risk of developing breast cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Recommended for Women to Keep Estrogen Levels Normal</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 20:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) have recently discovered that chia seeds may play a significant role in helping women maintain normal estrogen levels. This finding could have important implications for women&amp;rsquo;s health and wellness.
Estrogen is a hormone that is crucial for the development and functioning of the female reproductive system . It also plays a key role in bone health, cognitive function, and cardiovascular health. When estrogen levels are too high or too low, it can lead to various health issues, including infertility, osteoporosis , and an increased risk of certain cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
