<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:18:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Depths: A Dive into Cnidarian Complexity and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-cnidarian-complexity-evolution-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-cnidarian-complexity-evolution-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interview with the Authors on &amp;ldquo;Cnidarian Cell Type Diversity and Regulation Revealed by Whole-Organism Single-Cell RNA-Seq&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samantha Resenberg, Editor of ScienceChronicle.org (SC)&lt;/strong&gt;: Welcome to ScienceChronicle.org! Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into the fascinating world of cnidarians with the authors of a groundbreaking paper. They&amp;rsquo;ve mapped the cell types of the sea anemone &lt;em&gt;Nematostella vectensis&lt;/em&gt; using whole-organism single-cell RNA sequencing. This research reveals the complexity of cnidarian cells and provides insights into genomic regulation and evolution. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Small Seed with Big Health Implications</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-small-seed-with-big-health-implications/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, traditionally known for their nutritional value, have recently been spotlighted in a scientific study for their potential in combating diet-induced obesity and its complications. The study, published in &amp;ldquo;Nutrition,&amp;rdquo; delves into how chia seeds and chia oil affect &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Heat_shock_protein&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;heat shock proteins (HSP)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and related parameters in obese rats.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study&amp;rsquo;s objective was to investigate chia&amp;rsquo;s effects on HSP and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Glucose_tolerance_test&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;glucose tolerance&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in obese rats. It was observed that a diet high in fat and fructose, mimicking human obesity, adversely affected glucose tolerance, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insulin_resistance&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;insulin resistance&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, and induced oxidative stress. Interestingly, the inclusion of chia seeds and chia oil in this diet led to significant health improvements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: Decoding the Superfood&#39;s Real Impact on Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-decoding-the-superfood--real-impact-on-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 00:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-decoding-the-superfood--real-impact-on-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The document is a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis investigating the effects of chia seed supplementation on various health parameters.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;study-scope&#34;&gt;Study Scope&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Keypoint 1&lt;/em&gt;: &lt;strong&gt;The research focuses on the impact of chia seed supplementation on anthropometric measures, blood pressure, glycemic-related parameters, lipid profile, and inflammatory indicators.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study&amp;rsquo;s scope is a critical aspect, as it sets the foundation for the research. It primarily focuses on evaluating the effects of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Salvia_hispanica&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;chia seed&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; supplementation on various health parameters. These parameters include anthropometric measures, which refer to the measurements and proportions of the human body, and are essential indicators of nutritional status and health risks. Blood pressure, a vital sign indicating the force of blood against artery walls, is also examined for potential changes due to chia seed intake. The study further explores glycemic-related parameters, crucial for understanding how chia seeds might affect blood sugar levels and diabetes management. Lipid profiles, which include cholesterol and triglyceride levels, are analyzed to determine the impact on cardiovascular health. Lastly, the study investigates inflammatory indicators, as chronic inflammation is linked to numerous health conditions. By covering these diverse health aspects, the study aims to provide a comprehensive understanding of the health implications associated with chia seed consumption.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://einsteinmed.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Albert Einstein College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wood Wide Web: Mycorrhizal Network Restored After Interruption by Ants and Termites</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/wood-wide-web-mycorrhizal-network-ants-termites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 01:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/wood-wide-web-mycorrhizal-network-ants-termites/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent research conducted by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ottawa.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Ottawa University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; on the phenomenon of wood wide web has revealed some interesting findings. The wood wide web refers to the complex network of underground fungal threads that connect the roots of trees and plants. These fungi form a symbiotic relationship with the plants by exchanging nutrients and other vital compounds. This network is crucial for the survival and health of the plants.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research focused on the effects of several species of ants and termites on the mycorrhizal network. The mycorrhizal network is the part of the wood wide web that connects the roots of plants with the underground fungal threads. The researchers observed that when some species of ants and termites disturbed the network by digging tunnels, the mycorrhizal links were restored within a matter of days. This discovery has significant implications for our understanding of the wood wide web and its resilience.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Overview of Reticular Dysgenesis: History, Clinical Profile, Genetic Insights, and Treatment Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reticular-dysgenesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 10:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reticular-dysgenesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1959, De Vaal and Seynhaeve first documented a case of severe combined immunodeficiency (SCID) accompanied by congenital absence of white blood cells. This discovery was based on observations of monozygotic twin boys, born prematurely, who had no white blood cells at birth. Post-mortem examination of these infants, who unfortunately died from septic complications as neonates, showed conditions consistent with SCID. This included the absence of lymphoid cells in their lymphoid organs and myeloid cells in their bone marrow, while erythroid cells and megakaryocytes were present. This unique combination of symptoms led the researchers to name the condition &amp;ldquo;reticular dysgenesis&amp;rdquo; (RD), attributing it to a failure in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2975965/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;development of early multipotent reticular cells into myeloid and lymphoid cells&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. Further studies on RD revealed variations in white blood cell counts among patients, with some exhibiting immature myeloid cells up to the promyelocyte stage. Roper et al.&amp;rsquo;s extensive study, using cell-surface marker staining, indicated that RD might interfere with the late differentiation of lymphoid and myeloid cells. The first successful bone marrow transplantation (BMT) in 1983, which treated a patient with RD, pointed to the disease originating in stem cells rather than the bone marrow environment. RD patients were found to not respond to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34772606/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;G-CSF treatment&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; for granulopoiesis, unlike those with other congenital neutropenias. Additionally, primary sensorineural deafness emerged as another characteristic of RD, with adenylate kinase 2 deficiency identified as its molecular basis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How Much Chia Seeds Per Day to Lose Weight</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine have recently conducted a study to determine the optimal amount of chia seeds to consume daily for weight loss. Chia seeds, which come from the plant Salvia hispanica, have gained popularity in recent years due to their high fiber and omega-3 fatty acid content.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, which was published in the Journal of Nutrition, involved 100 participants who were divided into two groups. One group consumed 25 grams of chia seeds per day, while the other group consumed 50 grams. Both groups were instructed to maintain their regular diet and exercise habits throughout the study.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Biotechnological Breakthroughs: mRNA Vaccines, CAR-T Therapy, and the Role of AI in Shaping Future Medicine</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/biotechnological-breakthroughs-mrna-car-t-ai-future-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/biotechnological-breakthroughs-mrna-car-t-ai-future-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main driver of development in the medical field in the past year has been biotechnology. This is evidenced by highly objective indicators such as high publication activity and a substantial increase in both government and commercial funding for research in this area. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the key trends that emerged this year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the key technological breakthroughs in recent years has been the development and integration of mRNA vaccines into clinical practice. Unlike classical vaccines, which consist of a weakened pathogen or its protein, mRNA vaccines do not contain any fragments of the pathogen. They provide human cells with a &amp;ldquo;template&amp;rdquo; for the independent synthesis of the pathogen&amp;rsquo;s proteins, allowing the immune system to respond more rapidly and effectively to the threat. During the pandemic, mRNA vaccines underwent the necessary regulatory procedures and entered clinical practice within a year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy Simulated Without Complex Machinery</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy-simulated-without-complex-machinery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 01:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy-simulated-without-complex-machinery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/the-johns-hopkins-hospital&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;The Johns Hopkins Hospital&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have made a groundbreaking discovery in the field of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC8660605/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hyperbaric oxygen therapy&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. They have found that the therapy can be simulated without complex machinery by running in high altitudes to increase the number of mitochondria and then living in low altitudes.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://journals.biologists.com/jeb&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Experimental Biology&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, found that running in high altitudes can increase the number of mitochondria in the body. Mitochondria are the powerhouses of the cell, responsible for producing energy. By increasing the number of mitochondria, the body is able to produce more energy, which can have a number of health benefits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Salt-Kidney Connection: How Your Salt Habits Impact Chronic Kidney Disease Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists have discovered a link between the frequency of salt intake in food and an increased risk of chronic kidney disease (CKD). The research findings were &lt;a href=&#34;https://jamanetwork.com/journals/jamanetworkopen/fullarticle/2813410&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in the JAMA Network Open journal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Experts analyzed data from 465,288 participants in the long-term UK Biobank study, aged 37 to 73 years, who initially did not have CKD. They were divided into several categories based on self-reported frequency of salt intake (never, rarely, occasionally, usually, and always).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identification of an Active Plasmid in Antibiotic Resistance of Staphylococcus aureus</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/identification-of-an-active-plasmid-in-antibiotic-resistance-of-staphylococcus-aureus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/identification-of-an-active-plasmid-in-antibiotic-resistance-of-staphylococcus-aureus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Berlin, Germany - Researchers from Berlin University have identified a new active plasmid in antibiotic resistance of Staphylococcus aureus. Plasmids are extrachromosomal DNA molecules that can be transferred between bacteria and they often carry antibiotic resistance genes. Staphylococcus aureus is a bacterium commonly found on the skin and in the nose of healthy individuals, but it can also cause infections in humans and animals.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The plasmid, named pSA-03, was identified in a clinical isolate of Staphylococcus aureus collected from a patient with a skin infection. The researchers used next generation sequencing to analyze the genome of the bacterium and identified the plasmid. Further experiments confirmed that pSA-03 is a conjugative plasmid, meaning that it can transfer its genetic material to other bacteria.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reducing Calorie Intake Reduces Risk of Cancer and Metabolic Syndrome, MIT Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reducing-calorie-intake-reduces-risk-cancer-metabolic-syndrome-mit-study-finds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:37:57 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reducing-calorie-intake-reduces-risk-cancer-metabolic-syndrome-mit-study-finds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have found that reducing the calorie intake to the level of calorie restriction significantly reduces the risk of cancer and metabolic syndrome. The study, which was conducted on mice, showed that mice on a calorie-restricted diet had less inflammation and oxidative stress within their bodies, which are known to be markers of disease. The findings were published today in the journal Nature Communications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bees Social Interaction: Revealing the Social Engineering Techniques</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/bees-social-interaction-revealing-the-social-engineering-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 13:53:48 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/bees-social-interaction-revealing-the-social-engineering-techniques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bees are known for their complex social interactions that includes social engineering techniques. A new study conducted at Seoul University has shed light on some of the ways in which bees use social engineering to maintain their hives and ensure the survival of their colonies. The findings of the study were published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/journal/10905&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Insect Behaviour&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; on 12th May 2023.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study was conducted by a team of researchers led by Dr. Kim Sun, a professor in the Department of Ecology at Seoul University. The team used a combination of observation, experimentation, and mathematical modeling to gain insights into the social behavior of bees and how they influence each other through social engineering strategies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Antiaging Drug Modifying TOR Pathway of Immuno System Stem Cells Significantly Increases Lifespan of Mice and Rabbits, with a Promise for Human Aging Treatment</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-antiaging-drug-modifying-tor-pathway-immuno-system-stem-cells-increases-lifespan-mice-rabbits/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:21:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-antiaging-drug-modifying-tor-pathway-immuno-system-stem-cells-increases-lifespan-mice-rabbits/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at Ottawa University reveals a promising new anti-aging drug that modifies the TOR pathway of immunosystem stem cells, leading to a significant increase in the lifespan of mice and rabbits. The study shows that stem cells&amp;rsquo; unique ability to regenerate different types of cells in the body plays a critical role in aging. While stem cells can divide indefinitely, they also have a limited lifespan, leading to a decline in cellular function and ultimately, death. By modifying the TOR pathway that regulates stem cell function, the new drug enhances stem cell longevity and rejuvenates older cells.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Groundbreaking Discovery: Ottawa Scientists Unearth New Soil Microbe Species Thriving 3 Kilometers Below Earth&#39;s Surface</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/ottawa-scientists-discover-new-soil-microbe-species-3-kilometers-below-surface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:36:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/ottawa-scientists-discover-new-soil-microbe-species-3-kilometers-below-surface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ottawa, May 16, 2023 - In a groundbreaking scientific breakthrough, researchers from Ottawa have announced the discovery of a previously unknown soil microbe species that exists in the extreme depths of the Earth. Thriving an astonishing 3 kilometers below the surface, this newly identified microbe has been named &amp;ldquo;Subterraneus ottawensis&amp;rdquo; in honor of its subterranean habitat and the diligent researchers who unveiled its existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This extraordinary finding comes as a result of an extensive scientific expedition led by a team of microbiologists and geologists from Ottawa University. Armed with state-of-the-art equipment and a passion for exploration, they embarked on a mission to uncover the hidden secrets residing deep within the Earth&amp;rsquo;s crust.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
