<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rutin on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/rutin/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rutin on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 09:53:46 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/rutin/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rutein May Be Effective in Combating Osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutein-may-be-effective-in-combating-osteoarthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 09:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutein-may-be-effective-in-combating-osteoarthritis/</guid>
      <description>Rutein (rutin), a flavonoid found in certain fruits and vegetables, may be effective in combating osteoarthritis, according to a recent study conducted at Baylor College of Medicine. Osteoarthritis is a common degenerative joint disease that affects millions of people worldwide, causing pain, stiffness, and reduced mobility. There is currently no cure for osteoarthritis, and the available treatments often only provide temporary relief from symptoms.
Researchers at Baylor College of Medicine set out to investigate the potential benefits of rutein in treating osteoarthritis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Mulberry Fruit Extracts on Skin Aging: Comprehensive Assessments of Their Role in Hindering Glycation and Enhancing Antioxidant Functions, Both in Lab Tests and Real-World Applications.</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mulberry-extracts-anti-aging-antiglycation-antioxidant-evaluations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mulberry-extracts-anti-aging-antiglycation-antioxidant-evaluations/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Mulberry, a versatile agricultural product, is recognized for its health-promoting qualities and is a subject of extensive research as a beneficial health food. This fruit, along with its leaves, twigs, and roots, is packed with active compounds. Analysis has revealed that mulberry fruit primarily comprises two key functional components: polyphenols and polysaccharides, known for their antioxidant, anti-inflammatory, anti-cancer, memory-enhancing, and neuroprotective effects. Mulberry fruit extracts are particularly noted for their phenolic substances, which boost antioxidant enzyme activity and help slow down memory loss in aging by aiding the removal of amyloid-β.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Multifaceted Benefits of Rutin in Managing Diabetes</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/antidiabetic-effects-of-rutin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/antidiabetic-effects-of-rutin/</guid>
      <description>Unveiling Rutin: A Natural Ally Against Diabetes Diabetes, a global health challenge, continues to affect millions worldwide with its array of complications. In the search for effective treatments, natural compounds have garnered significant attention. One such compound, rutin, a flavonoid found in various plants like Fagopyrum esculentum, Ruta graveolens, and Sophora japonica, has shown promising potential in managing diabetes. Ahmad Ghorbani&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive review, &amp;ldquo;Mechanisms of antidiabetic effects of flavonoid rutin&amp;rdquo; in Biomedicine &amp;amp; Pharmacotherapy, 2017, delves into the multifaceted role of rutin in combating diabetes-related challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Neuroprotective Potential of Ruta graveolens</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-neuroprotective-potential-of-ruta-graveolens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-neuroprotective-potential-of-ruta-graveolens/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of traditional and complementary medicine, natural compounds have long been valued for their therapeutic properties. Among these, Ruta graveolens, commonly known as rue, has emerged as a plant of significant interest. Historically used in various forms of traditional medicine, recent scientific investigations have begun to unveil the potential neuroprotective benefits of this plant, particularly in the context of neurodegenerative diseases.
Ruta graveolens in Ethnobotany and Traditional Medicine Ruta graveolens, a perennial plant belonging to the Rutaceae family, has a rich history in ethnobotany and traditional medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutin health effects</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutin-health-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutin-health-effects/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The present-day scientific community now acknowledges flavonoids as a distinct category of therapeutic molecules owing to their varied therapeutic properties. Among these, rutin, alternatively known as vitamin P or rutoside, has been investigated for numerous pharmacological effects. Rutin is found in tea leaves, apples, and various other sources as one of its active constituents. Currently, rutin is recognized for its nutraceutical impact. This post emphasizes the latest information on rutin and its health-promoting effects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
