<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Diabetis on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/diabetis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Diabetis on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 11:18:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/diabetis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Multifaceted Benefits of Rutin in Managing Diabetes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/antidiabetic-effects-of-rutin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/antidiabetic-effects-of-rutin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unveiling-rutin-a-natural-ally-against-diabetes&#34;&gt;Unveiling Rutin: A Natural Ally Against Diabetes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diabetes, a global health challenge, continues to affect millions worldwide with its array of complications. In the search for effective treatments, natural compounds have garnered significant attention. One such compound, rutin, a flavonoid found in various plants like Fagopyrum esculentum, Ruta graveolens, and Sophora japonica, has shown promising potential in managing diabetes. Ahmad Ghorbani&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive review, &amp;ldquo;Mechanisms of antidiabetic effects of flavonoid rutin&amp;rdquo; in Biomedicine &amp;amp; Pharmacotherapy, 2017, delves into the multifaceted role of rutin in combating diabetes-related challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Reiki Sessions Have Very Positive Effects on Blood Sugar Levels and Blood Pressure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/reiki-sessions-positive-effects-blood-sugar-levels-blood-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/reiki-sessions-positive-effects-blood-sugar-levels-blood-pressure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the University of Madrid have found that reiki sessions can have very positive effects on blood sugar levels and blood pressure. This new study could lead to a breakthrough in diabetes and hypertension treatment and prevention.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Reiki is a form of alternative medicine that originated in Japan. It involves placing the hands on or near the body to balance energy levels and promote relaxation. While there has been some debate over the scientific validity of reiki, the therapy has gained popularity in recent years as a complementary treatment for a variety of health conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
