<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cucumbers and cancer on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/cucumbers-and-cancer/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cucumbers and cancer on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:51:22 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/cucumbers-and-cancer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Consuming 100g cucumbers per day may reduce prostate cancer risk by 28%</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/consuming-100g-cucumbers-per-day-may-reduce-prostate-cancer-risk-by-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/consuming-100g-cucumbers-per-day-may-reduce-prostate-cancer-risk-by-28/</guid>
      <description>Consuming 100g of cucumbers a day could help reduce the risk of developing prostate cancer by 28%, according to a study by Manchester University. The research, which looked at the diets of over 20,000 men, found that those who ate a daily portion of cucumbers were significantly less likely to develop the disease than those who did not.
Cucumbers are already known to be a healthy option for those looking to maintain a healthy weight, thanks to their low calorie and high water content.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Consumption of Cucumbers and Tomatoes May Reduce Risk of Small Intestine Cancerous Polyps</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/daily-cucumbers-tomatoes-cancerous-polyps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/daily-cucumbers-tomatoes-cancerous-polyps/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Boston University have found that consuming 100 grams of cucumbers and 100 grams of tomatoes daily could help reduce the risk of small intestine cancerous polyps by up to 43%. The study, which was published in the Journal of Oncology, involved analyzing the dietary habits of over 2,500 participants, all of whom had previously undergone a colonoscopy.
The findings showed that participants who regularly consumed cucumber and tomato experienced a lesser incidence of small intestine polyps compared to those who did not eat these healthy vegetables.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
