<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Developmental Biology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/developmental-biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Developmental Biology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:18:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/developmental-biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Depths: A Dive into Cnidarian Complexity and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-cnidarian-complexity-evolution-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-cnidarian-complexity-evolution-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interview with the Authors on &amp;ldquo;Cnidarian Cell Type Diversity and Regulation Revealed by Whole-Organism Single-Cell RNA-Seq&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samantha Resenberg, Editor of ScienceChronicle.org (SC)&lt;/strong&gt;: Welcome to ScienceChronicle.org! Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into the fascinating world of cnidarians with the authors of a groundbreaking paper. They&amp;rsquo;ve mapped the cell types of the sea anemone &lt;em&gt;Nematostella vectensis&lt;/em&gt; using whole-organism single-cell RNA sequencing. This research reveals the complexity of cnidarian cells and provides insights into genomic regulation and evolution. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hydra&#39;s mechanism of self-assembly is orchestrated by a few key genes shared with mammals</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/hydra-self-assembly-shared-genes-mammals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/hydra-self-assembly-shared-genes-mammals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hydras have long been subjects of interest in the field of developmental biology due to their remarkable ability to self-assemble in a dynamic and highly coordinated fashion. Recent research conducted at Oxford University has shed new light on the underlying genetic mechanisms that orchestrate this process, revealing several key genes that are shared with mammals&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the most fascinating aspects of hydra biology is the way in which these animals can regenerate their entire bodies from just a small piece of tissue. This process of self-assembly is made possible by a complex interplay of genetic and environmental factors that ultimately leads to the formation of a complete and functional organism.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
