<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Atmospheric Science on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/atmospheric-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Atmospheric Science on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 16:13:20 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/atmospheric-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kelvin-Helmholtz Atmospheric Waves Linked To Solar Wind, Say NYY Scientists</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/kelvin-helmholtz-atmospheric-waves-linked-to-solar-wind-say-nyy-scientists/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 16:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/kelvin-helmholtz-atmospheric-waves-linked-to-solar-wind-say-nyy-scientists/</guid>
      <description>Scientists at NYY University in the United States have made significant progress in understanding the Kelvin-Helmholtz atmospheric waves. These waves occur due to the interaction between two fluids with different densities, such as air and wind, in the atmosphere. The waves manifest as long, wavy patterns in the clouds, known as Kelvin-Helmholtz billows, which have puzzled scientists for years. Previous studies suggested that the waves were related to weather patterns, but recent research suggests that they may be connected to solar wind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fallstreak Holes Linked to Brunt-Väisälä Frequency, New Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/fallstreak-holes-linked-to-brunt-vaisala-frequency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:55:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/fallstreak-holes-linked-to-brunt-vaisala-frequency/</guid>
      <description>Fallstreak holes - those mysterious circular or oval holes that occasionally appear in cloud formations - have long fascinated both scientists and the general public. These strange phenomena have been the subject of numerous studies over the years, and now a team of researchers from NY University has made a new breakthrough in our understanding of how they are formed.
According to their research, fallstreak holes in altocumulus clouds are produced in a pattern dictated by Brunt-Väisälä frequency.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
