<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>earth science on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/earth-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in earth science on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:01:48 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/earth-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling Earth&#39;s Mysteries: A Look at Geomagnetic Anomalies Around The World</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/geomagnetic-anomalies-around-the-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 00:01:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/geomagnetic-anomalies-around-the-world/</guid>
      <description>The Earth&amp;rsquo;s magnetic field is not uniform, leading to areas of significant geomagnetic oddities. This editorial examines ten such sites, shedding light on the scientific, historical, and cultural impacts of these anomalies.
The Bermuda Triangle Bermuda Triangle anomalies Location: North Atlantic Ocean Description: A region connecting Miami, Bermuda, and Puerto Rico. Anomaly: Compass malfunctions and navigational issues. Impact: Historical accounts of missing ships and aircraft. Hessdalen Valley Hessdalen Valley anomalies Location: Central Norway Description: Known for unexplained light phenomena.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simulation Shows Effect of Exploding 10 Kiloton Bomb in Mariana Trench on Earth</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/simulation-effect-exploding-10-kiloton-bomb-mariana-trench-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/simulation-effect-exploding-10-kiloton-bomb-mariana-trench-earth/</guid>
      <description>A team of scientists at New York University have conducted a simulation to show the catastrophic effects of detonating a 10 kiloton bomb in the Mariana Trench, the deepest part of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans. The study aimed to examine the potential impact of such an explosion on the planet&amp;rsquo;s geological and environmental systems. The results of the simulation were stunning and suggest that such an event would have devastating consequences on both Earth&amp;rsquo;s natural systems and human civilization.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
