<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ashwaganda and Emotions on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/ashwaganda-and-emotions/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ashwaganda and Emotions on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/ashwaganda-and-emotions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring Ashwagandha: An Interview with Nutritionist Rebecca Wolfson</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/ashwagandha-benefits-explained-rebecca-wolfson-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 00:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/ashwagandha-benefits-explained-rebecca-wolfson-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In an enlightening session with Rebecca Wolfson, a renowned nutritionist, ScienceChronicle.org (SC) delves deep into the world of ashwagandha, uncovering its benefits, usage, and scientific backing. Here&amp;rsquo;s what we learned from our conversation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SC&lt;/strong&gt; Rebecca, it&amp;rsquo;s great to have you with us. To start, can you explain how ashwagandha supports stress reduction?&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Rebecca Wolfson:&lt;/strong&gt; Absolutely, and thank you for having me. Ashwagandha is an adaptogen, which means it helps the body manage stress more effectively. It does this by modulating the stress response, reducing cortisol levels, and enhancing endocrine function, thus offering a natural way to alleviate stress and anxiety.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling Nature&#39;s Calm: Eliana Adams on Ashwagandha and Emotional Well-Being</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/ashwagandha-emotional-well-being-interview-eliana-adams/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 01:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/ashwagandha-emotional-well-being-interview-eliana-adams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this exclusive interview for ScienceChronicle.org, we delve into the fascinating world of botanical pharmacology with renowned Canadian pharmacologist, Eliana Adams. With a focus that spans the breadth of nature&amp;rsquo;s pharmacy, Adams has dedicated her career to uncovering the medicinal secrets held by plants, a pursuit that has led her to become a leading voice in the field. Today, we explore one of the most intriguing yet controversial topics in herbal supplementation: the effects of Ashwagandha.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
