<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nutraceutical Benefits in Allergies on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/nutraceutical-benefits-in-allergies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nutraceutical Benefits in Allergies on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 02:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/nutraceutical-benefits-in-allergies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Nutraceuticals into Allergy Management for Children: A Guide for Healthcare Professionals</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/article/integrating-nutraceuticals-allergy-management-children-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/article/integrating-nutraceuticals-allergy-management-children-guide/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Allergy-related conditions are highly prevalent, encompassing a range of disorders such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Allergic_rhinitis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;allergic rhinitis&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; (AR) — the most frequently observed &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Immunoglobulin_E&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;IgE&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;-mediated condition, along with allergic asthma, food allergies, drug allergies, and reactions to insect stings. These conditions can trigger a broad array of symptoms, from minor itching to severe, potentially fatal, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anaphylaxis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;anaphylactic reactions&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. At the core of allergic diseases is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Type_2_inflammation&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;type 2 inflammatory response&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, marked by an &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Eosinophilic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;eosinophilic&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; infiltration in the nasal mucosa. The persistence of this type of immune reaction is linked to a specific, yet reversible, malfunction in T regulatory cells. Initially, this phenomenon was thought to be explained by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hygiene_hypothesis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;hygiene hypothesis&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, but recent insights have led to its reevaluation and the proposal of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microbiota&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;microbiota&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; hypothesis. Essentially, imbalances in the gut and respiratory microbiota can influence the development of a child&amp;rsquo;s immune system, promoting a type 2 immune orientation. Interestingly, this type 2 immune response begins even before birth, as a mechanism by the mother to prevent rejection of the fetus, leading to an initial type 2 bias in the newborn that must be corrected as the immune system matures toward a more balanced &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cell-mediated_immunity#Type_1_immunity&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;type 1 immunity&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
