<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chemistry on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chemistry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chemistry on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:07:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chemistry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Uncovering the potential of quantum machine learning algorithms for drug discovery</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/uncovering-the-potential-of-quantum-machine-learning-algorithms-for-drug-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:07:24 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/uncovering-the-potential-of-quantum-machine-learning-algorithms-for-drug-discovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists at the University of California, Berkeley have made significant progress in uncovering the vast potential of quantum machine learning algorithms for drug discovery. The research team composed of computer scientists and chemists have demonstrated that quantum computing combined with unsupervised machine learning algorithms can help identify potential drug candidates that can treat diseases more accurately and effectively. The team published their findings on June 9th, 2023, in the journal Nature Communications.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unique Iridium-Osmium Alloy Boosts Efficiency of Electric Car Engines</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unique-iridium-osmium-alloy-boosts-efficiency-of-electric-car-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 22:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unique-iridium-osmium-alloy-boosts-efficiency-of-electric-car-engines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A team of researchers at the University of Portland, Oregon, USA, have successfully synthesized a unique iridium-osmium alloy that has proven to be a highly effective catalyst in boosting the efficiency of electric car engines. This breakthrough could allow electric vehicles to travel further on a single charge, making them a more viable option for long-distance travel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research team&amp;rsquo;s findings were published in the latest issue of the Journal of Renewable Energy. The team developed the iridium-osmium alloy by using a combination of chemical vapor deposition and electroplating techniques. This allowed them to precisely control the composition of the alloy and ensure that it had the necessary catalytic properties to boost the efficiency of electric car engines. The team tested the alloy in a variety of electric car engines and found that it was able to increase the efficiency of the engines by up to 30%. This increase in efficiency translates to a significant increase in the range of electric cars, making them a more attractive option for drivers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
