<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>evolutionary biology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/evolutionary-biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in evolutionary biology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:50:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/evolutionary-biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Type of Monothalamea is Made of More Than 40 Living Distinct Living Clades</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-type-monothalamea-more-than-40-distinct-living-clades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-type-monothalamea-more-than-40-distinct-living-clades/</guid>
      <description>Berlin University has unveiled a new type of monothalamea, a single-celled organism, that is made up of more than 40 distinct living clades. The discovery was made by a team of researchers led by Dr. Maria Schmidt, who spent the last decade studying various single-celled organisms in an effort to better understand their evolution.
The new species, which has not yet been named, was discovered in the depths of the Pacific Ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee University research uncovers new insight into the behavior of ancient marine reptiles</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/tennessee-university-research-uncovers-new-insight-ancient-marine-reptiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/tennessee-university-research-uncovers-new-insight-ancient-marine-reptiles/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Tennessee University have made a groundbreaking discovery regarding the behavior of ancient marine reptiles known as ichthyosaurs. The team&amp;rsquo;s findings, published in the journal “Nature Communications” on May 26, 2023, are based on the analysis of a recently discovered ichthyosaur fossil that dates back 180 million years.
The fossil, which was found in a quarry in Warwickshire, UK, is believed to belong to a new species of ichthyosaur. Researchers named the species “Ichthyosaurus colossus” in recognition of its enormous size, reaching up to 26 feet in length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertebrate species have a wide range of mutation rates, reveals new study from MIT</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/vertebrate-species-have-wide-range-of-mutation-rates-reveals-new-study-from-mit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 09:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/vertebrate-species-have-wide-range-of-mutation-rates-reveals-new-study-from-mit/</guid>
      <description>MIT, 2023- An international research team conducted a study to measure the rate of mutation in a record number of vertebrate species. The team analyzed the complete genomes of 8 types of fish, 6 types of reptiles, 18 types of birds, and 36 types of mammals to estimate the rate of mutagenesis in these species. The results showed significant variations in the rate of mutation in different vertebrate species, ranging from 1 to 40 mutations per billion nucleotides per generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Human Neurons: Evidence of Horizontal Gene Transfer Mediated by Previously Unseen Plasmids</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</guid>
      <description>Scientists at the University of Tokyo have made an incredible discovery regarding the evolution of human neurons. Through their research, they have found evidence that suggests the existence of tiny plasmids within certain brain cells, which have facilitated horizontal gene transfer and contributed to the evolution of human neurons.
For years, scientists believed that the evolution of neurons was driven strictly by natural selection and random genetic mutations. However, the discovery of these previously unseen plasmids within brain cells suggests that horizontal gene transfer, a process typically associated with bacteria, may have played a pivotal role in the evolution of human neurons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein IRBP Supporting Human Visual System Inherited from Bacteria in Horizontal Transfer - Vienna University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/protein-irbp-supporting-human-visual-system-inherited-from-bacteria-in-horizontal-transfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/protein-irbp-supporting-human-visual-system-inherited-from-bacteria-in-horizontal-transfer/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at the Vienna University has discovered that a protein in the human visual system, IRBP, was inherited from bacteria through horizontal transfer. The researchers found evidence that this protein was likely acquired by an ancestral host organism through gene transfer from a photosynthetic bacterium that was engulfed around one billion years ago.
This finding sheds light on the evolutionary origins of the complex machinery behind vision. Prior to this, it was widely believed that the human visual system was entirely of animal origin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Genes Evolve Faster When They Interact With Other Proteins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/critical-genes-evolve-faster-when-they-interact-with-other-proteins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/critical-genes-evolve-faster-when-they-interact-with-other-proteins/</guid>
      <description>Evolutionary biologists have long been intrigued by the mechanisms driving the evolution of genes critical for organismal survival. A new study published in Nature Ecology and Evolution shows that critically important genes seem to evolve faster when their respective proteins interact with other proteins.
The researchers analyzed genome sequence data from 30 randomly chosen pairs of closely related bacterial species and found that quickly evolving genes were more likely to encode proteins that physically interact with other proteins &amp;ndash; a phenomenon known as compensatory effect of a protein complex.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
