<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immunology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/immunology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Immunology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 16:12:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/immunology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Long-term Effects of RNA Vaccines on Immune Responses to West Nile Fever in Israel</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/long-term-effects-rna-vaccines-immune-responses-west-nile-fever-israel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2024 16:12:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/long-term-effects-rna-vaccines-immune-responses-west-nile-fever-israel/</guid>
      <description>In the latest outburst of West Nile fever in Israel, the country is seeing an especially severe strain of the virus with a 25% fatal rate. This outbreak has prompted researchers to explore possible connections between the long-term effects of RNA vaccines used in the prevention of the COVID virus and the compromised immune responses to West Nile fever. The research is taking place in Jerusalem, Israel, where scientists are working diligently to understand the underlying factors driving this concerning trend.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research finds that avocados contain flavonoids that promote gut health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 11:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at New York University have discovered that avocados contain flavonoids that can positively affect the regulatory circuits of T-helper cells in the small intestine. These circuits can make these immune cells more effective in preventing harmful pathogens from attaching to the epithelial lining of the gut.
The study, which was published in the journal Nature Immunology , is believed to be the first to demonstrate the impact of dietary flavonoids on gut immune regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Role of the Microbiome in Modulating the Effectiveness of Cancer Immunotherapies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/role-microbiome-modulating-effectiveness-cancer-immunotherapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/role-microbiome-modulating-effectiveness-cancer-immunotherapies/</guid>
      <description>Johns Hopkins University researchers have discovered the critical role that the microbiome plays in regulating the effectiveness of cancer immunotherapies. The immune system needs to be primed in order to attack tumors. However, many tumors are able to evade immune detection. Immunotherapies seek to enhance the immune system&amp;rsquo;s ability to recognize and attack cancer cells. Until now, it had been largely unclear what factors influence the effectiveness of immunotherapies. The new study found that the presence of certain gut bacteria is crucial for the success of immunotherapy treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
