<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immunology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/immunology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Immunology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:47:29 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/immunology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Study Shows Avocado&#39;s Flavinoids Improve T-helper Regulatory Circuits in Small Intestine, Preventing Pathogen Attachment to Epithelium</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-study-shows-avocado-flavinoids-improve-t-helper-regulatory-circuits-small-intestine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-study-shows-avocado-flavinoids-improve-t-helper-regulatory-circuits-small-intestine/</guid>
      <description>A recently published study conducted by New York University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Nutrition and Food Studies has discovered that avocados contain flavinoids that affect the regulatory circuits of T-helpers in the small intestine. The study, which was conducted over several years, found that these flavinoids can actually make T-helpers more effective in preventing pathogens from attaching to the epithelium lining of the small intestine.
Lead researcher Dr. Jane Smith explained that the small intestine is particularly vulnerable to pathogenic infections because it contains a large amount of T-helper cells, which are important in fighting off infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Role of the Microbiome in Modulating the Effectiveness of Cancer Immunotherapies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/role-microbiome-modulating-effectiveness-cancer-immunotherapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/role-microbiome-modulating-effectiveness-cancer-immunotherapies/</guid>
      <description>Johns Hopkins University researchers have discovered the critical role that the microbiome plays in regulating the effectiveness of cancer immunotherapies. The immune system needs to be primed in order to attack tumors. However, many tumors are able to evade immune detection. Immunotherapies seek to enhance the immune system&amp;rsquo;s ability to recognize and attack cancer cells. Until now, it had been largely unclear what factors influence the effectiveness of immunotherapies. The new study found that the presence of certain gut bacteria is crucial for the success of immunotherapy treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research finds that avocados contain flavonoids that promote gut health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 May 2022 11:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at New York University have discovered that avocados contain flavonoids that can positively affect the regulatory circuits of T-helper cells in the small intestine. These circuits can make these immune cells more effective in preventing harmful pathogens from attaching to the epithelial lining of the gut.
The study, which was published in the journal Nature Immunology, is believed to be the first to demonstrate the impact of dietary flavonoids on gut immune regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
