<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Menstrual Cramps on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/menstrual-cramps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Menstrual Cramps on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:47:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/menstrual-cramps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The effect of zumba exercise on menstrual pain relief</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Menstrual pain, or dysmenorrhea, is a common issue affecting many women worldwide. While various treatments exist, ranging from medication to alternative therapies, an intriguing approach has emerged: Zumba exercise. A recent study conducted by Ahmed Samy et al. delved into this aspect, offering fascinating insights.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-study&#34;&gt;The Study&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study titled &amp;ldquo;The Effect of Zumba Exercise on Reducing Menstrual Pain in Young Women with Primary Dysmenorrhea: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&amp;rdquo; aimed to evaluate the impact of Zumba on menstrual pain severity and duration. Conducted as a randomized controlled trial at Cairo University Gynecology Hospital and Bahgat Gym and Fitness Center, it involved 98 women diagnosed with primary dysmenorrhea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Aromatherapy on Menstrual pain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/the-impact-of-aromatherapy-on-menstrual-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 00:14:18 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/the-impact-of-aromatherapy-on-menstrual-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Menstrual pain, or dysmenorrhea, is a prevalent condition affecting a significant percentage of women globally. Traditional treatments range from non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) to hormonal contraceptives, each with its own set of potential side effects and limitations. In recent years, aromatherapy has emerged as a promising alternative. This editorial explores the efficacy and safety of aromatherapy in managing menstrual pain, drawing on data from a comprehensive systematic review and meta-analysis detailed in a study published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Clinical Medicine&amp;rdquo; (J Clin Med 2018 November 10;7(11)).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
