<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Technology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/medical-technology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medical Technology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 01:24:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/medical-technology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nanoswimmers Can Travel Significant Distances Inside Blood Stream To Find A Cancer Target In The Brain</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/nanoswimmers-can-travel-significant-distances-inside-blood-stream-to-find-a-cancer-target-in-the-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 01:24:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/nanoswimmers-can-travel-significant-distances-inside-blood-stream-to-find-a-cancer-target-in-the-brain/</guid>
      <description>Princeton University scientists have recently made a breakthrough by developing innovative nanoswimmers that can travel a long distance inside the human blood stream to find and attack a cancer target in the brain. This innovative approach is expected to bring about a significant reduction in the number of cancer cell deaths that originate from brain tumors.
These nanoswimmers are composed of tiny, self-propelling robots that are only a few microns in size.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Wearable Biosensors for Real-time Monitoring and Early Detection of Disease Biomarkers</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/developing-wearable-biosensors-real-time-monitoring-early-detection-disease-biomarkers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:05:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/developing-wearable-biosensors-real-time-monitoring-early-detection-disease-biomarkers/</guid>
      <description>Scientists at ETH Zurich are developing a new generation of wearable biosensors for the real-time monitoring and early detection of disease biomarkers. These devices will have the capability to monitor biophysical and biochemical signals in real-time and alert patients and their healthcare providers of potential health issues before they become major problems.
The researchers are focusing on developing thin, flexible electronic devices that can be worn on the skin like a patch or a tattoo without causing discomfort for the patient.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
