<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Astronomy on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/astronomy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Astronomy on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:22:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/astronomy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>LST-1 Telescope Makes First Scientific Discovery</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/lst-1-telescope-makes-first-scientific-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:22:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/lst-1-telescope-makes-first-scientific-discovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Active galaxies are galaxies whose cores emit a large amount of energy due to processes occurring around their supermassive black hole. Quasars are one type of active galactic nucleus. It is rare to be able to detect them in the high-energy range, because the matter of the accretion disk weakens the high-energy radiation: photons with the highest energies are best absorbed. In addition, the further the object, the greater the influence of the extragalactic background light (EBL) on its high-energy radiation, &amp;lsquo;flying&amp;rsquo; to us. Extragalactic background light is the total radiation of objects beyond our Milky Way galaxy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strange Relic Excavated in Sumerian City Uruk Depicts Alien Astronauts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/strange-relic-sumerian-city-uruk-alien-astronauts-2023-jan-18/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 18:50:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/strange-relic-sumerian-city-uruk-alien-astronauts-2023-jan-18/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Exciting news in the world of archaeology! A strange relic has been excavated in the Sumerian city of Uruk, and it has depictions that strongly resemble alien astronauts. This discovery has once again raised theories of extraterrestrial visits to Earth. The relic was uncovered during a routine dig in the ancient city, and it has caused quite a buzz in the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/news/strange-relic-sumerian-city-uruk-alien-astronauts-2023-jan-18/t1.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/news/strange-relic-sumerian-city-uruk-alien-astronauts-2023-jan-18/t2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/news/strange-relic-sumerian-city-uruk-alien-astronauts-2023-jan-18/t3.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/news/strange-relic-sumerian-city-uruk-alien-astronauts-2023-jan-18/t4.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&#xA;&lt;em&gt;Space ships visits?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Experts have been studying the relic, and they are amazed at the depictions of what they believe to be alien visitors. The images show beings that resemble humans but have different characteristics, such as elongated heads, big eyes, and small bodies. In some depictions, they are shown wearing helmets, and in others, they are seen piloting some type of spacecraft. The artifact has sparked renewed interest in the theories of ancient astronauts and the possibility that extraterrestrial life has visited Earth.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rocky Planet in Remote Double Star System Could Have Water Oceans on Surface</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/rocky-planet-in-remote-double-star-system-could-have-water-oceans-on-surface/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/rocky-planet-in-remote-double-star-system-could-have-water-oceans-on-surface/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 12 May 2023, Cape Town Observatory scientists released a report regarding the possibility of a rocky planet in a remote double star system having water oceans on its surface. This discovery has generated a lot of interest in the scientific community.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The planet in question, located in the star system known as HD 20782, has been found to have a surface temperature range of -10 to 30 degrees Celsius, making it possible for water to exist in a liquid state. The planet has an estimated mass and radius of 1.4 Earths, with a year that lasts approximately 386 Earth days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Astronomers Discover Spectacular Double Star System: Introducing &#34;Celestial Duos&#34;</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/astronomers-discover-spectacular-double-star-system-celestial-duos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 May 2023 14:36:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/astronomers-discover-spectacular-double-star-system-celestial-duos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prepare to be astounded by the latest discovery in the vast expanse of our universe! Astronomers have unveiled an extraordinary double star system, which they have aptly named &amp;ldquo;Celestial Duos.&amp;rdquo; This stunning celestial formation promises to provide valuable insights into the mysteries of stellar evolution and captivate stargazers with its celestial dance.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Located millions of light-years away, &amp;ldquo;Celestial Duos&amp;rdquo; is a mesmerizing pair of stars locked in an elegant cosmic embrace. The system consists of two massive stars of comparable size and brilliance, orbiting each other in a delicate celestial ballet. Their radiance illuminates the surrounding space, casting a spellbinding glow that captivates observers both amateur and professional.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
