<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nutritional Content Dried Fruits on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/nutritional-content-dried-fruits/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nutritional Content Dried Fruits on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 02:20:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/nutritional-content-dried-fruits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Nutritional Secrets of Dried Fruits: A Comprehensive Review and Expert Insights</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/health-benefits-safety-dried-fruits-study-insights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 02:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/health-benefits-safety-dried-fruits-study-insights/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The research article &lt;a href=&#34;http://dx.doi.org/10.1016/j.foodchem.2016.10.049&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Potential health benefits and quality of dried fruits: goji fruits, cranberries and raisins&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; written by Magdalena Jeszka-Skowron and colleguages presents a comprehensive study on the health benefits and quality of dried fruits, with a focus on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Goji&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;goji berries&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cranberry&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cranberries&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raisin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;raisins&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. It extensively explores their &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Antioxidant&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;antioxidant&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; activity, mineral content, and safety levels, offering valuable insights into their contribution to a healthy diet. The study&amp;rsquo;s findings highlight the superior antioxidant properties of goji berries compared to the other fruits tested, as well as reassuring data regarding the low levels of contaminants, which underlines the safety of these dried fruits for consumption. The correlation found between &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Manganese&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;manganese&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; content and antioxidant activity opens new avenues for understanding the nutritional importance of these fruits. This research significantly contributes to the existing body of knowledge by providing a detailed analysis of the potential health benefits of including dried fruits in our diets, emphasizing their role in enhancing overall health and wellness.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
