<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>pharmacology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/pharmacology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in pharmacology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/pharmacology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Neuroprotective Potential of Ruta graveolens</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/exploring-the-neuroprotective-potential-of-ruta-graveolens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/exploring-the-neuroprotective-potential-of-ruta-graveolens/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the Neuroprotective Potential of Ruta graveolens Introduction to Ruta graveolens and Its Relevance in Modern Medicine In the realm of traditional and complementary medicine, natural compounds have long been valued for their therapeutic properties. Among these, Ruta graveolens, commonly known as rue, has emerged as a plant of significant interest. Historically used in various forms of traditional medicine, recent scientific investigations have begun to unveil the potential neuroprotective benefits of this plant, particularly in the context of neurodegenerative diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutin health effects</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/rutin-health-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/rutin-health-effects/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The present-day scientific community now acknowledges flavonoids as a distinct category of therapeutic molecules owing to their varied therapeutic properties. Among these, rutin, alternatively known as vitamin P or rutoside, has been investigated for numerous pharmacological effects. Rutin is found in tea leaves, apples, and various other sources as one of its active constituents. Currently, rutin is recognized for its nutraceutical impact. This post emphasizes the latest information on rutin and its health-promoting effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Duration of Brain Zap Can Accompany Treatment with SSRI</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/duration-brain-zap-accompany-treatment-ssri/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:52:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/duration-brain-zap-accompany-treatment-ssri/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted at Toronto University has found that brain zaps, a common side effect experienced during treatment with Selective Serotonin Reuptake Inhibitors (SSRIs), can persist throughout the entire duration of the treatment and may only disappear a week after discontinuing the medication.
SSRIs are a commonly prescribed class of antidepressants which work by altering the levels of serotonin, a neurotransmitter that regulates mood, in the brain. Some of the most well-known SSRIs include Prozac, Zoloft, and Lexapro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citalopram-induced Sexual Disorgasmia is an Expected Result of Antidepressant Treatment, Says Manchester University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 14:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted by researchers at Manchester University has found that citalopram, a drug commonly used to treat depression, can lead to sexual dysfunctions known as disorgasmia. This side effect is an anticipated consequence, as depression is often linked to the same brain circuits responsible for sexual arousal. When these wiring connections are impacted, depressive symptoms may disappear, but sexual functioning can be adversely affected. This study sheds light on this relationship and highlights the need for further research into potential interventions to address this common concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hydroxylized Mometasone Furoate Could Diminish Adverse Effects of Topical Psoriasis Treatment</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/hydroxylized-mometasone-furoate-diminish-adverse-effects-topical-psoriasis-treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:46:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/hydroxylized-mometasone-furoate-diminish-adverse-effects-topical-psoriasis-treatment/</guid>
      <description>Topical psoriasis is a chronic inflammatory skin disease that affects millions worldwide and can significantly reduce a patient’s quality of life. Corticosteroids, such as mometasone furoate, are often used to alleviate the symptoms of psoriasis. However, the use of these medications can have adverse effects, such as skin atrophy and telangiectasia. A recent study conducted in South California, USA, aimed to explore whether hydroxylated mometasone furoate could effectively treat psoriasis while diminishing these adverse effects.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
