<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Natural Remedies on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/natural-remedies/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Natural Remedies on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:47:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/natural-remedies/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The effects of chia seed consumption on reducing mild psoriasis symptoms</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effects-of-chia-seed-consumption-on-reducing-mild-psoriasis-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 12:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effects-of-chia-seed-consumption-on-reducing-mild-psoriasis-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Psoriasis, a chronic inflammatory skin condition, affects millions of individuals worldwide. While conventional treatments aim to control symptoms, natural dietary supplements are gaining attention for their potential therapeutic effects. This study investigates the impact of chia seed consumption on mild psoriasis symptoms over a 12-week period. Participants consuming chia seeds exhibited a significant reduction in &lt;strong&gt;Psoriasis Area and Severity Index (PASI)&lt;/strong&gt; scores, inflammation markers, and improvements in skin hydration. These findings suggest that chia seeds may serve as a natural, complementary therapy for managing psoriasis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Avocado Nourishing Hydration Mask Has Great Potential to Prevent Aging of Face Skin</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/avocado-nourishing-hydration-mask-prevent-aging-face-skin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 09:05:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/avocado-nourishing-hydration-mask-prevent-aging-face-skin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Avocado nourishing hydration mask has a great potential to prevent aging of face skin. Researchers at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ibmpan.pl/en/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Institute of Medical Biology (IMB)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have discovered that avocado nourishing hydration mask has a great potential to prevent aging of face skin. The study, published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jdsjournal.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Dermatological Science&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, found that the avocado nourishing hydration mask was able to significantly increase the moisture content and elasticity of the skin, which are key factors in preventing the signs of aging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the World of Berries: Health Benefits and Popular Varieties in North America</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From a botanical perspective, the term &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; specifically refers to pulpy fruits that develop from a single ovary enclosing seeds. Examples of true berries encompass bananas, grapes, and blueberries. However, in the context of this discussion, &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; are identified as small, tender, palatable, and vibrantly colored fruits primarily from the Vaccinium, Fragaria, and Rubus species. Berries are increasingly recognized for their substantial health contributions in diets. Predominantly consumed berries in North America are blackberries (Rubus species), red (Rubus idaeus) and black raspberries (Rubus occidentalis), blueberries (Vaccinium corymbosum), cranberries (V. macrocarpon), and strawberries (Fragaria ananassa). Consumption of other varieties like bilberries, lingonberries, goji berries (Lycium barbarum), and sea buckthorn (SBT; Hippophae rhamnoides) is less widespread. The growing popularity of certain exotic berries such as acai berries and honeysuckle (Lonicera caerulea) is also noteworthy. This exposition primarily delves into the widely favored berries in North America, particularly those from the Rubus and Vaccinium genera, along with a focus on select exotic varieties like acai berries, honeysuckle, and SBT.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
