<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Energy on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/energy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Energy on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 22:42:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/energy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unique Iridium-Osmium Alloy Boosts Efficiency of Electric Car Engines</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unique-iridium-osmium-alloy-boosts-efficiency-of-electric-car-engines/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 22:42:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unique-iridium-osmium-alloy-boosts-efficiency-of-electric-car-engines/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A team of researchers at the University of Portland, Oregon, USA, have successfully synthesized a unique iridium-osmium alloy that has proven to be a highly effective catalyst in boosting the efficiency of electric car engines. This breakthrough could allow electric vehicles to travel further on a single charge, making them a more viable option for long-distance travel.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research team&amp;rsquo;s findings were published in the latest issue of the Journal of Renewable Energy. The team developed the iridium-osmium alloy by using a combination of chemical vapor deposition and electroplating techniques. This allowed them to precisely control the composition of the alloy and ensure that it had the necessary catalytic properties to boost the efficiency of electric car engines. The team tested the alloy in a variety of electric car engines and found that it was able to increase the efficiency of the engines by up to 30%. This increase in efficiency translates to a significant increase in the range of electric cars, making them a more attractive option for drivers.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Crystal Lattice with Unique Piezo Effect Discovered at London University</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-crystal-lattice-piezo-effect-london-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:22:50 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-crystal-lattice-piezo-effect-london-university/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking discovery, researchers at London University have identified a new crystal lattice with a unique piezo effect that produces high electrical current. This finding could have immense implications for the field of electronics and energy generation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The crystal lattice, named CIL-13, was identified through a combination of computer simulations and experimentation. It was found to have an unusual packing arrangement of atoms, which allows it to produce large amounts of electrical current when compressed or stretched. This property, known as the piezo effect, has been observed in other materials, but the magnitude of the effect in CIL-13 is significantly higher than anything previously observed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
