<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>paleontology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/paleontology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in paleontology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:01:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/paleontology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee University research uncovers new insight into the behavior of ancient marine reptiles</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/tennessee-university-research-uncovers-new-insight-ancient-marine-reptiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/tennessee-university-research-uncovers-new-insight-ancient-marine-reptiles/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Tennessee University have made a groundbreaking discovery regarding the behavior of ancient marine reptiles known as ichthyosaurs. The team&amp;rsquo;s findings, published in the journal “Nature Communications” on May 26, 2023, are based on the analysis of a recently discovered ichthyosaur fossil that dates back 180 million years.
The fossil, which was found in a quarry in Warwickshire, UK, is believed to belong to a new species of ichthyosaur. Researchers named the species “Ichthyosaurus colossus” in recognition of its enormous size, reaching up to 26 feet in length.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabretooth Extinction Due to Climate Change- Scientific Report from Michigan University</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/sabretooth-extinction-climate-change-michigan-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:32:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/sabretooth-extinction-climate-change-michigan-university/</guid>
      <description>Sabretooth is a well-known prehistoric predator that went extinct around 10,000 years ago during the last ice age. There are various theories about what caused their extinction, but the most accepted one is that climate change led to the shrinking of their prey, which caused them to struggle to find enough food to survive. This research is focused on the correlation between the disappearance of Sabretooth and the changes in climate which caused their prey to diminish in size.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
