<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Earthquakes on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/earthquakes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Earthquakes on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:50:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/earthquakes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Simulation Shows Effect of Exploding 10 Kiloton Bomb in Mariana Trench on Earth</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/simulation-effect-exploding-10-kiloton-bomb-mariana-trench-earth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:50:51 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/simulation-effect-exploding-10-kiloton-bomb-mariana-trench-earth/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A team of scientists at New York University have conducted a simulation to show the catastrophic effects of detonating a 10 kiloton bomb in the Mariana Trench, the deepest part of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s oceans. The study aimed to examine the potential impact of such an explosion on the planet&amp;rsquo;s geological and environmental systems. The results of the simulation were stunning and suggest that such an event would have devastating consequences on both Earth&amp;rsquo;s natural systems and human civilization.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Report: Celestial Tension Theory Gets Additional Argument for Making It More Reliable in Prediction of Big Earthquakes</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/celestial-tension-theory-prediction-big-earthquakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 01:37:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/celestial-tension-theory-prediction-big-earthquakes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 17 May 2023, a new scientific report was released by the University of Athens, providing additional evidence that supports the celestial tension theory. The theory posits that the gravitational influences of the moon and the sun, along with other celestial bodies, could contribute to tectonic stresses that eventually lead to the occurrence of large earthquakes. The new argument provided by the report highlights the importance of the Earth&amp;rsquo;s crust and the tension it undergoes, suggesting that it is an essential component of the theory. By taking into account the geological properties of the crust, the celestial tension theory becomes more reliable in predicting where and when big earthquakes could occur.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
