<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Science on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/medical-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medical Science on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 13:44:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/medical-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BiochemIQ: Mastering Medical Biochemistry</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/biochem-iq-medical-biochemistry-quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 13:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/biochem-iq-medical-biochemistry-quiz/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Medical biochemistry is a fascinating field that delves into the intricate biochemical processes within the human body, deciphering the molecular underpinnings of health and disease. As a bridge between basic biochemistry and clinical medicine, it forms the foundation for understanding various medical conditions, their diagnoses, and treatments. In this article, we present 20 thought-provoking multiple-choice questions that not only test your knowledge but also encourage you to think critically and deduce answers from your understanding of biochemistry. These questions are designed to challenge your comprehension of biochemical principles and their real-world applications, requiring multiple logical steps to arrive at the correct answers. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a medical student, healthcare professional, or simply intrigued by the intersection of biology and medicine, join us on a journey through the complex world of medical biochemistry as we explore these questions and their detailed explanations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meditation as a Treatment for Untreated Medical Conditions</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/meditation-treatment-untreated-medical-conditions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:19:01 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/meditation-treatment-untreated-medical-conditions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Meditation has long been touted as a natural and effective method to treat various medical conditions, but recent research from &lt;a href=&#34;https://institut-curie.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Institut Curie&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; is shedding new light on the potential benefits of meditation for treating conditions that have traditionally been difficult to manage. In a groundbreaking study, researchers found that meditation can be a very effective method to treat untreated medical conditions such as schizophrenia, psoriasis, and varicose veins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Schizophrenia is a chronic and severe mental disorder that affects how a person thinks, feels, and behaves. It is one of the most challenging mental health conditions to treat, with traditional medications often providing limited relief from symptoms. However, the new research suggests that meditation could be a game-changer in the treatment of schizophrenia. Studies have shown that meditation can help reduce the severity of symptoms and improve overall quality of life for individuals living with schizophrenia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
