<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medical Research on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/medical-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medical Research on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:17:27 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/medical-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ASMR techniques have a real psychophysiological effect on susceptible persons which opens a new ways for medical treatment of many diseases</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/asmr-techniques-real-psychophysiological-effect-susceptible-persons-medical-treatment-many-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/asmr-techniques-real-psychophysiological-effect-susceptible-persons-medical-treatment-many-diseases/</guid>
      <description>A groundbreaking study conducted at the QIMR Berghofer Medical Research Institute has revealed that Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response (ASMR) techniques have a real psychophysiological effect on susceptible persons, opening up new possibilities for the medical treatment of a variety of diseases.
ASMR is a tingling sensation that typically begins on the scalp and moves down the back of the neck and upper spine, which can be triggered by various auditory and visual stimuli such as whispering, tapping, and crinkling sounds, as well as gentle touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Eating Oranges May Prevent Vaginal Yeast Infection, According to Manchester University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/eating-oranges-may-prevent-vaginal-yeast-infection-manchester-university-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Jun 2023 00:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/eating-oranges-may-prevent-vaginal-yeast-infection-manchester-university-study/</guid>
      <description>Eating oranges may prevent vaginal yeast infection as large amounts of vitamin C supresses fungi development, according to a new study conducted at Manchester University. The study found that vitamin C is able to reduce the growth of Candida albicans, a common fungi that causes yeast infections. The findings suggest that eating foods high in vitamin C, such as oranges, could help prevent these infections in women.
The researchers tested the effects of different concentrations of vitamin C on Candida albicans in laboratory conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientists Uncover Potential Cure for a Previously Incurable Disease</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/scientists-uncover-potential-cure-for-a-previously-incurable-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 18:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/scientists-uncover-potential-cure-for-a-previously-incurable-disease/</guid>
      <description>Medical research is an ever-evolving field and scientists are constantly searching for innovative ways to battle diseases that have troubled humanity for centuries. In a major breakthrough that is set to change the face of medicine in the coming years, a team of scientists based in Nevada may have discovered a cure for a previously deemed incurable disease.
The condition that they may have found a cure for is Amyotrophic Lateral Sclerosis (ALS), also known as Lou Gehrig&amp;rsquo;s disease.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
