<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Steve Horvath Aging on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/steve-horvath-aging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Steve Horvath Aging on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/steve-horvath-aging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Deciphering Longevity: Unveiling the Accuracy of Centenarian Clocks in Age Estimation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/centenarian-clocks-a-new-study-to-validate-claims-of-exceptional-longevity/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/centenarian-clocks-a-new-study-to-validate-claims-of-exceptional-longevity/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A very interesting study was published in the article &amp;ldquo;Centenarian Clocks: Epigenetic Clocks for Validating Claims of Exceptional Longevity.&amp;rdquo; This groundbreaking research introduces three DNA methylation-based age estimators, or &amp;rsquo;epigenetic clocks&amp;rsquo;, specifically designed to verify age claims of centenarians. The study utilized an extensive dataset comprising over 7000 blood and saliva samples, including significant contributions from centenarians, semi-supercentenarians, and supercentenarians.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research begins by highlighting the limitations of standard epigenetic clocks, especially their tendency to underestimate the ages of extremely old individuals. To address this, the researchers developed &amp;lsquo;Centenarian Clocks&amp;rsquo; using advanced machine learning techniques, including elastic net regression and neural networks. These clocks demonstrated improved accuracy in predicting the ages of centenarians compared to standard clocks.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
