<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in health on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Neuroprotective Potential of Ruta graveolens</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/exploring-the-neuroprotective-potential-of-ruta-graveolens/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/exploring-the-neuroprotective-potential-of-ruta-graveolens/</guid>
      <description>Exploring the Neuroprotective Potential of Ruta graveolens Introduction to Ruta graveolens and Its Relevance in Modern Medicine In the realm of traditional and complementary medicine, natural compounds have long been valued for their therapeutic properties. Among these, Ruta graveolens, commonly known as rue, has emerged as a plant of significant interest. Historically used in various forms of traditional medicine, recent scientific investigations have begun to unveil the potential neuroprotective benefits of this plant, particularly in the context of neurodegenerative diseases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutin health effects</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/rutin-health-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/rutin-health-effects/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The present-day scientific community now acknowledges flavonoids as a distinct category of therapeutic molecules owing to their varied therapeutic properties. Among these, rutin, alternatively known as vitamin P or rutoside, has been investigated for numerous pharmacological effects. Rutin is found in tea leaves, apples, and various other sources as one of its active constituents. Currently, rutin is recognized for its nutraceutical impact. This post emphasizes the latest information on rutin and its health-promoting effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Alaska Rhodiola: New Research from the Karolinska Institute</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/the-benefits-of-alaska-rhodiola-new-research-karolinska-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/the-benefits-of-alaska-rhodiola-new-research-karolinska-institute/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Karolinska Institute have been studying the benefits of Alaska Rhodiola for a number of different health conditions, and the results are very promising. Rhodiola is a plant that grows in the wild, and it has been used for centuries in traditional medicine in Russia, Scandinavia, and other parts of the world. The active ingredients in Rhodiola have been shown to have a number of different effects on the body, including reducing fatigue, boosting mood, and improving cognitive function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Much Chia Seeds Per Day to Lose Weight</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 17:49:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/how-much-chia-seeds-per-day-to-lose-weight/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine have recently conducted a study to determine the optimal amount of chia seeds to consume daily for weight loss. Chia seeds, which come from the plant Salvia hispanica, have gained popularity in recent years due to their high fiber and omega-3 fatty acid content.
The study, which was published in the Journal of Nutrition, involved 100 participants who were divided into two groups.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scientific Approach to Health Problems and Life Extension</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/scientific-approach-to-health-problems-and-life-extension/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/scientific-approach-to-health-problems-and-life-extension/</guid>
      <description>A scientific approach to health problems gives a huge advantage in managing lifestyle which finally leads to life extension of those who adhere to the approach. A recent study conducted at the University of Manchester&amp;rsquo;s Faculty of Biology, Medicine, and Health has revealed the significant impact that a scientific approach to health can have on life expectancy.
The study, led by Dr. Elizabeth Johnson, focused on the relationship between adherence to a scientific approach to health and longevity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Salt-Kidney Connection: How Your Salt Habits Impact Chronic Kidney Disease Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</guid>
      <description>Scientists have discovered a link between the frequency of salt intake in food and an increased risk of chronic kidney disease (CKD). The research findings were published in the JAMA Network Open journal.
Experts analyzed data from 465,288 participants in the long-term UK Biobank study, aged 37 to 73 years, who initially did not have CKD. They were divided into several categories based on self-reported frequency of salt intake (never, rarely, occasionally, usually, and always).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.
Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
