<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Microbiology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/microbiology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Microbiology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:50:21 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/microbiology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Type of Monothalamea is Made of More Than 40 Living Distinct Living Clades</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-type-monothalamea-more-than-40-distinct-living-clades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-type-monothalamea-more-than-40-distinct-living-clades/</guid>
      <description>Berlin University has unveiled a new type of monothalamea, a single-celled organism, that is made up of more than 40 distinct living clades. The discovery was made by a team of researchers led by Dr. Maria Schmidt, who spent the last decade studying various single-celled organisms in an effort to better understand their evolution.
The new species, which has not yet been named, was discovered in the depths of the Pacific Ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cymothoa exigua co-evolved with previously unknown bacteria which carries some types of plasmids with can faciliate parasite-host interactions</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/cymothoa-exigua-co-evolved-with-previously-unknown-bacteria-which-carries-some-types-of-plasmids-with-can-faciliate-parasite-host-interactions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 23:17:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/cymothoa-exigua-co-evolved-with-previously-unknown-bacteria-which-carries-some-types-of-plasmids-with-can-faciliate-parasite-host-interactions/</guid>
      <description>Cymothoa exigua is a type of parasitic crustacean that feeds on the tongue of fish and then attaches itself to the stub of the tongue where it lives out the rest of its life. It&amp;rsquo;s a well-studied organism, known for its curious adaptations that allow it to survive in its unique environment. Recently, researchers have discovered that Cymothoa exigua may have co-evolved with previously unknown bacteria, which carries some types of plasmids that can facilitate parasite-host interactions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Identification of an Active Plasmid in Antibiotic Resistance of Staphylococcus aureus</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/identification-of-an-active-plasmid-in-antibiotic-resistance-of-staphylococcus-aureus/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:35:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/identification-of-an-active-plasmid-in-antibiotic-resistance-of-staphylococcus-aureus/</guid>
      <description>Berlin, Germany - Researchers from Berlin University have identified a new active plasmid in antibiotic resistance of Staphylococcus aureus. Plasmids are extrachromosomal DNA molecules that can be transferred between bacteria and they often carry antibiotic resistance genes. Staphylococcus aureus is a bacterium commonly found on the skin and in the nose of healthy individuals, but it can also cause infections in humans and animals.
The plasmid, named pSA-03, was identified in a clinical isolate of Staphylococcus aureus collected from a patient with a skin infection.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geomagnetic field may influence behaviour of wood mycorrhizas</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mycorrhizas-influence-geomagnetic-field/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:33:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mycorrhizas-influence-geomagnetic-field/</guid>
      <description>Scientists from Helsinki University have discovered that the behaviour of wood mycorrhizas, the symbiotic relationships between fungi and plants, may be influenced by changes in the Earth&amp;rsquo;s geomagnetic field.
The research, led by Dr. Maria Kõljalg, studied the growth rates and activity of different species of wood mycorrhizas in a controlled laboratory environment. By exposing the fungi to different levels and orientations of simulated magnetic fields, the researchers found that there was a correlation between the strength and direction of the field and the behaviour of the mycorrhizas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mosquitoes may transfer microscopic parasitic worms that carry antibiotic resistance genes</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mosquitoes-microscopic-parasitic-worms-antibiotic-resistance-genes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:29:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mosquitoes-microscopic-parasitic-worms-antibiotic-resistance-genes/</guid>
      <description>Scientists from the University of Jakarta, Indonesia, have discovered that mosquitoes can transfer microscopic parasitic worms known as filarial nematodes, which carry antibiotic resistance genes. This could mean that the spread of antibiotic resistance is not just limited to human-to-human contact but can also be transmitted through these tiny insects. The research has opened up new possibilities for the prevention and treatment of bacterial infections and the development of new antibiotic therapies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sulfolobus solfataricus Has Nucleolus-like Structures Involved in Ribosome Formation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/sulfolobus-solfataricus-nucleolus-like-structures-ribosome-formation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 22:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/sulfolobus-solfataricus-nucleolus-like-structures-ribosome-formation/</guid>
      <description>Sulfolobus solfataricus is an archaeon that belongs to the phylum Crenarchaeota and is known for inhabiting acidic hot springs. One of the most striking features of this microorganism is the absence of a formed nucleus within its cell. However, recent studies have shown that ribosome formation happens on similar structures named nucleolus. This is a surprising discovery because the nucleolus is a hallmark of eukaryotic cells, which have a well-defined nucleus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Species of Soil Bacteria Discovered 3 km Underground</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-species-of-soil-bacteria-discovered-3-km-underground/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 20:23:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-species-of-soil-bacteria-discovered-3-km-underground/</guid>
      <description>Scientists at Adelaida University have made a ground-breaking discovery of a new soil bacteria species living as deep as 3 km under the surface. This new species, named DeepDownia profundum, was found in sedimentary rock samples collected from a borehole in the Adelaida Basin. The identification was confirmed through advanced DNA sequencing and comparison to existing bacteria species in scientific databases.
What makes this discovery significant is the extreme depth at which DeepDownia profundum was found.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
