<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medicine on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/categories/medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medicine on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 04:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/categories/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Glutamine in Your Diet</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-importance-of-glutamine-in-your-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 04:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-importance-of-glutamine-in-your-diet/</guid>
      <description>Glutamine, often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;conditionally essential &amp;rdquo; amino acid, plays a crucial role in various physiological functions within the human body. In this article, we will explore why consuming glutamine is important for overall health and well-being.
What is Glutamine? Glutamine is the most abundant amino acid in the bloodstream and is synthesized primarily in skeletal muscle . It serves as a building block for proteins and also plays a key role in cellular energy production.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Mysteries of Medical Biochemistry: A Challenging Quiz</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/medical-biochemistry-quiz-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/medical-biochemistry-quiz-challenge/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to &amp;ldquo;Unlocking the Mysteries of Medical Biochemistry: A Challenging Quiz&amp;rdquo;! This quiz is crafted for those passionate about the intricate world of medicine and biochemistry. It offers a deep dive into the biochemical basis of diseases, exploring how genetic conditions, enzyme deficiencies, and vitamin imbalances can lead to specific medical symptoms and diagnoses. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a medical student, a practicing healthcare professional, or simply a science enthusiast, this quiz will challenge your knowledge, sharpen your critical thinking skills, and enhance your understanding of the fundamental processes that drive human health and disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citalopram-induced Sexual Disorgasmia is an Expected Result of Antidepressant Treatment, Says Manchester University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted by researchers at Manchester University has found that citalopram, a drug commonly used to treat depression, can lead to sexual dysfunctions known as disorgasmia. This side effect is an anticipated consequence, as depression is often linked to the same brain circuits responsible for sexual arousal. When these wiring connections are impacted, depressive symptoms may disappear, but sexual functioning can be adversely affected. This study sheds light on this relationship and highlights the need for further research into potential interventions to address this common concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Master Your Vitamin Knowledge: Essential Nutrients Unveiled</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/master-your-vitamin-knowledge-essential-nutrients-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/master-your-vitamin-knowledge-essential-nutrients-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>Embark on a journey through the vibrant and essential universe of vitamins with our comprehensive quiz. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a nutrition enthusiast, a health professional, or simply curious about how vitamins influence bodily functions, this quiz is designed to enrich your understanding and test your knowledge. From the roles of vitamins in energy metabolism and immune support to their importance in preventing deficiency diseases, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover fascinating facts and gain insights into maintaining optimal health through nutrition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Analysis of Musculoskeletal Disorders: Osteoarthritis, Gout, Hyperuricemia, Crystal Arthritis, Osteoporosis, Metabolic Bone Disease, and Rheumatoid Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/comparative-analysis-musculoskeletal-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/comparative-analysis-musculoskeletal-disorders/</guid>
      <description>This article presents a comparative analysis of several major musculoskeletal disorders: Osteoarthritis (OA), Gout, Hyperuricemia, Crystal Arthritis, Osteoporosis, Metabolic Bone Disease (MBD), and Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA). The focus is on the etiological factors, pathophysiology, and key clinical manifestations of each condition. Understanding these aspects is crucial for accurate diagnosis, management, and therapeutic interventions.
Introduction Musculoskeletal disorders encompass a range of conditions affecting the bones, joints, and connective tissues. They can result from various causes, including genetic predisposition, metabolic imbalances, autoimmune responses, and physical wear and tear.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Health: The Promising Horizon of Exercise Mimetics</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/revolutionizing-health-the-promising-horizon-of-exercise-mimetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/revolutionizing-health-the-promising-horizon-of-exercise-mimetics/</guid>
      <description>Definition and Development of Exercise Mimetics Exercise mimetics, an emerging concept in the field of medical science, refer to molecules or microorganisms designed to replicate the health benefits of physical exercise. These innovative agents are poised to revolutionize drug development by potentially overcoming some of the limitations inherent in traditional pharmaceutical approaches. The primary objective of exercise mimetics is to activate the same physiological pathways that are stimulated during physical activities, such as running or swimming.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mannosidosis: Treatment and Management</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mannosidosis-treatment-and-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 09:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mannosidosis-treatment-and-management/</guid>
      <description>Mannosidosis, a rare genetic disorder and metabolic anomaly, arises when the body fails to efficiently break down mannose sugar chains. This inability leads to an accumulation of sugar-laden compounds in various cells, tissues, and even urine, disrupting regular bodily functions and skeletal development.
Description The onset of Mannosidosis is linked to a genetic inability to produce a specific enzyme vital for lysosomes, the cell&amp;rsquo;s structures tasked with breaking down proteins, sugars, and fats, and recycling them into other molecules.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Overview of Reticular Dysgenesis: History, Clinical Profile, Genetic Insights, and Treatment Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reticular-dysgenesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 10:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reticular-dysgenesis/</guid>
      <description>History In 1959, De Vaal and Seynhaeve first documented a case of severe combined immunodeficiency (SCID) accompanied by congenital absence of white blood cells. This discovery was based on observations of monozygotic twin boys, born prematurely, who had no white blood cells at birth. Post-mortem examination of these infants, who unfortunately died from septic complications as neonates, showed conditions consistent with SCID. This included the absence of lymphoid cells in their lymphoid organs and myeloid cells in their bone marrow, while erythroid cells and megakaryocytes were present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Minute Running Exercise and Protein Consumption Can Strengthen Achilles Tendon Threefold</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/10-minute-running-exercise-protein-consumption-can-strengthen-achilles-tendon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/10-minute-running-exercise-protein-consumption-can-strengthen-achilles-tendon/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted by the London University has shown that a simple running exercise and protein consumption can make a huge difference in the strengthening of Achilles tendon. According to the study, performing a 10-minute running exercise every day and consuming at least 30 grams of protein and chondroitin can make the Achilles tendon three times stronger!
The Achilles tendon is the largest tendon in the body, and it connects the calf muscles to the heel bone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
