<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Medicine on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/categories/medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Medicine on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 13:14:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/categories/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coffee and Aerobic Exercise: A Potential Treatment for Vaginal Yeast Infections</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/coffee-and-aerobic-exercise-potential-treatment-vaginal-yeast-infections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 13:14:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/coffee-and-aerobic-exercise-potential-treatment-vaginal-yeast-infections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.adelaidemedicalcentre.nhs.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Adelaiada Medical Center&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have made a groundbreaking discovery that could change the way women approach the treatment of vaginal yeast infections. Contrary to general beliefs, a new study suggests that &lt;strong&gt;coffee can be recommended&lt;/strong&gt; for treating these infections, but with a catch - women must engage in very intensive aerobic exercises while consuming the beverage.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, led by Dr. Sophia Rodriguez and her team, focused on the effects of coffee consumption on vaginal yeast infections in relation to aerobic exercise. The findings, published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.medicinearticle.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Medical Research&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, revealed that caffeine induces the creation of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/articles/s41580-020-0230-3&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;reactive oxygen species (ROS)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; under high aerobic conditions. These ROS species effectively suppress the growth of yeast, providing a potential new treatment for vaginal infections.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Prevents Yeast Infections in 86% of Cases, Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/garlic-prevents-yeast-infections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 12:54:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/garlic-prevents-yeast-infections/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study conducted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcm.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Baylor College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has found that consuming 50 grams of garlic per week can effectively prevent yeast infections in 86 out of 100 cases. The research, led by Dr. Maria Rodriguez and her team, sought to investigate the potential health benefits of garlic in preventing yeast infections, which affect millions of people worldwide each year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yeast infections are caused by an overgrowth of a type of fungus called &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Candida_%28fungus%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Candida&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, which can lead to uncomfortable symptoms such as itching, burning, and discharge. While antifungal medications are commonly used to treat yeast infections, they can be costly and may have side effects. Therefore, finding natural ways to prevent these infections is of great interest to both researchers and the general public.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Complex Interplay Between Adiponectin and Inflammation in Lung Cancer Weight Loss</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/adiponectin-inflammation-weight-loss-nsclc-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/adiponectin-inflammation-weight-loss-nsclc-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking study that sheds new light on the metabolic and inflammatory challenges faced by patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), researchers have explored the intricate relationship between adiponectin levels, systemic inflammation, and weight loss. This research, published in a reputable scientific journal, offers valuable insights into how the body&amp;rsquo;s response to cancer can impact overall health and disease progression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-crucial-role-of-adiponectin-in-cancer-induced-weight-loss&#34;&gt;The Crucial Role of Adiponectin in Cancer-Induced Weight Loss&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adiponectin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Adiponectin&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, a hormone produced by adipose tissue, is known for its anti-inflammatory properties and its role in regulating glucose levels and fatty acid breakdown. In healthy individuals, adiponectin helps to maintain insulin sensitivity and protect against metabolic diseases. However, its role in the context of cancer, especially NSCLC, and associated weight loss has remained less understood until now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Glutamine in Your Diet</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-importance-of-glutamine-in-your-diet/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 04:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/the-importance-of-glutamine-in-your-diet/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Glutamine, often referred to as the &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Essential_amino_acid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;conditionally essential&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&amp;rdquo; amino acid, plays a crucial role in various physiological functions within the human body. In this article, we will explore why consuming glutamine is important for overall health and well-being.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-is-glutamine&#34;&gt;What is Glutamine?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Glutamine is the most abundant &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amino_acid&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;amino acid&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in the bloodstream and is synthesized primarily in &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Skeletal_muscle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;skeletal muscle&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. It serves as a building block for proteins and also plays a key role in cellular energy production. While the body can produce glutamine on its own, there are instances where the demand for glutamine exceeds the body&amp;rsquo;s ability to produce it, making dietary sources of glutamine crucial for meeting the body&amp;rsquo;s needs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unlocking the Mysteries of Medical Biochemistry: A Challenging Quiz</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/medical-biochemistry-quiz-challenge/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 00:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/medical-biochemistry-quiz-challenge/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome to &amp;ldquo;Unlocking the Mysteries of Medical Biochemistry: A Challenging Quiz&amp;rdquo;! This quiz is crafted for those passionate about the intricate world of medicine and biochemistry. It offers a deep dive into the biochemical basis of diseases, exploring how genetic conditions, enzyme deficiencies, and vitamin imbalances can lead to specific medical symptoms and diagnoses. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a medical student, a practicing healthcare professional, or simply a science enthusiast, this quiz will challenge your knowledge, sharpen your critical thinking skills, and enhance your understanding of the fundamental processes that drive human health and disease. Ready to test your knowledge and learn something new? Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Citalopram-induced Sexual Disorgasmia is an Expected Result of Antidepressant Treatment, Says Manchester University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 16:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A new study conducted by researchers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.manchester.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Manchester University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has found that citalopram, a drug commonly used to treat depression, can lead to sexual dysfunctions known as disorgasmia. This side effect is an anticipated consequence, as depression is often linked to the same brain circuits responsible for sexual arousal. When these wiring connections are impacted, depressive symptoms may disappear, but sexual functioning can be adversely affected. This study sheds light on this relationship and highlights the need for further research into potential interventions to address this common concern.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Master Your Vitamin Knowledge: Essential Nutrients Unveiled</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/master-your-vitamin-knowledge-essential-nutrients-unveiled/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Feb 2024 11:17:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/quiz/master-your-vitamin-knowledge-essential-nutrients-unveiled/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Embark on a journey through the vibrant and essential universe of vitamins with our comprehensive quiz. Whether you&amp;rsquo;re a nutrition enthusiast, a health professional, or simply curious about how vitamins influence bodily functions, this quiz is designed to enrich your understanding and test your knowledge. From the roles of vitamins in energy metabolism and immune support to their importance in preventing deficiency diseases, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover fascinating facts and gain insights into maintaining optimal health through nutrition. Ready to challenge yourself and become a vitamin virtuoso? Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comparative Analysis of Musculoskeletal Disorders: Osteoarthritis, Gout, Hyperuricemia, Crystal Arthritis, Osteoporosis, Metabolic Bone Disease, and Rheumatoid Arthritis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/comparative-analysis-musculoskeletal-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 00:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/comparative-analysis-musculoskeletal-disorders/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article presents a comparative analysis of several major musculoskeletal disorders: Osteoarthritis (OA), Gout, Hyperuricemia, Crystal Arthritis, Osteoporosis, Metabolic Bone Disease (MBD), and Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA). The focus is on the etiological factors, pathophysiology, and key clinical manifestations of each condition. Understanding these aspects is crucial for accurate diagnosis, management, and therapeutic interventions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Musculoskeletal disorders encompass a range of conditions affecting the bones, joints, and connective tissues. They can result from various causes, including genetic predisposition, metabolic imbalances, autoimmune responses, and physical wear and tear.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Revolutionizing Health: The Promising Horizon of Exercise Mimetics</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/revolutionizing-health-the-promising-horizon-of-exercise-mimetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/revolutionizing-health-the-promising-horizon-of-exercise-mimetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;definition-and-development-of-exercise-mimetics&#34;&gt;Definition and Development of Exercise Mimetics&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Exercise mimetics, an emerging concept in the field of medical science, refer to molecules or microorganisms designed to replicate the health benefits of physical exercise. These innovative agents are poised to revolutionize drug development by potentially overcoming some of the limitations inherent in traditional pharmaceutical approaches. The primary objective of exercise mimetics is to activate the same physiological pathways that are stimulated during physical activities, such as running or swimming.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mannosidosis: Treatment and Management</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mannosidosis-treatment-and-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 09:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/mannosidosis-treatment-and-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mannosidosis, a rare genetic disorder and metabolic anomaly, arises when the body fails to efficiently break down mannose sugar chains. This inability leads to an accumulation of sugar-laden compounds in various cells, tissues, and even urine, disrupting regular bodily functions and skeletal development.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h1 id=&#34;description&#34;&gt;Description&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The onset of Mannosidosis is linked to a genetic inability to produce a specific enzyme vital for lysosomes, the cell&amp;rsquo;s structures tasked with breaking down proteins, sugars, and fats, and recycling them into other molecules. Lysosomes require this enzyme for the degradation of long sugar chains. Without it, these sugars accumulate within the lysosomes, causing them to expand and multiply, ultimately harming the cell and resulting in Mannosidosis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Overview of Reticular Dysgenesis: History, Clinical Profile, Genetic Insights, and Treatment Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reticular-dysgenesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 10:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reticular-dysgenesis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;history&#34;&gt;History&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In 1959, De Vaal and Seynhaeve first documented a case of severe combined immunodeficiency (SCID) accompanied by congenital absence of white blood cells. This discovery was based on observations of monozygotic twin boys, born prematurely, who had no white blood cells at birth. Post-mortem examination of these infants, who unfortunately died from septic complications as neonates, showed conditions consistent with SCID. This included the absence of lymphoid cells in their lymphoid organs and myeloid cells in their bone marrow, while erythroid cells and megakaryocytes were present. This unique combination of symptoms led the researchers to name the condition &amp;ldquo;reticular dysgenesis&amp;rdquo; (RD), attributing it to a failure in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2975965/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;development of early multipotent reticular cells into myeloid and lymphoid cells&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. Further studies on RD revealed variations in white blood cell counts among patients, with some exhibiting immature myeloid cells up to the promyelocyte stage. Roper et al.&amp;rsquo;s extensive study, using cell-surface marker staining, indicated that RD might interfere with the late differentiation of lymphoid and myeloid cells. The first successful bone marrow transplantation (BMT) in 1983, which treated a patient with RD, pointed to the disease originating in stem cells rather than the bone marrow environment. RD patients were found to not respond to &lt;a href=&#34;https://pubmed.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/34772606/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;G-CSF treatment&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; for granulopoiesis, unlike those with other congenital neutropenias. Additionally, primary sensorineural deafness emerged as another characteristic of RD, with adenylate kinase 2 deficiency identified as its molecular basis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Deciphered Inca&#39;s Inscription on the Stone Tablets Describes Complex Operations Done by Ancient Surgeons with Mushroom-Extracted Anesthetics</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/deciphered-inca-inscription-describes-ancient-surgeons-with-mushroom-extracted-anesthetics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:31:44 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/deciphered-inca-inscription-describes-ancient-surgeons-with-mushroom-extracted-anesthetics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking study at &lt;a href=&#34;https://wustl.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Washington University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, a team of archaeologists and medical researchers have uncovered an ancient Incan inscription that sheds new light on the medical practices of the pre-Columbian civilization. The inscription, found on stone tablets, describes complex surgical procedures performed by Incan surgeons using mushroom-extracted &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anesthetic&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;anesthetics&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The discovery of the tablets sheds new light on &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inca_Empire&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Incan&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; medicine, which is believed to have been highly advanced for its time. According to the researchers, the mushroom-extracted anesthetics used by the Incan surgeons were likely made from the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Amanita_muscaria&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;fly agaric mushroom&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, which is known to have psychoactive properties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>10 Minute Running Exercise and Protein Consumption Can Strengthen Achilles Tendon Threefold</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/10-minute-running-exercise-protein-consumption-can-strengthen-achilles-tendon/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/10-minute-running-exercise-protein-consumption-can-strengthen-achilles-tendon/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted by the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.london.ac.uk/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;London University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has shown that a simple running exercise and protein consumption can make a huge difference in the strengthening of Achilles tendon. According to the study, performing a 10-minute running exercise every day and consuming at least 30 grams of protein and chondroitin can make the Achilles tendon three times stronger!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Achilles_tendon&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Achilles tendon&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; is the largest tendon in the body, and it connects the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Triceps_surae_muscle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;calf muscles&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; to the heel bone. It is an essential component in the movement of the foot and the running motion. The Achilles tendon is prone to injury, especially among athletes who engage in intense physical activities, such as running, jumping, and changing direction. An Achilles tendon tear is a common injury that can be severe and take time to heal fully.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Adiponectin: A Potential Key to Unlocking New Therapies for Lung Cancer</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/adiponectin-down-regulates-creb-and-inhibits-proliferation-of-a549-lung-cancer-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/adiponectin-down-regulates-creb-and-inhibits-proliferation-of-a549-lung-cancer-cells/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the ongoing battle against cancer, scientists are constantly in search of novel pathways and mechanisms that could lead to new therapeutic strategies. Among the myriad of molecules being studied, adipokines stand out for their significant role in cancer-related molecular pathways. Adiponectin, a major adipokine, is gaining attention for its anti-inflammatory properties and beneficial metabolic actions. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.pupt.2017.05.009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Recent research&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has highlighted its potential anti-carcinogenic effects, suggesting a promising avenue for cancer therapy, particularly in lung cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
