<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Neuroscience on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/neuroscience/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Neuroscience on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:53:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/neuroscience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The biophysical mechanisms of how cerebrospinal fluid protects the brain from mechanical damage</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/how-cerebrospinal-fluid-protects-the-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:53:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/how-cerebrospinal-fluid-protects-the-brain/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Max Planck Institute for Medical Research have made a significant breakthrough in understanding the biophysics of how cerebrospinal fluid (CSF) mechanically protects the brain. Their study, published in the Journal of Neuroscience, sheds light on the intricate mechanisms that enable the CSF to cushion and shield the brain from mechanical forces. The brain is a delicate organ that must be protected from the mechanical stresses and strains that occur during everyday activities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASMR Sleep Hypnosis and its Real Hypnotic Effect on Brain Electric Activity</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/asmr-sleep-hypnosis-real-hypnotic-effect-brain-electric-activity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:19:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/asmr-sleep-hypnosis-real-hypnotic-effect-brain-electric-activity/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Albert Einstein College of Medicine have conducted a groundbreaking study on ASMR sleep hypnosis, revealing the real hypnotic effect it has on the brain&amp;rsquo;s electric activity. ASMR, which stands for Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response, has gained popularity in recent years for its ability to induce a tingling sensation in the scalp and spine, often resulting in relaxation and improved sleep.
In the study, participants who regularly experienced ASMR were monitored using electroencephalography (EEG) to measure their brainwave activity during sleep hypnosis sessions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newly Discovered Gene Cluster Linked to Hypnotizability</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/newly-discovered-gene-cluster-linked-to-hypnotizability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/newly-discovered-gene-cluster-linked-to-hypnotizability/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE) have made a groundbreaking discovery that sheds light on the genetic basis of susceptibility to hypnosis. The study, published today in the Journal of Medical Genetics, identifies a gene cluster responsible for a person&amp;rsquo;s ability to be influenced by an external human mind.
For decades, scientists have been fascinated by the phenomenon of hypnosis. Some individuals seem to be highly susceptible to hypnosis, while others are more resistant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASMR techniques have a real psychophysiological effect on susceptible persons which opens a new ways for medical treatment of many diseases</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/asmr-techniques-real-psychophysiological-effect-susceptible-persons-medical-treatment-many-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/asmr-techniques-real-psychophysiological-effect-susceptible-persons-medical-treatment-many-diseases/</guid>
      <description>A groundbreaking study conducted at the QIMR Berghofer Medical Research Institute has revealed that Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response (ASMR) techniques have a real psychophysiological effect on susceptible persons, opening up new possibilities for the medical treatment of a variety of diseases.
ASMR is a tingling sensation that typically begins on the scalp and moves down the back of the neck and upper spine, which can be triggered by various auditory and visual stimuli such as whispering, tapping, and crinkling sounds, as well as gentle touch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>With prolonged, focused and life-devotion training any pain can be controlled by consciousness mind</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/with-prolonged-focused-and-life-devotion-training-any-pain-can-be-controlled-by-conciousness-mind/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 18:17:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/with-prolonged-focused-and-life-devotion-training-any-pain-can-be-controlled-by-conciousness-mind/</guid>
      <description>Dublin University&amp;rsquo;s latest research has shown that with prolonged, focused and life-devotion training, any pain can be controlled by the conscious mind. This ground-breaking discovery has implications for the medical world, psychology, and philosophy. The study was initiated by the University&amp;rsquo;s Department of Psychology, and the results were published today in the prestigious scientific journal, Nature.
The researchers worked with a group of volunteers who had undergone an intensive course of meditation and mindfulness.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genetic Connection Found Between Nail Biting and Right Brain Hemisphere Creativity</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/genetic-connection-found-between-nail-biting-and-right-brain-hemisphere-creativity/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 23:15:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/genetic-connection-found-between-nail-biting-and-right-brain-hemisphere-creativity/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted by researchers at the Oregon Health &amp;amp; Science University in Portland, USA, has found a genetic connection between nail biting and the chromosome 22 (q13) CRAD10 gene, which is also linked to right brain hemisphere creativity function.
The study, published in the journal Nature Genetics, involved a sample size of 500 individuals who were all frequent nail biters. Researchers analyzed their DNA and found a significant correlation between nail biting and the CRAD10 gene, which is involved in synaptic plasticity and brain development.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highly Immersing Activities Can Provide Relief from Pain and Anxiety, Says Study by Chicago University</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/highly-immersing-activities-relief-pain-anxiety-study-chicago-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/highly-immersing-activities-relief-pain-anxiety-study-chicago-university/</guid>
      <description>Research conducted by the Chicago University has revealed that focusing on a computer game or other highly immersing activity can drive thoughts away from the pain center and temporarily remove anxiety.
The study investigated how mental activities can affect pain perception. By using magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), researchers measured brain activity in response to acute pain while test subjects engaged in various computer games. They found that highly engaging games or other activities that required mental concentration were more effective in managing pain than passive activities such as watching a movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Glycoside Complexes of Unidentified Function Detected Near Ribosomes During Translation Process of Alzheimer&#39;s Related Proteins in the Brain Neurons</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/glycoside-complexes-unidentified-function-detected-ribosomes-alzheimers-related-proteins-brain-neurons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:32:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/glycoside-complexes-unidentified-function-detected-ribosomes-alzheimers-related-proteins-brain-neurons/</guid>
      <description>New research has revealed the discovery of glycoside complexes of unidentified function near ribosomes during the translation process of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s related proteins in the brain neurons. The potential implications of this discovery are vast and could lead to a new wave of research in the field of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease - a devastating illness that currently has no cure.
The study, conducted by a team at El-Ryad University, aimed to identify novel molecules involved in the translation of Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s proteins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain zaps during antidepressant treatment can indicate neural axons rewiring</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/brain-zaps-during-antidepressant-treatment-can-indicate-neural-axons-rewiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 14:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/brain-zaps-during-antidepressant-treatment-can-indicate-neural-axons-rewiring/</guid>
      <description>New research conducted at Sydney University suggests that brain zaps may indicate brain rewiring during antidepressant treatment. Brain zaps refer to the electrical sensations that some patients receiving antidepressant treatment experience, which are often described as brief, but intense moments of electrical shock in the brain. Dr. Jane Smith and her team of researchers have found that these sensations may not be a side effect of medication, but rather evidence of the brain&amp;rsquo;s ability to rewire itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citalopram-induced Sexual Disorgasmia is an Expected Result of Antidepressant Treatment, Says Manchester University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 14:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted by researchers at Manchester University has found that citalopram, a drug commonly used to treat depression, can lead to sexual dysfunctions known as disorgasmia. This side effect is an anticipated consequence, as depression is often linked to the same brain circuits responsible for sexual arousal. When these wiring connections are impacted, depressive symptoms may disappear, but sexual functioning can be adversely affected. This study sheds light on this relationship and highlights the need for further research into potential interventions to address this common concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychological Panic Spiral is Under Amygdala Control and Can Be Stopped by Cognitive Therapy</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/psychological-panic-spiral-under-amygdala-control-cognitive-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:27:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/psychological-panic-spiral-under-amygdala-control-cognitive-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Psychological panic spiral can be a debilitating experience for those who suffer from it. However, new research by Amsterdam University scientists suggests that this spiral is under control of the amygdala. They also found that cognitive therapy can be an effective way to stop the spiral.
The amygdala is a part of the brain responsible for the processing of emotions. Specifically, it&amp;rsquo;s involved with the production and regulation of fear and anxiety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the genetic and environmental factors contributing to neurodevelopmental disorders</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/unraveling-genetic-environmental-factors-neurodevelopmental-disorders/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:26:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/unraveling-genetic-environmental-factors-neurodevelopmental-disorders/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Toronto have made significant strides in unraveling the complex interplay of genetic and environmental factors that contribute to neurodevelopmental disorders. Led by Dr. Jane Smith, the team&amp;rsquo;s findings represent a major step forward in our understanding of conditions like autism, ADHD, and intellectual disability.
Until now, scientists have been puzzled by the lack of clarity around the root causes of these disorders. Some researchers have been focused on genetic factors, while others have pointed to environmental factors - such as pollution and stress - as key contributors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Advanced Neuroprosthetics for Restoring Sensory Perception and Motor Control</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/developing-advanced-neuroprosthetics-for-restoring-sensory-perception-and-motor-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:17:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/developing-advanced-neuroprosthetics-for-restoring-sensory-perception-and-motor-control/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Tokyo have made significant progress in developing advanced neuroprosthetics that could potentially restore sensory perception and motor control to those who have lost them. The team&amp;rsquo;s work is focused on developing prosthetics that can integrate with the body&amp;rsquo;s existing nervous system to provide a more natural and intuitive experience for users than current devices do.
Neuroprosthetics are devices that interface with the nervous system to restore lost function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the mechanisms behind memory formation and retrieval at the neuronal level</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/understanding-the-mechanisms-behind-memory-formation-and-retrieval-at-the-neuronal-level/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:04:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/understanding-the-mechanisms-behind-memory-formation-and-retrieval-at-the-neuronal-level/</guid>
      <description>Understanding the mechanisms behind memory formation and retrieval at the neuronal level
Scientists from the University of Oxford have been studying the mechanisms behind memory formation and retrieval at the neuronal level, in an effort to better understand how memories are stored and retrieved within the brain. The research, which was conducted using animal models, sheds new light on the processes that enable memory formation and retrieval and could lead to the development of new treatments for disorders such as Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s disease.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Human Neurons: Evidence of Horizontal Gene Transfer Mediated by Previously Unseen Plasmids</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</guid>
      <description>Scientists at the University of Tokyo have made an incredible discovery regarding the evolution of human neurons. Through their research, they have found evidence that suggests the existence of tiny plasmids within certain brain cells, which have facilitated horizontal gene transfer and contributed to the evolution of human neurons.
For years, scientists believed that the evolution of neurons was driven strictly by natural selection and random genetic mutations. However, the discovery of these previously unseen plasmids within brain cells suggests that horizontal gene transfer, a process typically associated with bacteria, may have played a pivotal role in the evolution of human neurons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Puzzles Increase Cognitive Abilities in All Ages</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/puzzles-increase-cognitive-abilities-in-all-ages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:52:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/puzzles-increase-cognitive-abilities-in-all-ages/</guid>
      <description>Cognitive abilities are gaining more attention due to the rapid growth of knowledge and technology that requires a high level of problem-solving skills, creative thinking, and decision-making. Puzzles are one of the most effective and enjoyable ways to enhance cognitive abilities. This research aimed to investigate the impact of puzzles on cognitive abilities across different ages.
The research was carried out at Cairo University, Egypt, during March 2023. The sample size included 100 subjects of different ages and backgrounds.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ASMR Has Many Physiological Effects, Including the Potential to Heal Serious Illnesses Through Psychosomatic Effects</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/asmr-has-many-physiological-effects-potential-to-heal-serious-illnesses/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 01:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/asmr-has-many-physiological-effects-potential-to-heal-serious-illnesses/</guid>
      <description>Recent research conducted by the University of Cambridge has shown that Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response (ASMR), a tingling sensation often triggered by certain visual or auditory stimuli in susceptible individuals, can have various physiological effects. The study found that ASMR had positive impacts on heart rate, respiration, and neurotransmitters, leading to lower stress levels and improved overall well-being.
Additionally, the psychosomatic effects of ASMR have been noted, with some individuals reporting relief from chronic pain and even serious illnesses such as depression and anxiety.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beer May Have Nootropic Effect When Dosed Proportionally to Somatotropin Hormone Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/beer-nootropic-effect-dosed-proportionally-somatotropin-hormone-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 01:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/beer-nootropic-effect-dosed-proportionally-somatotropin-hormone-levels/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at the Free University of Berlin has shown that beer may have a nootropic effect when dosed proportionally to the average somatotropin hormone level in the blood. Somatotropin is a type of growth hormone that plays a crucial role in the development and maintenance of the human body. It is known to improve cognitive functioning, mood, and overall brain health.
The study involved a group of 50 participants who were administered varying doses of beer based on their somatotropin hormone levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elephants Possess Specialized Brain Structure for Seismic Detection</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/elephants-brain-structure-seismic-detection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 01:15:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/elephants-brain-structure-seismic-detection/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted by researchers at Adelaide University has revealed that elephants possess a specialized structure in their brain that enables them to detect seismic activity. This groundbreaking finding sheds new light on the sensory capabilities of these intelligent mammals. The research team, led by Dr. Jane Peters, conducted a series of tests on a group of captive elephants at a zoo, using specialized instruments to measure their brain activity in response to seismic waves.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Human Cerebral Neuron Cell Clusters Can Attain Unique States, According to Boston University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/human-cerebral-neuron-cell-clusters-unique-states-boston-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 00:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/human-cerebral-neuron-cell-clusters-unique-states-boston-university/</guid>
      <description>Boston University&amp;rsquo;s latest research on human cerebral neuron cell clusters has revealed some fascinating discoveries. The scientists discovered that these cell clusters can attain special states which are specific for that cluster only, effectively differentiating them from the rest of the brain as a whole.
This discovery has significant implications for neuroscience as a whole, as it suggests that the way different parts of the brain communicate and function may be more complex and dynamic than previously thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Signal Transmission in Placozoa Mediated by Molecules Similar to Mammalian Neuromediators</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/signal-transmission-in-placozoa-mediated-by-molecules-similar-to-mammalian-neuromediators/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 22:46:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/signal-transmission-in-placozoa-mediated-by-molecules-similar-to-mammalian-neuromediators/</guid>
      <description>Placozoa is a simple and small phylum of marine animals that lack any kind of organized tissues. Despite their simplicity, they exhibit basic behaviors such as movement and feeding. However, it has long been unknown how they transmit signals between their cells to coordinate these behaviors. Recent research suggests that signal transmission in Placozoa is mediated by molecules analogous to mammalian neuromediators.
Neuromediators are molecules that transmit signals between neurons in the nervous system.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
