<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Environmental Science on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/environmental-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Environmental Science on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:24:09 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/environmental-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Understanding the Impact of Climate Change on Biodiversity and Ecosystems</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/understanding-the-impact-of-climate-change-on-biodiversity-and-ecosystems/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/understanding-the-impact-of-climate-change-on-biodiversity-and-ecosystems/</guid>
      <description>Scientists at the University of Cape Town have been studying the impact of climate change on biodiversity and ecosystems, revealing some worrying trends. A team of researchers spent six years studying ten different ecosystems around the world, collecting data on species diversity and abundance, as well as environmental factors like temperature and precipitation. The results of their research show that climate change is having a significant impact on biodiversity and ecosystems, and that urgent action is needed to protect them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wood Wide Web: Mycorrhizal Network Restored After Interruption by Ants and Termites</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/wood-wide-web-mycorrhizal-network-ants-termites/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 01:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/wood-wide-web-mycorrhizal-network-ants-termites/</guid>
      <description>A recent research conducted by Ottawa University on the phenomenon of wood wide web has revealed some interesting findings. The wood wide web refers to the complex network of underground fungal threads that connect the roots of trees and plants. These fungi form a symbiotic relationship with the plants by exchanging nutrients and other vital compounds. This network is crucial for the survival and health of the plants.
The research focused on the effects of several species of ants and termites on the mycorrhizal network.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
