<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:24:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title> Understanding Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy in Diabetic Foot Ulcers</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/understanding-hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy-in-diabetic-foot-ulcers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 10:24:09 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/understanding-hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy-in-diabetic-foot-ulcers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy (HBO) has been a topic of debate in the medical community, particularly regarding its use for diabetic foot ulcers (DFUs). This therapy involves patients breathing concentrated oxygen at high pressure, believed to stimulate healing processes. The scientific paper by Magnus Löndahl and Andrew J.M. Boulton presents a balanced view of this controversial subject.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;pros-of-hbo&#34;&gt;Pros of HBO&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some studies suggest HBO can accelerate healing in specific types of ischemic or neuro-ischemic ulcers, particularly after standard treatments have failed. It reportedly enhances angiogenesis (formation of new blood vessels), reduces swelling, improves white blood cell function, and promotes stem cell mobilization. These benefits could be critical for patients with hard-to-heal DFUs.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbaric Oxygen Theraphy: Recommended, Optional, Controversal and Non Indications</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/indications-for-using-hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 10:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/indications-for-using-hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hyperbaric oxygen (HBO) therapy is a traditional and established treatment for patients suffering from tissue hypoxia. This method enhances oxygen levels in tissues, thereby boosting wound healing and tissue regeneration capabilities. It also reactivates cellular functions to improve survival rates and adjusts the anti-inflammatory and immunological responses of immune cells, aiding in the recovery from severe infections. HBO therapy is versatile in its applications, encompassing a variety of conditions such as carbon monoxide poisoning, hard-to-treat infectious diseases like necrotizing soft tissue infections, gas gangrene, osteomyelitis, traumatic ischemia, crush injuries, diabetic foot ulcers, and more. It is particularly effective in treating diving-related issues like gas embolism and decompression sickness, where it is known as recompression therapy. However, it&amp;rsquo;s important to understand that HBO therapy is not a standalone miracle treatment but rather a supplementary approach, enhancing the effectiveness of other treatment methods or working in conjunction with them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
