<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Car T Cell Theraphy on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/car-t-cell-theraphy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Car T Cell Theraphy on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:59:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/car-t-cell-theraphy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Biotechnological Breakthroughs: mRNA Vaccines, CAR-T Therapy, and the Role of AI in Shaping Future Medicine</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/biotechnological-breakthroughs-mrna-car-t-ai-future-medicine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/biotechnological-breakthroughs-mrna-car-t-ai-future-medicine/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The main driver of development in the medical field in the past year has been biotechnology. This is evidenced by highly objective indicators such as high publication activity and a substantial increase in both government and commercial funding for research in this area. Let&amp;rsquo;s take a closer look at the key trends that emerged this year.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the key technological breakthroughs in recent years has been the development and integration of mRNA vaccines into clinical practice. Unlike classical vaccines, which consist of a weakened pathogen or its protein, mRNA vaccines do not contain any fragments of the pathogen. They provide human cells with a &amp;ldquo;template&amp;rdquo; for the independent synthesis of the pathogen&amp;rsquo;s proteins, allowing the immune system to respond more rapidly and effectively to the threat. During the pandemic, mRNA vaccines underwent the necessary regulatory procedures and entered clinical practice within a year.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
