<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>sport on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/sport/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sport on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:47:31 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/sport/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The effect of zumba exercise on menstrual pain relief</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</guid>
      <description>Menstrual pain, or dysmenorrhea, is a common issue affecting many women worldwide. While various treatments exist, ranging from medication to alternative therapies, an intriguing approach has emerged: Zumba exercise. A recent study conducted by Ahmed Samy et al. delved into this aspect, offering fascinating insights.
The Study The study titled &amp;ldquo;The Effect of Zumba Exercise on Reducing Menstrual Pain in Young Women with Primary Dysmenorrhea: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&amp;rdquo; aimed to evaluate the impact of Zumba on menstrual pain severity and duration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running it Out - How Endurance Exercise May Help Remove Disease from Your Body</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/running-it-out-how-endurance-exercise-may-help-remove-disease-from-your-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/running-it-out-how-endurance-exercise-may-help-remove-disease-from-your-body/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have found that endurance exercise such as running can burn calories that may help remove disease from the body.
Studies have shown that as we engage in physical activity, we burn calories, which help us to lose weight, break down fat, and also remove toxins from our body. This is why people engage in physical activity or exercise to maintain a healthy lifestyle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
