<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aerospace Medicine on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/aerospace-medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Aerospace Medicine on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:30:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/aerospace-medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the impact of microgravity on human physiology and potential countermeasures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/investigating-the-impact-of-microgravity-on-human-physiology-and-potential-countermeasures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 10:30:19 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/investigating-the-impact-of-microgravity-on-human-physiology-and-potential-countermeasures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The University of São Paulo has undertaken a groundbreaking research project to explore the impact of microgravity on human physiology and potential countermeasures. The experiments carried out on the International Space Station in collaboration with NASA and other space agencies have revealed that being in a space environment can cause significant changes to the human body, both in the short and long term.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;One of the key findings is that the lack of gravity can cause muscle and bone loss, which could lead to serious health problems over time. This is because our bones and muscles are constantly being pulled on by gravity on Earth, and without that constant force, they start to weaken. It is also believed that the cardiovascular system is affected, as fluid accumulates in the upper body and head, which can cause dizziness, headaches, and even visual problems. The immune system is also thought to be impacted, which could increase the risk of infections and illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
