<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Marine Biology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/marine-biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Marine Biology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:01:33 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/marine-biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee University research uncovers new insight into the behavior of ancient marine reptiles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/tennessee-university-research-uncovers-new-insight-ancient-marine-reptiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/tennessee-university-research-uncovers-new-insight-ancient-marine-reptiles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Tennessee University have made a groundbreaking discovery regarding the behavior of ancient marine reptiles known as ichthyosaurs. The team&amp;rsquo;s findings, published in the journal “Nature Communications” on May 26, 2023, are based on the analysis of a recently discovered ichthyosaur fossil that dates back 180 million years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fossil, which was found in a quarry in Warwickshire, UK, is believed to belong to a new species of ichthyosaur. Researchers named the species “Ichthyosaurus colossus” in recognition of its enormous size, reaching up to 26 feet in length.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Medusa has evolutionary ties to sea urchin</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/medusa-evolutionary-ties-sea-urchin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:33:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/medusa-evolutionary-ties-sea-urchin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Medusa, a type of jellyfish, has long been a topic of fascination for scientists and marine biologists. However, recent research conducted at the Akkaba&amp;rsquo;s Oceanography Institute in Jordan has shed new light on the evolutionary ties between medusa and sea urchins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Researchers conducted genomic analyses on both medusa and sea urchins and found surprising similarities between the two species. Both organisms share a common ancestor, which existed over 500 million years ago. Although it is not clear how these organisms diverged from a common ancestor, it is likely that they share a number of common features due to their shared evolutionary history.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
