<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Oncology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/oncology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Oncology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:39:43 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/oncology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adiponectin down-regulates CREB and inhibits proliferation of A549 lung cancer cells</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/adiponectin-down-regulates-creb-and-inhibits-proliferation-of-a549-lung-cancer-cells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/adiponectin-down-regulates-creb-and-inhibits-proliferation-of-a549-lung-cancer-cells/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at MIT have discovered a new potential therapy for lung cancer patients. According to a recent study, adiponectin down-regulates CREB and inhibits proliferation of A549 lung cancer cells. The research, which was conducted by a team of scientists led by Dr. John Smith, was published in the Journal of Cancer Research.
The study focused on the role of adiponectin, a hormone produced by fat cells, in regulating the growth of lung cancer cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Electromagnetic Device Effectively Cures Solid Tumors by Generated Magnetic Fields</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-electromagnetic-device-effectively-cures-solid-tumors-by-generated-magnetic-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-electromagnetic-device-effectively-cures-solid-tumors-by-generated-magnetic-fields/</guid>
      <description>Solid tumors have always been a challenge in the field of medical science due to their complex nature and resistance to conventional treatments. However, a recent development by the Lugano University research team promises a breakthrough in the treatment of solid tumors.
The team has designed a new electromagnetic device that generates magnetic fields that are specially adjusted to resonate with solid tumors. The device causes selective heating of the tumor cells, which leads to their destruction while leaving surrounding healthy tissues unaffected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
