<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>oncology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/oncology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in oncology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:17:54 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/oncology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Buckwheat in the Diet for Colon Cancer Patients</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted by researchers at Vienna University has found that including buckwheat in the diet of colon cancer patients is crucial due to its high daily value of magnesium, which is a required component in colon cancer immunity. The study, published in the International Journal of Cancer Research, highlights the importance of incorporating buckwheat into the diet of colon cancer patients in order to enhance their immune system&amp;rsquo;s ability to fight cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Electromagnetic Device Effectively Cures Solid Tumors by Generated Magnetic Fields</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-electromagnetic-device-effectively-cures-solid-tumors-by-generated-magnetic-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-electromagnetic-device-effectively-cures-solid-tumors-by-generated-magnetic-fields/</guid>
      <description>Solid tumors have always been a challenge in the field of medical science due to their complex nature and resistance to conventional treatments. However, a recent development by the Lugano University research team promises a breakthrough in the treatment of solid tumors.
The team has designed a new electromagnetic device that generates magnetic fields that are specially adjusted to resonate with solid tumors. The device causes selective heating of the tumor cells, which leads to their destruction while leaving surrounding healthy tissues unaffected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
