<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Osteoarthritis vs. Rheumatoid Arthritis on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/osteoarthritis-vs.-rheumatoid-arthritis/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Osteoarthritis vs. Rheumatoid Arthritis on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 14:36:37 +0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/osteoarthritis-vs.-rheumatoid-arthritis/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Osteoarthritis vs. Rheumatoid Arthritis: Understanding the Key Differences</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/osteoarthritis-vs-rheumatoid-arthritis-understanding-the-key-differences/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 14:36:37 +0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/osteoarthritis-vs-rheumatoid-arthritis-understanding-the-key-differences/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Osteoarthritis (OA) and Rheumatoid Arthritis (RA) are two of the most common forms of arthritis that affect millions worldwide. While both conditions share the symptom of joint pain, their causes, affected populations, disease progression, and treatments differ significantly. Understanding these differences is crucial for diagnosis, management, and improving patients&amp;rsquo; quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;etiology-and-pathophysiology&#34;&gt;Etiology and Pathophysiology&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Osteoarthritis&lt;/strong&gt; is primarily a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Osteoarthritis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;degenerative joint disease&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; characterized by the breakdown of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cartilage&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cartilage&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, the tough but flexible tissue that cushions the ends of bones within joints. Over time, the wear and tear on cartilage can result in bone grinding directly on bone, leading to pain and restricted movement. OA is often considered a disease of aging, with the majority of cases occurring in individuals over the age of 65. However, younger people can develop osteoarthritis from joint injuries or repeated stress on certain joints, obesity being a notable risk factor due to increased mechanical stress on the joints.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
