<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>anti aging on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/anti-aging/</link>
    <description>Recent content in anti aging on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:29:08 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/anti-aging/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the World of Berries: Health Benefits and Popular Varieties in North America</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>From a botanical perspective, the term &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; specifically refers to pulpy fruits that develop from a single ovary enclosing seeds. Examples of true berries encompass bananas, grapes, and blueberries. However, in the context of this discussion, &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; are identified as small, tender, palatable, and vibrantly colored fruits primarily from the Vaccinium, Fragaria, and Rubus species. Berries are increasingly recognized for their substantial health contributions in diets. Predominantly consumed berries in North America are blackberries (Rubus species), red (Rubus idaeus) and black raspberries (Rubus occidentalis), blueberries (Vaccinium corymbosum), cranberries (V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Benefits and Anti-Aging Effects of Licochalcone A</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/health-benefits-anti-aging-effects-licochalcone-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 01:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/health-benefits-anti-aging-effects-licochalcone-a/</guid>
      <description>Opening Overview Since ancient times, flora has served as a fundamental resource for nourishment, habitat, and therapeutic remedies. Prior to the advent of contemporary scientific and medical advancements, ancient cultures heavily relied on botanical remedies. Out of approximately 390,000 identified species of plants, a mere 6% have undergone examination for their biological properties. In many developing regions, particularly within Asia and Africa, the utilization of herbal extracts for treating diseases in both humans and animals is still prevalent.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
