<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Regenerative Therapy on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/regenerative-therapy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Regenerative Therapy on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 10:44:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/regenerative-therapy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Liver&#39;s Remarkable Regenerative Prowess</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/unveiling-the-livers-remarkable-regenerative-prowess/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jan 2024 10:44:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/unveiling-the-livers-remarkable-regenerative-prowess/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The liver&amp;rsquo;s inherent regenerative capacity is crucial, given its strategic physiological role. After digestion, a mix of nutrients, toxins, and bacterial products is transported to the liver via the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Portal_vein&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;portal vein&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. Essential for detoxifying, metabolizing, and synthesizing, the liver maintains systemic balance. Its ability to regenerate underscores the need for a minimal functional mass for these activities. Studying liver regeneration typically involves surgically removing two-thirds of its mass, triggering its natural repair mechanisms. This regeneration is controlled by the synchronized activation of various &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cell_signaling&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;signaling pathways&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, a fact established through animal studies. These pathways ensure the proliferation of all liver cell types, critical for restoring the lost mass. Understanding these pathways is key in managing abnormal growth in liver tumors and has significant implications in medical fields such as oncology and regenerative medicine, including areas like stem cell differentiation, tissue engineering, and liver transplantation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
