<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Licochalcone A on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/licochalcone-a/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Licochalcone A on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 01:20:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/licochalcone-a/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Health Benefits and Anti-Aging Effects of Licochalcone A</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/health-benefits-anti-aging-effects-licochalcone-a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 01:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/health-benefits-anti-aging-effects-licochalcone-a/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;opening-overview&#34;&gt;Opening Overview&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since ancient times, flora has served as a fundamental resource for nourishment, habitat, and therapeutic remedies. Prior to the advent of contemporary scientific and medical advancements, ancient cultures heavily relied on botanical remedies. Out of approximately 390,000 identified species of plants, a mere 6% have undergone examination for their biological properties. In many developing regions, particularly within Asia and Africa, the utilization of herbal extracts for treating diseases in both humans and animals is still prevalent. Various organic compounds found in plants, such as flavonoids, alkaloids, triterpenoids, saponins, and phenols, are known to facilitate diverse biochemical processes. From these natural substances, numerous pharmaceuticals have been derived. One notable example is Licochalcone A (LCA), sourced from Glycyrrhiza uralensis, which demonstrates significant anti-inflammatory, anti-cancer, anti-obesity, and antibacterial properties. Glycyrrhiza uralensis, the plant from which LCA is derived, has a long history in traditional medicine for its various healing properties, such as replenishing spleen and qi (energy), cooling the body, detoxifying, aiding in expectoration, and alleviating coughs.&#xA;&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/news/health-benefits-anti-aging-effects-licochalcone-a/1.png&#34; alt=&#34;extraction&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
