<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Depression on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/depression/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Depression on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/depression/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Between the body and the deed</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/between-the-body-and-the-deed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/between-the-body-and-the-deed/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;On the Possible &amp;ldquo;Physical&amp;rdquo; Nature of Depression&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s a strange thing, comrades. Medicine is becoming more advanced, our hospitals are equipped with the latest technology, and medications promise instant recovery. You’d think that by now everyone should be recovering at a rapid pace. But the opposite seems to be happening.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There are more patients and more diseases. Can you imagine a person who is completely healthy and doesn’t suffer from any illness?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I overcame depression</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-i-overcame-depression/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-i-overcame-depression/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Experience of Self-Healing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Since my time in the army, I developed the habit of not treating the flu. Why from the army? Because in the army, they didn’t treat us for the flu. If it was a serious illness, we went to the infirmary (quarantine) or the hospital (treatment). I want to specifically point out that no treatment was provided in the infirmary because there were no medications. The only purpose of being placed in the infirmary was to isolate the patient. Getting into the hospital required a solid reason, like a concussion or self-harm. I don’t remember any cases of concussions in our unit, but self-harm was frequent. Although, it wasn’t real, just simulated. Cut your hand with a razor, and you’d be sent to the hospital and then discharged. A couple of weeks later, you’d come back, pack your things, and go home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
