<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Managing Weight Loss in Nsclc Patients on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/managing-weight-loss-in-nsclc-patients/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Managing Weight Loss in Nsclc Patients on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 10:39:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/managing-weight-loss-in-nsclc-patients/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unraveling the Complex Interplay Between Adiponectin and Inflammation in Lung Cancer Weight Loss</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/adiponectin-inflammation-weight-loss-nsclc-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Feb 2024 10:39:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/adiponectin-inflammation-weight-loss-nsclc-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In a groundbreaking study that sheds new light on the metabolic and inflammatory challenges faced by patients with advanced non-small cell lung cancer (NSCLC), researchers have explored the intricate relationship between adiponectin levels, systemic inflammation, and weight loss. This research, published in a reputable scientific journal, offers valuable insights into how the body&amp;rsquo;s response to cancer can impact overall health and disease progression.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-crucial-role-of-adiponectin-in-cancer-induced-weight-loss&#34;&gt;The Crucial Role of Adiponectin in Cancer-Induced Weight Loss&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adiponectin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Adiponectin&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, a hormone produced by adipose tissue, is known for its anti-inflammatory properties and its role in regulating glucose levels and fatty acid breakdown. In healthy individuals, adiponectin helps to maintain insulin sensitivity and protect against metabolic diseases. However, its role in the context of cancer, especially NSCLC, and associated weight loss has remained less understood until now.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
