<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Physics on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Physics on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 15:53:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A new millisecond pulsar in the globular cluster GLIMPSE-C01</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/a-new-millisecond-pulsar-in-glimpse-c01/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Dec 2023 15:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/a-new-millisecond-pulsar-in-glimpse-c01/</guid>
      <description>Astronomers have discovered a new millisecond pulsar in the globular cluster GLIMPSE-C01. According to the research results published on the preprint server arXiv , this is the first such object in this cluster.
A pulsar is a rotating neutron star with intense magnetic fields that emits symmetrical beams of narrow-directed electromagnetic radiation, similar to a lighthouse. The fastest rotating pulsars with rotation periods of less than 30 milliseconds are known as millisecond pulsars (MSP).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Vacuum Behaviour near Black Holes Explored by Tokyo University Researchers</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/quantum-vacuum-behaviour-black-holes-tokyo-university-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/quantum-vacuum-behaviour-black-holes-tokyo-university-researchers/</guid>
      <description>Tokyo University researchers have uncovered new information about the behaviour of the quantum vacuum near black holes. According to the study published in Physical Review D, the quantum vacuum separates a virtual particle-antiparticle pair from the point event horizon of a black hole. The event horizon marks the &amp;lsquo;point of no return&amp;rsquo; in which any matter or energy that enters it is unable to escape.
The research was led by Professor Akira Ishibashi from the university&amp;rsquo;s Department of Physics and Astronomy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Hessdalen Lights can be explained by local magnetic field anomalies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/hessdalen-lights-local-magnetic-field-anomalies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 01:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/hessdalen-lights-local-magnetic-field-anomalies/</guid>
      <description>The Hessdalen Lights can be explained by local magnetic field anomalies, according to a team of researchers at Oslo University. The mysterious lights, which have been observed in the Hessdalen valley in Norway for decades, have long puzzled scientists and locals alike. However, new research has shed light on the possible cause of the phenomenon.
Using advanced scientific techniques and equipment, the team was able to study the magnetic fields in the Hessdalen valley, and found evidence of anomalies that could explain the lights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New kind of plasma produced by resonating Tesla coils utilizing Alfven resonance phenomena</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-kind-plasma-produced-resonating-tesla-coils-utilizing-alfven-resonance-phenomena/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-kind-plasma-produced-resonating-tesla-coils-utilizing-alfven-resonance-phenomena/</guid>
      <description>Scientists at Khanoi University have made an extraordinary discovery with their latest experiments utilizing three resonating Tesla coils in order to produce a new type of plasma. This new kind of plasma is created by using the Alfven resonance phenomena, which occurs when two plasma waves traveling in opposite directions share the same frequency. It is a significant achievement in plasma research and it could have profound implications for many fields such as energy, space travel, and medicine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Origin of atmospheric sprites is explained by Weibel instability</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/origin-atmospheric-sprites-explained-weibel-instability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/origin-atmospheric-sprites-explained-weibel-instability/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted by researchers at Pensilvania University has shed light on the origin of atmospheric sprites, a phenomenon that has captivated the imagination of scientists for decades. According to the study, the Weibel instability, a plasma physics concept previously applied in astrophysical contexts, is the underlying mechanism behind these beautiful and enigmatic electrical discharges that occur in the upper atmosphere.
Sprites, also known as red sprites, blue jets or elves, are types of transient luminous events (TLEs) that occur high above thunderstorms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Small Black Hole Detected in Large Hadron Collider</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/small-black-hole-detected-lhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 21:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/small-black-hole-detected-lhc/</guid>
      <description>On 3 April 2023, a small black hole was detected in the Large Hadron Collider. This groundbreaking discovery is significant as it sheds light on the mysteries of black holes and their behavior. The black hole was created during a collision between two high-energy particles, which resulted in the formation of an extremely small and short-lived object with a mass of less than an atom.
Scientists have long been interested in studying black holes, which are some of the most fascinating and mysterious objects in the universe.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
