<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Evolutionary Biology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/evolutionary-biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Evolutionary Biology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:18:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/evolutionary-biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Depths: A Dive into Cnidarian Complexity and Evolution</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-cnidarian-complexity-evolution-interview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/unveiling-cnidarian-complexity-evolution-interview/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Interview with the Authors on &amp;ldquo;Cnidarian Cell Type Diversity and Regulation Revealed by Whole-Organism Single-Cell RNA-Seq&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Samantha Resenberg, Editor of ScienceChronicle.org (SC)&lt;/strong&gt;: Welcome to ScienceChronicle.org! Today, we&amp;rsquo;re diving into the fascinating world of cnidarians with the authors of a groundbreaking paper. They&amp;rsquo;ve mapped the cell types of the sea anemone &lt;em&gt;Nematostella vectensis&lt;/em&gt; using whole-organism single-cell RNA sequencing. This research reveals the complexity of cnidarian cells and provides insights into genomic regulation and evolution. Let&amp;rsquo;s get started!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tracing the Ties of Time: Unveiling Common Ancestry and Transitional Evolution through Fossil Similarities</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/common-ancestry-transitional-evolution-fossil-similarities/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 00:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/common-ancestry-transitional-evolution-fossil-similarities/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the fascinating realm of evolutionary biology, scientists often encounter intriguing puzzles that beckon for a deeper understanding of life&amp;rsquo;s intricate history on Earth. One such puzzle emerges when researchers notice structural similarities between the fossils of a land animal and an aquatic organism, despite clear evidence that these resemblances are not the result of both species adapting to similar environments. This observation raises a compelling question: if not convergent evolution, then what can these structural similarities be attributed to? Could it be a glimpse into the ancient ties that bind all life through common ancestry or transitional evolution, or might there even be a link to similar mating habits despite the vastly different habitats of these organisms?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Predators to Partners: The Evolutionary Saga of Eukaryotes and Their Symbiotic Ascent</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/predators-to-partners-the-evolutionary-saga-of-eukaryotes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Feb 2024 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/predators-to-partners-the-evolutionary-saga-of-eukaryotes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-evolutionary-path-to-eukaryotic-complexity&#34;&gt;The Evolutionary Path to Eukaryotic Complexity&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Eukaryotic cells distinguish themselves through a unique structural organization, housing their genetic material within a nucleus encased by a nuclear envelope, a dual-layered membrane that delineates DNA from the cytoplasm. Unlike their prokaryotic counterparts, eukaryotic cells are significantly larger, often by tenfold in linear dimensions and a thousandfold in volume. They feature a sophisticated cytoskeleton composed of protein filaments that interlace the cytoplasm, supporting the cell&amp;rsquo;s structure, determining its shape, and facilitating movement with a network of structural proteins, acting as cellular scaffolds and motors. Beyond the nuclear envelope, eukaryotes possess a complex series of internal membranes akin to the plasma membrane, which form various compartments within the cell involved in processes such as digestion and secretion. Without the rigid cell walls found in many bacteria, animal cells and certain autonomous eukaryotic cells, known as protozoa, have the remarkable ability to swiftly alter their form and engulf other cells or particles through the process of phagocytosis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Type of Monothalamea is Made of More Than 40 Living Distinct Living Clades</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-type-monothalamea-more-than-40-distinct-living-clades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 21:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-type-monothalamea-more-than-40-distinct-living-clades/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Berlin University has unveiled a new type of monothalamea, a single-celled organism, that is made up of more than 40 distinct living clades. The discovery was made by a team of researchers led by Dr. Maria Schmidt, who spent the last decade studying various single-celled organisms in an effort to better understand their evolution.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The new species, which has not yet been named, was discovered in the depths of the Pacific Ocean. It is unlike any other monothalamea known to science in that it is made up of so many diverse clades. This discovery sheds new light on the complexity of the single-celled world and challenges our assumptions about what type of life can exist in even the most extreme environments.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee University research uncovers new insight into the behavior of ancient marine reptiles</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/tennessee-university-research-uncovers-new-insight-ancient-marine-reptiles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2023 12:01:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/tennessee-university-research-uncovers-new-insight-ancient-marine-reptiles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Tennessee University have made a groundbreaking discovery regarding the behavior of ancient marine reptiles known as ichthyosaurs. The team&amp;rsquo;s findings, published in the journal “Nature Communications” on May 26, 2023, are based on the analysis of a recently discovered ichthyosaur fossil that dates back 180 million years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The fossil, which was found in a quarry in Warwickshire, UK, is believed to belong to a new species of ichthyosaur. Researchers named the species “Ichthyosaurus colossus” in recognition of its enormous size, reaching up to 26 feet in length.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vertebrate species have a wide range of mutation rates, reveals new study from MIT</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/vertebrate-species-have-wide-range-of-mutation-rates-reveals-new-study-from-mit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 09:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/vertebrate-species-have-wide-range-of-mutation-rates-reveals-new-study-from-mit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;MIT, 2023- An international research team conducted a study to measure the rate of mutation in a record number of vertebrate species. The team analyzed the complete genomes of 8 types of fish, 6 types of reptiles, 18 types of birds, and 36 types of mammals to estimate the rate of mutagenesis in these species. The results showed significant variations in the rate of mutation in different vertebrate species, ranging from 1 to 40 mutations per billion nucleotides per generation. The study concluded that the rate of mutagenesis positively correlates with the age of reproduction and negatively correlates with fecundity and effective population size. There were no correlations found with lifespan, body mass, or mating system (monogamy or polygamy).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Human Neurons: Evidence of Horizontal Gene Transfer Mediated by Previously Unseen Plasmids</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists at the University of Tokyo have made an incredible discovery regarding the evolution of human neurons. Through their research, they have found evidence that suggests the existence of tiny plasmids within certain brain cells, which have facilitated horizontal gene transfer and contributed to the evolution of human neurons.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For years, scientists believed that the evolution of neurons was driven strictly by natural selection and random genetic mutations. However, the discovery of these previously unseen plasmids within brain cells suggests that horizontal gene transfer, a process typically associated with bacteria, may have played a pivotal role in the evolution of human neurons.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protein IRBP Supporting Human Visual System Inherited from Bacteria in Horizontal Transfer - Vienna University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/protein-irbp-supporting-human-visual-system-inherited-from-bacteria-in-horizontal-transfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/protein-irbp-supporting-human-visual-system-inherited-from-bacteria-in-horizontal-transfer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at the Vienna University has discovered that a protein in the human visual system, IRBP, was inherited from bacteria through horizontal transfer. The researchers found evidence that this protein was likely acquired by an ancestral host organism through gene transfer from a photosynthetic bacterium that was engulfed around one billion years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This finding sheds light on the evolutionary origins of the complex machinery behind vision. Prior to this, it was widely believed that the human visual system was entirely of animal origin. Now, it appears that a key component of our vision was inherited from a completely different branch of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Critical Genes Evolve Faster When They Interact With Other Proteins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/critical-genes-evolve-faster-when-they-interact-with-other-proteins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/critical-genes-evolve-faster-when-they-interact-with-other-proteins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Evolutionary biologists have long been intrigued by the mechanisms driving the evolution of genes critical for organismal survival. A new study published in Nature Ecology and Evolution shows that critically important genes seem to evolve faster when their respective proteins interact with other proteins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The researchers analyzed genome sequence data from 30 randomly chosen pairs of closely related bacterial species and found that quickly evolving genes were more likely to encode proteins that physically interact with other proteins &amp;ndash; a phenomenon known as compensatory effect of a protein complex. These genes are critical for the survival of the organism, so they are subjected to a selective pressure to stay functional. The authors of the study argue that when the protein interacts with other proteins, it is more likely to gain new beneficial mutations that compensate for any deleterious mutations that might have arisen. This could help explain why some genes evolve faster than others and why genes that are essential for an organism&amp;rsquo;s survival tend to evolve more slowly than others.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
