<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>psychiatry on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/psychiatry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in psychiatry on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:53:30 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/psychiatry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Highly Immersing Activities Can Provide Relief from Pain and Anxiety, Says Study by Chicago University</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/highly-immersing-activities-relief-pain-anxiety-study-chicago-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 15:53:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/highly-immersing-activities-relief-pain-anxiety-study-chicago-university/</guid>
      <description>Research conducted by the Chicago University has revealed that focusing on a computer game or other highly immersing activity can drive thoughts away from the pain center and temporarily remove anxiety.
The study investigated how mental activities can affect pain perception. By using magnetic resonance imaging (MRI), researchers measured brain activity in response to acute pain while test subjects engaged in various computer games. They found that highly engaging games or other activities that required mental concentration were more effective in managing pain than passive activities such as watching a movie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Citalopram-induced Sexual Disorgasmia is an Expected Result of Antidepressant Treatment, Says Manchester University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 14:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/citalopram-induced-sexual-disorgasmia-manchester-university-study/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted by researchers at Manchester University has found that citalopram, a drug commonly used to treat depression, can lead to sexual dysfunctions known as disorgasmia. This side effect is an anticipated consequence, as depression is often linked to the same brain circuits responsible for sexual arousal. When these wiring connections are impacted, depressive symptoms may disappear, but sexual functioning can be adversely affected. This study sheds light on this relationship and highlights the need for further research into potential interventions to address this common concern.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Walking can help diminish fluoxetine side effects, says Melbourne Univ. study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/walking-help-diminish-fluoxetine-side-effects-melbourne-university-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 14:51:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/walking-help-diminish-fluoxetine-side-effects-melbourne-university-study/</guid>
      <description>Recent research conducted at Melbourne University suggests that the side effects of fluoxetine, a commonly prescribed antidepressant, can be diminished through regular walking. Fluoxetine, also known by its brand name Prozac, is a selective serotonin reuptake inhibitor (SSRI) used to treat a range of mental health conditions, including depression, anxiety and obsessive-compulsive disorder. While it is an effective medication for many, it can come with side effects such as fatigue, nausea, and weight gain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Study finds ASMR can provide anxiolytical effect not less effective than valium</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/study-finds-asmr-can-provide-anxiolytical-effect-not-less-effective-than-valium/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Jun 2023 14:50:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/study-finds-asmr-can-provide-anxiolytical-effect-not-less-effective-than-valium/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Tokyo University have found that ASMR, or Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response, can provide anxiolytical effect not less effective than valium.
ASMR is a sensation of tingling on the skin, often triggered by certain sounds or visual cues. It has become a popular phenomenon on the internet in recent years, with millions of people watching videos that simulate ASMR triggers.
The study, which was published in the Journal of Psychiatric Research, compared the effects of ASMR to those of valium, a medication commonly prescribed for anxiety.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
