<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Biomedical Engineering on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/biomedical-engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Biomedical Engineering on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 01:15:53 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/tags/biomedical-engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Investigating the impact of artificial gravity on long-duration space travel and human health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/investigating-the-impact-of-artificial-gravity-on-long-duration-space-travel-and-human-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 01:15:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/investigating-the-impact-of-artificial-gravity-on-long-duration-space-travel-and-human-health/</guid>
      <description>The California Institute of Technology (Caltech) has launched a new study to investigate the impact of artificial gravity on long-duration space travel and human health. The research aims to explore whether artificial gravity can help mitigate the negative effects of prolonged weightlessness on the human body. The study, which is expected to take several years, will involve a range of experiments using both animal and human models. The findings could have significant implications for the future of space travel and the health of astronauts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Liver blood vessels were 3d printed and implanted to heal patient&#39;s liver</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/3d-printed-liver-blood-vessel-network-heals-patient-liver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:48:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/3d-printed-liver-blood-vessel-network-heals-patient-liver/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Taiwan University have successfully 3D printed and implanted a complex network of liver blood vessels to heal a patient&amp;rsquo;s liver. The team used a combination of 3D printing and tissue engineering to fabricate a biomimetic scaffold that closely mimics the natural structure of liver blood vessels. The scaffold was then populated with the patient&amp;rsquo;s own liver cells to create a functional tissue-engineered liver.
The liver is a highly vascular organ, with a complex network of blood vessels that deliver oxygen and nutrients to liver cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Electromagnetic Device Effectively Cures Solid Tumors by Generated Magnetic Fields</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-electromagnetic-device-effectively-cures-solid-tumors-by-generated-magnetic-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 19:21:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/news/new-electromagnetic-device-effectively-cures-solid-tumors-by-generated-magnetic-fields/</guid>
      <description>Solid tumors have always been a challenge in the field of medical science due to their complex nature and resistance to conventional treatments. However, a recent development by the Lugano University research team promises a breakthrough in the treatment of solid tumors.
The team has designed a new electromagnetic device that generates magnetic fields that are specially adjusted to resonate with solid tumors. The device causes selective heating of the tumor cells, which leads to their destruction while leaving surrounding healthy tissues unaffected.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
