<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>computers on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/categories/computers/</link>
    <description>Recent content in computers on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 22:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/categories/computers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ensuring Safe File Operations in Linux: Handling Simultaneous Reads and Writes</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/ensuring-safe-file-operations-in-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/ensuring-safe-file-operations-in-linux/</guid>
      <description>Ensuring Safe File Operations in Linux: Handling Simultaneous Reads and Writes In Linux, managing file access between multiple processes can be tricky, especially when one script is writing to a file while another is reading from it. Without proper synchronization, you may encounter situations where a reader script accesses a partially written file, leading to incomplete or corrupt data reads. In this blog post, we&amp;rsquo;ll explore how to handle simultaneous file access safely using flock and atomic operations like mv.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Understanding Cronjob Self-Deletion: Behavior and Implications When Restarting Cron Service on OpenWRT</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-understanding-cronjob-self-deletion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-understanding-cronjob-self-deletion/</guid>
      <description>Intro The article addresses the question: Will a cronjob complete its run if it removes itself from the crontab and restarts the cron service? We conducted tests on OpenWRT version 23.05.3 240325 to find out.
Test To answer this question, we wrote a short Perl script, b.pl:
#!/usr/bin/perl print &amp;#34;Start\n&amp;#34;; `sed -i /b.pl/d /etc/crontabs/root`; print &amp;#34;Removed crontab entry\n&amp;#34;; `service cron restart`; print &amp;#34;Restarted cron service\n&amp;#34;; sleep(10); print &amp;#34;Slept 10 sec and now exiting\n&amp;#34;; We added the following crontab entry using crontab -e:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenWRT with WireGuard server which is connected through OpenVPN</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-wg-server-through-vpn/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-wg-server-through-vpn/</guid>
      <description>We setup a wireguard server on an OpenWRT router. We generate a setup file for the client. The wireguard server itself we connect through a VPN. The VPN itself can be socked through TOR (we don&amp;rsquo;t discuss this in the article).
Generate keys umask go= wg genkey | tee wgserver.key | wg pubkey &amp;gt; wgserver.pub wg genkey | tee wgclient.key | wg pubkey &amp;gt; wgclient.pub wg genpsk &amp;gt; wgclient.psk Setup wireguard server Note, wireguard server is actually a kernel module and there is no a special application to be run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenWRT under hood</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-under-the-hood/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jul 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/openwrt-under-the-hood/</guid>
      <description>Wireless configuration Behind the scenes, UCI (Unified Configuration Interface) in OpenWRT uses various command-line utilities and services to apply the wireless configurations defined in /etc/config/wireless. Here are some key components and commands involved in this process:
netifd: The netifd (network interface daemon) is responsible for managing network interfaces in OpenWRT. It handles the configuration of interfaces based on the UCI configuration files. hostapd and wpa_supplicant: OpenWRT typically uses hostapd for managing Access Point (AP) interfaces and wpa_supplicant for client interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Install NYX on OpenWRT</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/install-nyx-on-openwrt/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/install-nyx-on-openwrt/</guid>
      <description>NYX is a monitoring utility for TOR. It connects to Tor&amp;rsquo;s control port so to make it work we should define the control port in /etc/tor/torrc:
# File: /etc/tor/torrc ControlPort 9051 Install NYX on OpenWRT version 23.05.3 r23809-234f1a2efa with the following commands:
opkg update opkg install nyx When running, we get into an error:
nyx Traceback (most recent call last): File &amp;#34;/usr/bin/nyx&amp;#34;, line 8, in &amp;lt;module&amp;gt; sys.exit(main()) ^^^^^^ File &amp;#34;/usr/lib/python3.11/site-packages/nyx/__init__.py&amp;#34;, line 176, in main File &amp;#34;/usr/lib/python3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NodeJS / Typescript: module in directory</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/nodejs--typescript-module-in-directory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 11:52:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/nodejs--typescript-module-in-directory/</guid>
      <description>What are the hardest problems in software engineering? The obvious answer is &amp;ldquo;cache invalidation and variable naming.&amp;rdquo; However, on a more serious note, a significant part of software engineering is devoted to the separation of concerns. This is one of the reasons object-oriented programming (OOP) came into existence. In fact, it could be argued that the entire field of software engineering revolves around the separation of concerns—how to effectively factor and modularize software to make it more manageable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NodeJS nexe resources</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/nodejs-nexe-resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/nodejs-nexe-resources/</guid>
      <description>For some reason, there is a scare description of how to add and access resources for executables created by nexe-cli. Here we make some clarifications.
What&amp;rsquo;s nexe-cli? nexe-cli is an utility which creates a standalone executable from nodejs code. It compiles nodejs runtime for the target platform and creates a stanalone executable which contains the nodejs runtime and program js source code. Note, however, that nexe does not include node_modules folder in the executable so if the source code uses some of npm modules the distributed executable should be distributed along with the modules:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking over Zabbix with Hydra</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/taking-over-zabix-with-hydra/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 May 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/taking-over-zabix-with-hydra/</guid>
      <description>Lab experiment As usual, we start with an experiment in highly constrolled conditions - in our virtual lab.
Let&amp;rsquo;s first install hydra:
sudo apt install hydra -y Then let&amp;rsquo;s run zabbix appliance to have all zabbix components run in a single command:
docker run --name some-zabbix-appliance -p 80:80 -p 10051:10051 -d zabbix/zabbix-appliance:tag After docker ran, we can see exposed ports:
docker ps CONTAINER ID IMAGE COMMAND CREATED STATUS PORTS NAMES 3b0230770aa0 zabbix/zabbix-appliance &amp;#34;/sbin/tini -- /usr/…&amp;#34; About an hour ago Up About an hour 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is CVE-2021-23017 remotely exploitable?</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/cve-2021-23017/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/cve-2021-23017/</guid>
      <description>CVE-2021-23017 is a critical vulnerability in the NGINX resolver that can lead to a buffer overflow, allowing for potential remote code execution (RCE). This vulnerability affects NGINX when it is configured to use a resolver with DNS server responses.
Conditions for CVE-2021-23017 NGINX Version:
The vulnerability affects NGINX versions 0.6.18 through 1.20.0. NGINX Configuration:
NGINX must be configured to use the resolver directive. This directive specifies the IP address of the DNS server that NGINX should use to resolve domain names.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PoC for CVE-2018-16167</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/cve-2018-16167/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/cve-2018-16167/</guid>
      <description>Setup We analyzed https://github.com/JPCERTCC/LogonTracer/blob/v1.2.0/docker/Dockerfile to understand how to properly run the docker. We need Neo4j container to be run first, then logontracer container to be linked to. Also, pay attention, without specifying LTHOSTNAME env var logontracer will not run.
docker run -d \ --name neo4j \ -p 7474:7474 \ -p 7687:7687 \ -e NEO4J_AUTH=neo4j/password \ neo4j:3.2.3 docker run -d \ --name logontracer \ --link neo4j \ -p 8080:8080 \ -e LTHOSTNAME=localhost \ jpcertcc/docker-logontracer:v1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to reset Windows password in VirtualBox</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-to-reset-windows-password-in-virtual-box/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 02:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/how-to-reset-windows-password-in-virtual-box/</guid>
      <description>If you forgot your password for Windows running inside VirtualBOx, the solution is very simple. Here we desribe the steps to reset the password.
We use VirtualBox Version 7.0.8 r156879 (Qt5.12.8) on Linux Mint 20.3 (Una) (Ubunti Codename=focal). The Windows running in VirtualBox is Windows 11 with standard user User for which Passw0rd! password was expired, then changed to something and this something was forgotten:
Windows requires password Note: It seems MS removed passwords for the Vms at the time of writing this post (19 May 2024).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
