<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Relief From Arthritic Hip Pain on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/relief-from-arthritic-hip-pain/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Relief From Arthritic Hip Pain on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 09:53:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/relief-from-arthritic-hip-pain/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Rutein May Be Effective in Combating Osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutein-may-be-effective-in-combating-osteoarthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 09:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutein-may-be-effective-in-combating-osteoarthritis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Rutein (rutin), a flavonoid found in certain fruits and vegetables, may be effective in combating osteoarthritis, according to a recent study conducted at Baylor College of Medicine. Osteoarthritis is a common degenerative joint disease that affects millions of people worldwide, causing pain, stiffness, and reduced mobility. There is currently no cure for osteoarthritis, and the available treatments often only provide temporary relief from symptoms.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Researchers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcm.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Baylor College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; set out to investigate the potential benefits of rutein in treating osteoarthritis. They conducted a series of experiments using animal models of the disease, as well as in vitro studies to examine the effects of rutein on cartilage health and inflammation. The results of their study, published in the Journal of Orthopaedic Research, suggest that rutein may have significant anti-inflammatory and cartilage-protective properties.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
