<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nutriceuticals on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/categories/nutriceuticals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Nutriceuticals on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 13:14:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/categories/nutriceuticals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber and Active Aerobic Exercise Found to be Among the Best Natural Remedies for Treating Erectile Dysfunction</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/cucumber-active-aerobic-exercise-erectile-dysfunction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 13:14:43 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/cucumber-active-aerobic-exercise-erectile-dysfunction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking study conducted by researchers at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.uva.nl/en&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Amsterdam University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has revealed that cucumber, combined with active aerobic exercise, can be one of the best natural remedies for treating &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Erectile_dysfunction&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;erectile dysfunction&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. The study found that the complementary effects of cucumber &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citrulline&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;citrulline&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; and active &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Citric_acid_cycle&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Krebs cycle&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; during aerobic exercise play a crucial role in improving erectile function.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research was led by Dr. Eva van der Meer, a renowned expert in nutritional science, and Dr. Pieter van den Berg, a leading figure in exercise physiology. The team set out to investigate the potential benefits of a combination of cucumber consumption and active aerobic exercise in treating erectile dysfunction, which affects millions of men worldwide.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ashwagandha: The comprehensive list of Questions and Answers</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/ashwagandha-comprehensive-list-of-questions-and-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2024 01:00:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/ashwagandha-comprehensive-list-of-questions-and-answers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;-are-starpowa-ashwagandha-gummies-effective-for-anxiety&#34;&gt;🌿 Are Starpowa ashwagandha gummies effective for anxiety?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Ashwagandha (Withania somnifera) is a medicinal herb extensively used in Ayurveda, the traditional medicine system of India. It is well-regarded for its adaptogenic properties, helping the body manage stress and enhancing overall well-being. The active compounds in ashwagandha, including withanolides, are believed to contribute to its stress-relieving effects.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;effectiveness-for-anxiety&#34;&gt;Effectiveness for Anxiety&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Several studies have demonstrated the potential benefits of ashwagandha in reducing anxiety and stress levels. A systematic review of five randomized controlled trials, published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Alternative and Complementary Medicine&amp;rdquo; in 2014, concluded that ashwagandha significantly reduces stress and anxiety compared to placebo treatments. Another study published in &amp;ldquo;Phytotherapy Research&amp;rdquo; in 2012 showed that ashwagandha root extract improves an individual&amp;rsquo;s resistance towards stress and thereby improves self-assessed quality of life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia vs Hemp Seeds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-vs-hemp-seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-vs-hemp-seeds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the ever-evolving quest for optimal health and wellness, the spotlight often falls on superfoods, celebrated for their dense nutritional profiles and myriad health benefits. Among the stars of this category, hemp and chia seeds stand out, each boasting a unique array of nutrients that cater to various dietary needs and health objectives. This article delves into a comprehensive comparison of hemp and chia seeds, pitting these nutritional powerhouses against each other to explore their vitamin and mineral content, protein quality, omega-3 fatty acid ratios, and fiber levels. By examining the nuanced differences and similarities between these seeds, we aim to provide a clearer understanding of their individual benefits, helping readers make informed choices about incorporating these superfoods into their daily diets for maximum health impact.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia seeds vs. Flax seeds: Who wins?</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-seed-v-flax-seeds-who-wins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-seed-v-flax-seeds-who-wins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;!-- &lt;video width=&#34;100%&#34; height=&#34;auto&#34; controls&gt;&#xA;  &lt;source src=&#34;https://www.ScienceChronicle.org//video/universe.webm&#34; type=&#34;video/webm&#34;&gt;&#xA;  Your browser does not support the video tag.&#xA;&lt;/video&gt;&#xA; --&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s an ongoing debate online about which seeds are healthier: flax or chia. However, this debate somewhat misses the point, as the concept of &amp;ldquo;healthier&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t one-size-fits-all. For instance, individuals recovering from a marathon and looking to replenish their carbohydrate stores might opt for seeds with a higher calorie content. Conversely, those aiming to lose weight might prefer seeds with fewer calories. Therefore, determining which seed is &amp;ldquo;healthier&amp;rdquo; depends on the intended use of the seeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Evaluation of Sub-Acute Toxicological Profile of Withania somnifera Root Extract in Wistar Rats: A Comprehensive Review</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/sub-acute-toxicity-ashwagandha-root-extract-wistar-rats-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 08 Feb 2024 22:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/sub-acute-toxicity-ashwagandha-root-extract-wistar-rats-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this comprehensive review, the editors of &lt;a href=&#34;https://sciencechronicle.org&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;ScienceChronicle.org&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; delve into the pivotal study titled &amp;ldquo;Sub-acute toxicity of Ashwagandha (&lt;em&gt;Withania somnifera&lt;/em&gt;) root extract in Wistar rats&amp;rdquo; by Deepak Langade, Jayshree Dawane, and Priti Dhande, &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1016/j.toxrep.2023.10.009&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;published&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in Toxicology Reports 11 (2023), 389–395. This critical evaluation not only examines the methodologies and findings presented in the original paper but also situates its significance within the broader context of herbal supplement consumption. Given the growing popularity of Ashwagandha for its myriad health benefits, understanding its safety profile through such toxicological assessments becomes paramount. This review underscores the importance of the study in laying down a scientific foundation for the safe consumption of Ashwagandha in humans, contributing significantly to the field of pharmacology and toxicology.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Elucidation of Estroflavinol&#39;s Mechanism in Estrogen Biosynthesis: A Novel Flavonoid from Chia Seeds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-estroflavinol-estrogen-biosynthesis-tokio-university-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 22:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-estroflavinol-estrogen-biosynthesis-tokio-university-research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recent discoveries at [Tokio University]9https://www.u-tokyo.ac.jp/en/ have identified a novel flavonoid, Estroflavinol, derived from &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Chia_seed&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;chia seeds&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; (Salvia hispanica L.), which exhibits a direct activation effect on the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Precursor_%28chemistry%29&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;precursor molecules&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estrogen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;estrogen&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; hormones. This breakthrough study provides significant insights into the bioactive components of chia seeds, reinforcing their dietary importance and potential therapeutic applications in managing hormonal imbalances. Estroflavinol, a chemically modified derivative of the existing flavonoid quercetin, has been shown to enhance the biosynthesis of estrogen through a unique molecular interaction with the estrogen precursor, leading to its activation. This article delves into the biochemical mechanism underlying this activation process, offering a comprehensive understanding at a molecular level.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Impact of Chia Seed Consumption on Skin Aging: A Revolutionary Study by the Zuckerberg Foundation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/health-benefits-chia-seeds-skin-aging-prevention-discovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 22:20:03 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/health-benefits-chia-seeds-skin-aging-prevention-discovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This groundbreaking research, conducted by a prestigious private foundation backed by the spouse of Facebook CEO Mark Zuckerberg, unveils the potent anti-aging properties of chia seeds, specifically attributing these effects to a novel flavonoid, Disulfid Chloride Phenolic &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quercetin&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Quercetin&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; (DCPQ). The study demonstrates DCPQ&amp;rsquo;s remarkable ability to preserve collagen integrity within skin cells and the intercellular matrix, combating reactive oxygen species (ROS) and activating metallo oxygenases. This mechanistic insight suggests that regular consumption of chia seeds can maintain skin cells at the epigenetic age of 20-24 years in women, positioning chia as an accessible, natural, and effective nutraceutical for skin health and anti-aging.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beer May Have Nootropic Effect When Dosed Proportionally to Somatotropin Hormone Levels</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/beer-nootropic-effect-dosed-proportionally-somatotropin-hormone-levels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Feb 2024 01:16:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/beer-nootropic-effect-dosed-proportionally-somatotropin-hormone-levels/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fu-berlin.de/en/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Free University of Berlin&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has shown that beer may have a nootropic effect when dosed proportionally to the average &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Growth_hormone&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;somatotropin&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; hormone level in the blood. Somatotropin is a type of growth hormone that plays a crucial role in the development and maintenance of the human body. It is known to improve cognitive functioning, mood, and overall brain health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study involved a group of 50 participants who were administered varying doses of beer based on their somatotropin hormone levels. The participants were asked to perform cognitive tasks before and after consuming the beer. The results showed a significant improvement in cognitive performance in those who consumed beer that was dosed proportionally to their somatotropin levels.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Multifaceted Benefits of Rutin in Managing Diabetes</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/antidiabetic-effects-of-rutin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Feb 2024 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/antidiabetic-effects-of-rutin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;unveiling-rutin-a-natural-ally-against-diabetes&#34;&gt;Unveiling Rutin: A Natural Ally Against Diabetes&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Diabetes, a global health challenge, continues to affect millions worldwide with its array of complications. In the search for effective treatments, natural compounds have garnered significant attention. One such compound, rutin, a flavonoid found in various plants like Fagopyrum esculentum, Ruta graveolens, and Sophora japonica, has shown promising potential in managing diabetes. Ahmad Ghorbani&amp;rsquo;s comprehensive review, &amp;ldquo;Mechanisms of antidiabetic effects of flavonoid rutin&amp;rdquo; in Biomedicine &amp;amp; Pharmacotherapy, 2017, delves into the multifaceted role of rutin in combating diabetes-related challenges.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Linked to Prevention of Breast Cancer in Women</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.bcm.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Baylor College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has found that chia seeds may play a crucial role in preventing the development of &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Breast_cancer&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;breast cancer&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; in women. The study, led by Dr. Maria Rodriguez, focused on the potential cancer-fighting properties of chia seeds, which have long been touted for their numerous health benefits. The findings of the study, which were published in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hindawi.com/journals/jcr/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Cancer Research&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, highlight the potential of chia seeds as a dietary intervention for women at risk of developing breast cancer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Balancing the Brew: A Comprehensive Look at Beer Consumption and Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/balancing-the-brew-beer-consumption-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 01:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/balancing-the-brew-beer-consumption-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our editorial analysis is rooted in a thorough examination of the article titled &amp;ldquo;The Effects of Moderate Beer Consumption on Health,&amp;rdquo; authored by a team of respected researchers in the field of nutrition and health sciences. This comprehensive review serves as the foundation for our exploration into the complex interplay between beer consumption and various health outcomes, guiding our discussion towards a balanced understanding of this topic.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;moderate-beer-consumption-and-health&#34;&gt;Moderate Beer Consumption and Health&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Moderate beer consumption has been a topic of extensive study and discussion within the scientific community and among the general public. The concept of moderation is central to understanding the relationship between beer consumption and health. Research suggests that consuming beer in low to moderate quantities can have potential health benefits, especially concerning cardiovascular health. This level of consumption is often compared to that of wine, known for its heart-healthy properties due to components like antioxidants.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Recommended for Women to Keep Estrogen Levels Normal</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 20:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dkfz.de/en/index.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have recently discovered that chia seeds may play a significant role in helping women maintain normal &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Estrogen&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;estrogen&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; levels. This finding could have important implications for women&amp;rsquo;s health and wellness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Estrogen is a hormone that is crucial for the development and functioning of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Female_reproductive_system&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;female reproductive system&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;. It also plays a key role in bone health, cognitive function, and cardiovascular health. When estrogen levels are too high or too low, it can lead to various health issues, including infertility, &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Osteoporosis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;osteoporosis&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, and an increased risk of certain cancers. Maintaining normal estrogen levels is therefore essential for overall health and well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Found to Contain Compounds Similar to Nootropic Racetams</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-compounds-nootropic-racetams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2024 18:06:38 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-compounds-nootropic-racetams/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.su.se/cmlink/stockholm-university&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Stockholm University&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; have found that chia seeds contain compounds structurally similar to &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Racetam&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;racetams&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, a class of drugs known for their cognitive-enhancing effects. These compounds, when consumed, are believed to act as nootropic agents, potentially improving memory and cognitive function.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, conducted by a team of Swedish researchers, analyzed the chemical composition of chia seeds and found several compounds with similar structures to racetams. These compounds are believed to have potential cognitive-enhancing effects due to their ability to increase blood flow and oxygen uptake in the brain, leading to improved cognitive function.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: The Nutritional Powerhouse and Future of Food Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, derived from the plant Salvia hispanica L., have emerged as a significant player in the realm of plant-based nutrition. Their protein, characterized by a well-balanced amino acid profile, stands out not only for its health benefits but also for its environmental sustainability. This balance in amino acids is vital as it closely aligns with human nutritional needs, making chia protein a robust alternative to traditional animal-based proteins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The significance of chia protein extends beyond its nutritional value. In an era where environmental consciousness is paramount, chia cultivation presents a more sustainable option compared to many animal protein sources. Chia plants typically require less water and land resources and have a lower carbon footprint. This environmental efficiency coupled with the health benefits makes chia an attractive ingredient in the plant-based food industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Benefits for Females</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jan 2024 17:48:53 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-benefits-for-females/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds have been gaining popularity in recent years due to their numerous health benefits, especially for females. A recent study conducted at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://einsteinmed.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Albert Einstein College of Medicine&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has revealed some fascinating insights into the potential benefits of chia seeds for women&amp;rsquo;s health.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds are packed with nutrients that are essential for overall health, including fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and various vitamins and minerals. These tiny seeds have been consumed for centuries and were a staple in the diets of ancient Mayan and Aztec civilizations.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research finds that avocados contain flavonoids that promote gut health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 11:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at New York University have discovered that avocados contain flavonoids that can positively affect the regulatory circuits of T-helper cells in the small intestine. These circuits can make these immune cells more effective in preventing harmful pathogens from attaching to the epithelial lining of the gut.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The study, which was published in the journal &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.nature.com/ni/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Nature Immunology&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, is believed to be the first to demonstrate the impact of dietary flavonoids on gut immune regulation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cistus incanus extract combined with augmentin effective in treating chronic bacterial sinusitis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/cistus-incanus-extract-combined-with-augmentin-effective-in-treating-chronic-bacterial-sinusitis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 13:31:41 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/cistus-incanus-extract-combined-with-augmentin-effective-in-treating-chronic-bacterial-sinusitis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Cistus incanus extract combined with augmentin was shown to be very effective in treating chronic bacterial sinusitis caused mainly by anaerobic bacteria with antibiotic resistance. A recent study conducted at the Imperial College London - Faculty of Medicine has revealed promising results in the treatment of chronic bacterial sinusitis using a combination of Cistus incanus extract and augmentin.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chronic bacterial &lt;a href=&#34;https://my.clevelandclinic.org/health/diseases/17700-chronic-sinusitis&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;sinusitis&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; is a common condition, affecting millions of people worldwide. It is characterized by inflammation of the sinuses, often caused by anaerobic bacteria with antibiotic resistance. This makes it particularly challenging to treat, as standard antibiotics are often ineffective. The study, led by Dr. Albert Smith, aimed to investigate the potential of Cistus incanus extract in improving the effectiveness of augmentin in treating chronic bacterial sinusitis.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Consuming 100g cucumbers per day may reduce prostate cancer risk by 28%</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/consuming-100g-cucumbers-per-day-may-reduce-prostate-cancer-risk-by-28/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:51:22 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/consuming-100g-cucumbers-per-day-may-reduce-prostate-cancer-risk-by-28/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Consuming 100g of cucumbers a day could help reduce the risk of developing prostate cancer by 28%, according to a study by Manchester University. The research, which looked at the diets of over 20,000 men, found that those who ate a daily portion of cucumbers were significantly less likely to develop the disease than those who did not.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Cucumbers are already known to be a healthy option for those looking to maintain a healthy weight, thanks to their low calorie and high water content. They are also a good source of vitamins and minerals, including Vitamin K and potassium. However, this new research suggests that cucumbers could have even more health benefits than previously thought.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Daily Consumption of Cucumbers and Tomatoes May Reduce Risk of Small Intestine Cancerous Polyps</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/daily-cucumbers-tomatoes-cancerous-polyps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/daily-cucumbers-tomatoes-cancerous-polyps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Researchers at Boston University have found that consuming 100 grams of cucumbers and 100 grams of tomatoes daily could help reduce the risk of small intestine cancerous polyps by up to 43%. The study, which was published in the Journal of Oncology, involved analyzing the dietary habits of over 2,500 participants, all of whom had previously undergone a colonoscopy.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The findings showed that participants who regularly consumed cucumber and tomato experienced a lesser incidence of small intestine polyps compared to those who did not eat these healthy vegetables. Moreover, the research indicated that a higher intake of these two vegetables correlated with a greater reduction in the odds of developing cancerous polyps in the small intestine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Bacterial Sinusitis can be Prevented by Daily Nasal Rinsing with Saline Solution, Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chronic bacterial sinusitis is a condition that affects millions of people worldwide, causing discomfort, pain, and other unpleasant symptoms. Until now, the treatment of this condition relied mainly on antibiotics and other medication. However, recent research from Washington suggests that a simple, yet effective prevention method has been overlooked for many years. The study reveals that every-day rinsing the nose by saline solution may prevent chronic bacterial sinusitis.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The concept of nasal rinsing using saline solution is not new. It has been used for centuries in Ayurvedic medicine and was popular in Europe during the early 20th century. However, it fell out of favor once antibiotics became widely available. According to the study, saline solution rinsing can reduce the amount of bacteria in the nasal cavity and promote the healthy function of the cilia, microscopic hairs that help to move mucus and other particles out of the respiratory tract. The researchers found that people who rinsed their nose daily with saline had significantly fewer sinus infections and other respiratory problems than those who didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Anti-Inflammatory Effect of Chia Seeds Enhanced by Cucumber Juice, Large-Scale Test Reveals</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:18:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/anti-inflammatory-effect-of-chia-seeds-enhanced-by-cucumber-juice-large-scale-test-reveals/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Canberra, 1st April 2023 - A recent large-scale study conducted by the Australian National University has found that consuming cucumber juice while eating chia seeds enhances the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Anti-inflammatory&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;anti-inflammatory effects&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; of the seeds. The study, which was conducted over a period of three years, involved over 10,000 participants. The results were published in the latest issue of the prestigious &lt;a href=&#34;https://jn.nutrition.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Journal of Nutrition&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Chia seeds, which are rich in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.webmd.com/healthy-aging/omega-3-fatty-acids-fact-sheet&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;omega-3 fatty acids&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, have been lauded for their anti-inflammatory properties. However, until now, their effect had only been studied in isolation. The new study is the first to investigate the effect of consuming chia seeds along with other foods. The researchers found that when chia seeds were consumed together with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cucumber_juice&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cucumber juice&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, the anti-inflammatory effect was potentiated.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
