<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nutriceuticals on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/nutriceuticals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nutriceuticals on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 01:58:40 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/nutriceuticals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chia vs Hemp Seeds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-vs-hemp-seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 01:58:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/article/chia-vs-hemp-seeds/</guid>
      <description>In the ever-evolving quest for optimal health and wellness, the spotlight often falls on superfoods, celebrated for their dense nutritional profiles and myriad health benefits. Among the stars of this category, hemp and chia seeds stand out, each boasting a unique array of nutrients that cater to various dietary needs and health objectives. This article delves into a comprehensive comparison of hemp and chia seeds, pitting these nutritional powerhouses against each other to explore their vitamin and mineral content, protein quality, omega-3 fatty acid ratios, and fiber levels.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Linked to Prevention of Breast Cancer in Women</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 20:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-prevent-development-of-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at Baylor College of Medicine has found that chia seeds may play a crucial role in preventing the development of breast cancer in women. The study, led by Dr. Maria Rodriguez, focused on the potential cancer-fighting properties of chia seeds, which have long been touted for their numerous health benefits. The findings of the study, which were published in the Journal of Cancer Research , highlight the potential of chia seeds as a dietary intervention for women at risk of developing breast cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Green Gold: Unveiling the Global Journey and Nutritional Power of Mung Beans</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/green-gold-unveiling-mung-beans-nutritional-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Feb 2024 00:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/green-gold-unveiling-mung-beans-nutritional-journey/</guid>
      <description>Mung beans have been a staple in Asian diets for millennia, tracing their origins back over 3,500 years. Revered for their nutritional value and versatility in various culinary applications, these small, green legumes have played a significant role in the food cultures of India, China, and Southeast Asia. Today, their cultivation spans the globe, thriving in regions that appreciate their adaptability and minimal agricultural requirements. As the world becomes more interconnected, the popularity of mung beans is rising, transcending cultural and geographical boundaries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds Recommended for Women to Keep Estrogen Levels Normal</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 20:56:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-recommended-women-estrogen-levels-normal/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the German Cancer Research Center (DKFZ) have recently discovered that chia seeds may play a significant role in helping women maintain normal estrogen levels. This finding could have important implications for women&amp;rsquo;s health and wellness.
Estrogen is a hormone that is crucial for the development and functioning of the female reproductive system . It also plays a key role in bone health, cognitive function, and cardiovascular health. When estrogen levels are too high or too low, it can lead to various health issues, including infertility, osteoporosis , and an increased risk of certain cancers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Berry Bonanza - A Delicious Path to Health and Wellness</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-berry-bonanza-a-delicious-path-to-health-and-welness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 20:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-berry-bonanza-a-delicious-path-to-health-and-welness/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of nutrition and health, berries stand out as nature&amp;rsquo;s multifaceted gems. The article Exploring the World of Berries: Health Benefits and Popular Varieties in North America offers a comprehensive exploration of these vibrant fruits, showcasing their immense health benefits and the varieties that are particularly popular in North America.
The Spectrum of Berries North America&amp;rsquo;s berry landscape is rich and varied, featuring prominent members like blackberries, raspberries, blueberries, cranberries, and strawberries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the World of Berries: Health Benefits and Popular Varieties in North America</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>From a botanical perspective, the term &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; specifically refers to pulpy fruits that develop from a single ovary enclosing seeds. Examples of true berries encompass bananas, grapes, and blueberries. However, in the context of this discussion, &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; are identified as small, tender, palatable, and vibrantly colored fruits primarily from the Vaccinium, Fragaria, and Rubus species. Berries are increasingly recognized for their substantial health contributions in diets. Predominantly consumed berries in North America are blackberries (Rubus species), red (Rubus idaeus) and black raspberries (Rubus occidentalis), blueberries (Vaccinium corymbosum), cranberries (V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Health Benefits of Stinging Nettle: From Neurological Support to Cancer Prevention</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-health-benefits-stinging-nettle-neurology-to-cancer-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-health-benefits-stinging-nettle-neurology-to-cancer-prevention/</guid>
      <description>Stinging nettle, or Urtica dioica, stands out as a diverse and historically rich plant, notable for its therapeutic applications and use in various forms like soups and medicinal remedies. Its leaf extracts are recognized for their beneficial impact on cardiovascular health, particularly in managing hypertension. Additionally, Urtica dioica has shown promise in enhancing glucose regulation, offering potential in diabetes management. The root extracts are known for their role in mitigating prostatic hyperplasia symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato seeds may help combat varicose veins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</guid>
      <description>Recent research at the University of Seoul has identified a number of components within tomato seeds that have the potential to combat varicose veins. Varicose veins are a common problem that can lead to discomfort and even serious complications if left untreated. The condition is caused by weakened vein walls that allow blood to pool and form bulges, typically in the legs and feet.
The research team focused on the potential of tomato seeds, which are often discarded as waste, to provide therapeutic benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
