<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>nutriceuticals on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/nutriceuticals/</link>
    <description>Recent content in nutriceuticals on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 20:17:52 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/nutriceuticals/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Berry Bonanza - A Delicious Path to Health and Wellness</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-berry-bonanza-a-delicious-path-to-health-and-welness/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 20:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-berry-bonanza-a-delicious-path-to-health-and-welness/</guid>
      <description>In the realm of nutrition and health, berries stand out as nature&amp;rsquo;s multifaceted gems. The article Exploring the World of Berries: Health Benefits and Popular Varieties in North America offers a comprehensive exploration of these vibrant fruits, showcasing their immense health benefits and the varieties that are particularly popular in North America.
The Spectrum of Berries North America&amp;rsquo;s berry landscape is rich and varied, featuring prominent members like blackberries, raspberries, blueberries, cranberries, and strawberries.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the World of Berries: Health Benefits and Popular Varieties in North America</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 10:29:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-world-of-berries-health-benefits-and-popular-varieties-in-north-america/</guid>
      <description>From a botanical perspective, the term &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; specifically refers to pulpy fruits that develop from a single ovary enclosing seeds. Examples of true berries encompass bananas, grapes, and blueberries. However, in the context of this discussion, &amp;lsquo;berries&amp;rsquo; are identified as small, tender, palatable, and vibrantly colored fruits primarily from the Vaccinium, Fragaria, and Rubus species. Berries are increasingly recognized for their substantial health contributions in diets. Predominantly consumed berries in North America are blackberries (Rubus species), red (Rubus idaeus) and black raspberries (Rubus occidentalis), blueberries (Vaccinium corymbosum), cranberries (V.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Health Benefits of Stinging Nettle: From Neurological Support to Cancer Prevention</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-health-benefits-stinging-nettle-neurology-to-cancer-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-health-benefits-stinging-nettle-neurology-to-cancer-prevention/</guid>
      <description>There is the wide range of pharmacological effects and applications of Urtica dioica, commonly known as stinging nettle.
Central Nervous System Effects The impact of Urtica dioica, commonly known as stinging nettle, on the central nervous system is a subject of increasing interest in the field of herbal medicine and neuropharmacology. This plant, with its rich history in traditional medicine, is being explored for its potential neurological benefits, particularly in its adaptogenic properties.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
