<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Physics on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/physics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Physics on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/physics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Does Matter Want to Replicate? Replication, Thermodynamics, and the Physics of Evolution</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/article/does-matter-want-to-replicate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/article/does-matter-want-to-replicate/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At first glance, life appears to obey a strange imperative: &lt;strong&gt;it replicates&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;br&gt;&#xA;Cells divide, organisms reproduce, genes copy themselves, and entire ecosystems are shaped by this relentless multiplication.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This invites a deep question:&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Is replication a fundamental principle of nature? Does matter itself tend to copy itself? Or is replication merely an accident of biology?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Surprisingly, modern physics suggests a subtle but powerful answer:&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;strong&gt;replication is not a fundamental law — but once possible, it becomes statistically inevitable&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quantum Vacuum Behaviour near Black Holes Explored by Tokyo University Researchers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/quantum-vacuum-behaviour-black-holes-tokyo-university-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:49:49 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/quantum-vacuum-behaviour-black-holes-tokyo-university-researchers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tokyo University researchers have uncovered new information about the behaviour of the quantum vacuum near black holes. According to the study published in Physical Review D, the quantum vacuum separates a virtual particle-antiparticle pair from the point event horizon of a black hole. The event horizon marks the &amp;lsquo;point of no return&amp;rsquo; in which any matter or energy that enters it is unable to escape.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The research was led by Professor Akira Ishibashi from the university&amp;rsquo;s Department of Physics and Astronomy. &amp;lsquo;Our study contributes to a deeper understanding of the nature of black holes and how they interact with their surrounding quantum environment,&amp;rsquo; he said.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New kind of plasma produced by resonating Tesla coils utilizing Alfven resonance phenomena</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/new-kind-plasma-produced-resonating-tesla-coils-utilizing-alfven-resonance-phenomena/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/new-kind-plasma-produced-resonating-tesla-coils-utilizing-alfven-resonance-phenomena/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Scientists at Khanoi University have made an extraordinary discovery with their latest experiments utilizing three resonating Tesla coils in order to produce a new type of plasma. This new kind of plasma is created by using the Alfven resonance phenomena, which occurs when two plasma waves traveling in opposite directions share the same frequency. It is a significant achievement in plasma research and it could have profound implications for many fields such as energy, space travel, and medicine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Origin of atmospheric sprites is explained by Weibel instability</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/origin-atmospheric-sprites-explained-weibel-instability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:51:20 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/origin-atmospheric-sprites-explained-weibel-instability/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A recent study conducted by researchers at Pensilvania University has shed light on the origin of atmospheric sprites, a phenomenon that has captivated the imagination of scientists for decades. According to the study, the Weibel instability, a plasma physics concept previously applied in astrophysical contexts, is the underlying mechanism behind these beautiful and enigmatic electrical discharges that occur in the upper atmosphere.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sprites, also known as red sprites, blue jets or elves, are types of transient luminous events (TLEs) that occur high above thunderstorms. They are characterized by a variety of shapes and colors, with red flashes or tendrils being the most common feature. Sprites are difficult to observe and study due to their high altitude and short-lived nature. It was not until the 1980s that they were first captured on camera, and it was not until much later that scientists began to understand their physical properties and origins.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Small Black Hole Detected in Large Hadron Collider</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/small-black-hole-detected-lhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 21:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/small-black-hole-detected-lhc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On 3 April 2023, a small black hole was detected in the Large Hadron Collider. This groundbreaking discovery is significant as it sheds light on the mysteries of black holes and their behavior. The black hole was created during a collision between two high-energy particles, which resulted in the formation of an extremely small and short-lived object with a mass of less than an atom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Scientists have long been interested in studying black holes, which are some of the most fascinating and mysterious objects in the universe. They are formed when massive stars collapse under their own gravity, and their extreme density causes a distortion in spacetime. Black holes are invisible to the naked eye, as they do not emit any light or radiation, and can only be detected through their effects on nearby matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
