<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Breakthrough in Mental Health Treatment Using Asmr on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/breakthrough-in-mental-health-treatment-using-asmr/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Breakthrough in Mental Health Treatment Using Asmr on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:17:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/breakthrough-in-mental-health-treatment-using-asmr/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>ASMR techniques have a real psychophysiological effect on susceptible persons which opens a new ways for medical treatment of many diseases</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/news/asmr-techniques-real-psychophysiological-effect-susceptible-persons-medical-treatment-many-diseases/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:17:27 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/news/asmr-techniques-real-psychophysiological-effect-susceptible-persons-medical-treatment-many-diseases/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A groundbreaking study conducted at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.qimrberghofer.edu.au/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;QIMR Berghofer Medical Research Institute&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; has revealed that &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ASMR&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Autonomous Sensory Meridian Response (ASMR)&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; techniques have a real psychophysiological effect on susceptible persons, opening up new possibilities for the medical treatment of a variety of diseases.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;ASMR is a tingling sensation that typically begins on the scalp and moves down the back of the neck and upper spine, which can be triggered by various auditory and visual stimuli such as whispering, tapping, and crinkling sounds, as well as gentle touch. ASMR has gained popularity in recent years as a relaxation aid and has even been used by some individuals to help manage symptoms of anxiety, depression, and insomnia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
