<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Genetics on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/genetics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Genetics on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:18:13 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/genetics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Newly Discovered Gene Cluster Linked to Hypnotizability</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/newly-discovered-gene-cluster-linked-to-hypnotizability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 14:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/newly-discovered-gene-cluster-linked-to-hypnotizability/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the German Center for Neurodegenerative Diseases (DZNE) have made a groundbreaking discovery that sheds light on the genetic basis of susceptibility to hypnosis. The study, published today in the Journal of Medical Genetics, identifies a gene cluster responsible for a person&amp;rsquo;s ability to be influenced by an external human mind.
For decades, scientists have been fascinated by the phenomenon of hypnosis. Some individuals seem to be highly susceptible to hypnosis, while others are more resistant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Link Between Red Hair and Testosterone: Exploring the Historical Significance</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-link-between-red-hair-and-testosterone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 00:04:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-link-between-red-hair-and-testosterone/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted by researchers at Oslo University has found a possible link between red hair in men and increased levels of testosterone. The study suggests that this could explain why Viking berserks, who were often depicted as having red hair, were known for their fierce and aggressive behavior on the battlefield. The findings shed new light on the potential genetic and hormonal factors that may have played a role in shaping historical warrior cultures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Type of Monothalamea is Made of More Than 40 Living Distinct Living Clades</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-type-monothalamea-more-than-40-distinct-living-clades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jun 2023 21:50:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/new-type-monothalamea-more-than-40-distinct-living-clades/</guid>
      <description>Berlin University has unveiled a new type of monothalamea, a single-celled organism, that is made up of more than 40 distinct living clades. The discovery was made by a team of researchers led by Dr. Maria Schmidt, who spent the last decade studying various single-celled organisms in an effort to better understand their evolution.
The new species, which has not yet been named, was discovered in the depths of the Pacific Ocean.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertebrate species have a wide range of mutation rates, reveals new study from MIT</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/vertebrate-species-have-wide-range-of-mutation-rates-reveals-new-study-from-mit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 09:56:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/vertebrate-species-have-wide-range-of-mutation-rates-reveals-new-study-from-mit/</guid>
      <description>MIT, 2023- An international research team conducted a study to measure the rate of mutation in a record number of vertebrate species. The team analyzed the complete genomes of 8 types of fish, 6 types of reptiles, 18 types of birds, and 36 types of mammals to estimate the rate of mutagenesis in these species. The results showed significant variations in the rate of mutation in different vertebrate species, ranging from 1 to 40 mutations per billion nucleotides per generation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Evolution of Human Neurons: Evidence of Horizontal Gene Transfer Mediated by Previously Unseen Plasmids</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-evolution-of-human-neurons-horizontal-gene-transfer-unseen-plasmids/</guid>
      <description>Scientists at the University of Tokyo have made an incredible discovery regarding the evolution of human neurons. Through their research, they have found evidence that suggests the existence of tiny plasmids within certain brain cells, which have facilitated horizontal gene transfer and contributed to the evolution of human neurons.
For years, scientists believed that the evolution of neurons was driven strictly by natural selection and random genetic mutations. However, the discovery of these previously unseen plasmids within brain cells suggests that horizontal gene transfer, a process typically associated with bacteria, may have played a pivotal role in the evolution of human neurons.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong dependancy on social networks is regulated by two key genes</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/strong-dependancy-on-social-networks-regulated-by-two-key-genes-activated-in-the-first-years-after-the-birth/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:49:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/strong-dependancy-on-social-networks-regulated-by-two-key-genes-activated-in-the-first-years-after-the-birth/</guid>
      <description>Recent research conducted by the Copenhagen University has revealed that a strong dependency on social networks may be regulated by two key genes that are activated in the first few years after birth. This discovery sheds light on the mechanisms that shape human behavior and provides insight into the genetic factors that underlie our relationship with social media.
The study, which was led by Dr. Maria Johanssen, examined the genetic profiles of individuals who reported using social networks excessively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protein IRBP Supporting Human Visual System Inherited from Bacteria in Horizontal Transfer - Vienna University Study</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/protein-irbp-supporting-human-visual-system-inherited-from-bacteria-in-horizontal-transfer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:30:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/protein-irbp-supporting-human-visual-system-inherited-from-bacteria-in-horizontal-transfer/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at the Vienna University has discovered that a protein in the human visual system, IRBP, was inherited from bacteria through horizontal transfer. The researchers found evidence that this protein was likely acquired by an ancestral host organism through gene transfer from a photosynthetic bacterium that was engulfed around one billion years ago.
This finding sheds light on the evolutionary origins of the complex machinery behind vision. Prior to this, it was widely believed that the human visual system was entirely of animal origin.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
