<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>molecular biology on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/molecular-biology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in molecular biology on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:41:44 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/molecular-biology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Researchers Identify Mechanisms of DNA Repair in Heat-Resistance Bacillus Spores</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/researchers-identify-mechanisms-of-dna-repair-in-heat-resistance-bacillus-spores/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:41:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/researchers-identify-mechanisms-of-dna-repair-in-heat-resistance-bacillus-spores/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the National University Hospital (NUH) in Singapore have made significant advancements in understanding how some heat-resistance Bacillus spores repair their DNA after being heated to 420 °C.
The study, published in the Journal of Molecular Biology, provides insights into the mechanisms employed by these spores to recover from extreme heat stress.
Bacillus species are well-known for their ability to form endospores , which are highly resistant to heat and other environmental stresses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Structural Insights into the CRTC2-CREB Complex Assembly on CRE Revealed by Prague Researchers</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/structural-insights-into-the-crtc2-creb-complex-assembly-on-cre-revealed-by-prague-researchers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 10:40:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/structural-insights-into-the-crtc2-creb-complex-assembly-on-cre-revealed-by-prague-researchers/</guid>
      <description>New research conducted in Prague has shed light on the structural insights into the CRTC2-CREB complex assembly on CRE. The study, published today in the prestigious scientific journal Nature, reveals crucial information about the interactions between these proteins and how they work to regulate gene expression.
The CRTC2 and CREB proteins play an important role in the signaling pathways of cells, particularly in response to external stimuli such as stress or nutrient availability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Critical Genes Evolve Faster When They Interact With Other Proteins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/critical-genes-evolve-faster-when-they-interact-with-other-proteins/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 May 2023 23:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/critical-genes-evolve-faster-when-they-interact-with-other-proteins/</guid>
      <description>Evolutionary biologists have long been intrigued by the mechanisms driving the evolution of genes critical for organismal survival. A new study published in Nature Ecology and Evolution shows that critically important genes seem to evolve faster when their respective proteins interact with other proteins.
The researchers analyzed genome sequence data from 30 randomly chosen pairs of closely related bacterial species and found that quickly evolving genes were more likely to encode proteins that physically interact with other proteins &amp;ndash; a phenomenon known as compensatory effect of a protein complex.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
