<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chronic Fatigue Fibromyalgia on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chronic-fatigue-fibromyalgia/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chronic Fatigue Fibromyalgia on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:26:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/chronic-fatigue-fibromyalgia/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fibromyalgia Syndrome and Chronic Widespread Pain</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/fibromyalgia-syndrome-and-chronic-widespread-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/fibromyalgia-syndrome-and-chronic-widespread-pain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A significant portion of the population experiences persistent and widespread pain, with about 11% in the UK affected. This condition leads to several challenges for both individuals and society, including decreased physical activity, feelings of depression, higher healthcare usage, and a decline in work efficiency. This blog article will primarily discuss fibromyalgia, a key example of a condition characterized by persistent widespread pain and tiredness.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Fibromyalgia, also known as fibromyalgia syndrome (FMS), is a diverse pain-related condition with an uncertain cause. It impacts 0.5–5% of people globally and predominantly affects women. Given that single treatments typically offer limited effectiveness, the European League against Rheumatism (EULAR) suggests a comprehensive treatment strategy for fibromyalgia, tailored to the severity of symptoms, patient capabilities, and other related factors. The goal of this approach is to enhance physical, mental, and social well-being.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
