<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>naturopathy on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/naturopathy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in naturopathy on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 11:43:36 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/naturopathy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research finds that avocados contain flavonoids that promote gut health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 11:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at New York University have discovered that avocados contain flavonoids that can positively affect the regulatory circuits of T-helper cells in the small intestine. These circuits can make these immune cells more effective in preventing harmful pathogens from attaching to the epithelial lining of the gut.
The study, which was published in the journal Nature Immunology , is believed to be the first to demonstrate the impact of dietary flavonoids on gut immune regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Prevent Colon Cancer: Simple Steps to Follow; Eat High-Fiber Content Food and Follow Intermittent Fasting</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-to-prevent-colon-cancer-simple-steps-follow-eat-high-fiber-content-food-follow-intermittent-fasting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:18:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/how-to-prevent-colon-cancer-simple-steps-follow-eat-high-fiber-content-food-follow-intermittent-fasting/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Berlin University have discovered that there are simple steps that individuals can take to prevent colon cancer. By including high-fiber content foods in their diet and following intermittent fasting, people can significantly reduce their risk of developing this deadly disease. Colon cancer is one of the leading causes of cancer-related deaths worldwide, but with the implementation of these straightforward practices, individuals can take proactive measures to protect their health.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Consumption of Cucumbers and Tomatoes May Reduce Risk of Small Intestine Cancerous Polyps</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/daily-cucumbers-tomatoes-cancerous-polyps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Jun 2023 00:49:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/daily-cucumbers-tomatoes-cancerous-polyps/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Boston University have found that consuming 100 grams of cucumbers and 100 grams of tomatoes daily could help reduce the risk of small intestine cancerous polyps by up to 43%. The study, which was published in the Journal of Oncology, involved analyzing the dietary habits of over 2,500 participants, all of whom had previously undergone a colonoscopy.
The findings showed that participants who regularly consumed cucumber and tomato experienced a lesser incidence of small intestine polyps compared to those who did not eat these healthy vegetables.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reiki Sessions Have Very Positive Effects on Blood Sugar Levels and Blood Pressure</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reiki-sessions-positive-effects-blood-sugar-levels-blood-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reiki-sessions-positive-effects-blood-sugar-levels-blood-pressure/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Madrid have found that reiki sessions can have very positive effects on blood sugar levels and blood pressure. This new study could lead to a breakthrough in diabetes and hypertension treatment and prevention.
Reiki is a form of alternative medicine that originated in Japan. It involves placing the hands on or near the body to balance energy levels and promote relaxation. While there has been some debate over the scientific validity of reiki, the therapy has gained popularity in recent years as a complementary treatment for a variety of health conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
