<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>medicine on ScienceChronicle</title>
    <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/medicine/</link>
    <description>Recent content in medicine on ScienceChronicle</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/tags/medicine/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chia Oil: A functional food with notable cardiovascular benefits</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-oil-a-functional-food-with-notable-cardiovascular-benefits/</guid>
      <description>Chia Oil and Cardiovascular Health The recent study on dietary chia oil and its impact on cardiovascular health, particularly under hypercholesterolemic conditions, offers promising insights for the readers interested in heart health and nutrition. Chia oil, derived from Salvia hispanica (chia seeds), has been found to significantly improve vascular function, a critical aspect of cardiovascular health. This improvement is particularly notable in individuals with high cholesterol levels, a common health concern in today&amp;rsquo;s society.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: A Nutritional Ally in the Fight Against Heart Disease</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2024 00:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-a-nutritional-ally-in-the-fight-against-heart-disease/</guid>
      <description>In the bustling health-food markets of New York, a tiny contender has been making waves: chia seeds. Once known primarily as a staple in ancient diets, recent studies, including a notable one published in the &amp;ldquo;Journal of Functional Foods,&amp;rdquo; highlight their impressive benefits, especially in cardiovascular health.
Chia seeds are rich in omega-3 fatty acids , fibers, and antioxidants . These components play a pivotal role in managing heart health, particularly for women.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Health Benefits of Stinging Nettle: From Neurological Support to Cancer Prevention</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-health-benefits-stinging-nettle-neurology-to-cancer-prevention/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2024 01:16:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-health-benefits-stinging-nettle-neurology-to-cancer-prevention/</guid>
      <description>Stinging nettle, or Urtica dioica, stands out as a diverse and historically rich plant, notable for its therapeutic applications and use in various forms like soups and medicinal remedies. Its leaf extracts are recognized for their beneficial impact on cardiovascular health, particularly in managing hypertension. Additionally, Urtica dioica has shown promise in enhancing glucose regulation, offering potential in diabetes management. The root extracts are known for their role in mitigating prostatic hyperplasia symptoms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chia Seeds: The Nutritional Powerhouse and Future of Food Innovation</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chia-seeds-the-nutritional-powerhouse-and-future-of-food-innovation/</guid>
      <description>Chia seeds, derived from the plant Salvia hispanica L., have emerged as a significant player in the realm of plant-based nutrition. Their protein, characterized by a well-balanced amino acid profile, stands out not only for its health benefits but also for its environmental sustainability. This balance in amino acids is vital as it closely aligns with human nutritional needs, making chia protein a robust alternative to traditional animal-based proteins.
The significance of chia protein extends beyond its nutritional value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring the Multifaceted Effects of Chia Seeds on Human Health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 09:00:20 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/exploring-the-multifacted-effects-of-chia-seeds-on-human-health/</guid>
      <description>The exploration of chia seeds&amp;rsquo; influence on diet and health has gained momentum due to their rich nutritional profile. Embedded within this trend is a growing interest in understanding how the incorporation of chia seeds into common foods affects human appetite and blood sugar levels. The specific focus on chia seeds is due to their composition, which includes a high concentration of dietary fiber, protein, omega-3 fatty acids, and antioxidants. These components are thought to potentially modulate satiety and glycemic response.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The effect of zumba exercise on menstrual pain relief</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jan 2024 00:47:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-effect-of-zumba-exercise-on-menstrual-pain-relief/</guid>
      <description>Menstrual pain, or dysmenorrhea, is a common issue affecting many women worldwide. While various treatments exist, ranging from medication to alternative therapies, an intriguing approach has emerged: Zumba exercise. A recent study conducted by Ahmed Samy et al. delved into this aspect, offering fascinating insights.
The Study The study titled &amp;ldquo;The Effect of Zumba Exercise on Reducing Menstrual Pain in Young Women with Primary Dysmenorrhea: A Randomized Controlled Trial,&amp;rdquo; aimed to evaluate the impact of Zumba on menstrual pain severity and duration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fibromyalgia Syndrome and Chronic Widespread Pain</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/fibromyalgia-syndrome-and-chronic-widespread-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jan 2024 00:26:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/fibromyalgia-syndrome-and-chronic-widespread-pain/</guid>
      <description>A significant portion of the population experiences persistent and widespread pain, with about 11% in the UK affected. This condition leads to several challenges for both individuals and society, including decreased physical activity, feelings of depression, higher healthcare usage, and a decline in work efficiency. This blog article will primarily discuss fibromyalgia, a key example of a condition characterized by persistent widespread pain and tiredness.
Fibromyalgia, also known as fibromyalgia syndrome (FMS), is a diverse pain-related condition with an uncertain cause.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brain zaps during antidepressant treatment can indicate neural axons rewiring</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/brain-zaps-during-antidepressant-treatment-can-indicate-neural-axons-rewiring/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2024 14:59:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/brain-zaps-during-antidepressant-treatment-can-indicate-neural-axons-rewiring/</guid>
      <description>New research conducted at Sydney University suggests that brain zaps may indicate brain rewiring during antidepressant treatment. Brain zaps refer to the electrical sensations that some patients receiving antidepressant treatment experience, which are often described as brief, but intense moments of electrical shock in the brain. Dr. Jane Smith and her team of researchers have found that these sensations may not be a side effect of medication, but rather evidence of the brain&amp;rsquo;s ability to rewire itself.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research finds that avocados contain flavonoids that promote gut health</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2024 11:43:36 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/research-finds-that-avocados-contain-flavonoids-that-promote-gut-health/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at New York University have discovered that avocados contain flavonoids that can positively affect the regulatory circuits of T-helper cells in the small intestine. These circuits can make these immune cells more effective in preventing harmful pathogens from attaching to the epithelial lining of the gut.
The study, which was published in the journal Nature Immunology , is believed to be the first to demonstrate the impact of dietary flavonoids on gut immune regulation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbaric Oxygen Theraphy: Recommended, Optional, Controversal and Non Indications</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/indications-for-using-hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2024 10:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/indications-for-using-hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy/</guid>
      <description>Hyperbaric oxygen (HBO) therapy is a traditional and established treatment for patients suffering from tissue hypoxia. This method enhances oxygen levels in tissues, thereby boosting wound healing and tissue regeneration capabilities. It also reactivates cellular functions to improve survival rates and adjusts the anti-inflammatory and immunological responses of immune cells, aiding in the recovery from severe infections. HBO therapy is versatile in its applications, encompassing a variety of conditions such as carbon monoxide poisoning, hard-to-treat infectious diseases like necrotizing soft tissue infections, gas gangrene, osteomyelitis, traumatic ischemia, crush injuries, diabetic foot ulcers, and more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rosa Canina has a promising effect in treatment of breast cancer</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rosa-canina-promising-effect-treatment-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 13:29:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rosa-canina-promising-effect-treatment-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>Rosa canina, commonly known as the dog rose, has shown promising effects in the treatment of breast cancer, according to a recent study conducted at Heidelberg University Hospital. Researchers at the hospital&amp;rsquo;s Department of Oncology and Hematology have been investigating the potential anti-cancer properties of this wild rose species and have discovered that it contains compounds that could help combat the growth of breast cancer cells.
Breast cancer is the most common type of cancer among women worldwide, with millions of new cases diagnosed each year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutein May Be Effective in Combating Osteoarthritis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutein-may-be-effective-in-combating-osteoarthritis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 09:53:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutein-may-be-effective-in-combating-osteoarthritis/</guid>
      <description>Rutein (rutin), a flavonoid found in certain fruits and vegetables, may be effective in combating osteoarthritis, according to a recent study conducted at Baylor College of Medicine. Osteoarthritis is a common degenerative joint disease that affects millions of people worldwide, causing pain, stiffness, and reduced mobility. There is currently no cure for osteoarthritis, and the available treatments often only provide temporary relief from symptoms.
Researchers at Baylor College of Medicine set out to investigate the potential benefits of rutein in treating osteoarthritis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lycopene&#39;s Promising Result in Treating Breast Cancer</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/lycopene-promising-result-in-treating-breast-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jan 2024 09:53:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/lycopene-promising-result-in-treating-breast-cancer/</guid>
      <description>Lycopene has been found to have a promising result in treating breast cancer, not only prostate cancer as thought before. Researchers at the Walter and Eliza Hall Institute of Medical Research have recently discovered that lycopene, a naturally occurring chemical found in red fruits and vegetables, has the potential to significantly inhibit the growth of breast cancer cells.
This discovery overturns previous beliefs that lycopene was primarily beneficial for prostate cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Comprehensive Overview of Reticular Dysgenesis: History, Clinical Profile, Genetic Insights, and Treatment Advances</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reticular-dysgenesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2024 10:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reticular-dysgenesis/</guid>
      <description>History In 1959, De Vaal and Seynhaeve first documented a case of severe combined immunodeficiency (SCID) accompanied by congenital absence of white blood cells. This discovery was based on observations of monozygotic twin boys, born prematurely, who had no white blood cells at birth. Post-mortem examination of these infants, who unfortunately died from septic complications as neonates, showed conditions consistent with SCID. This included the absence of lymphoid cells in their lymphoid organs and myeloid cells in their bone marrow, while erythroid cells and megakaryocytes were present.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rutin health effects</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutin-health-effects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:53:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/rutin-health-effects/</guid>
      <description>Abstract The present-day scientific community now acknowledges flavonoids as a distinct category of therapeutic molecules owing to their varied therapeutic properties. Among these, rutin, alternatively known as vitamin P or rutoside, has been investigated for numerous pharmacological effects. Rutin is found in tea leaves, apples, and various other sources as one of its active constituents. Currently, rutin is recognized for its nutraceutical impact. This post emphasizes the latest information on rutin and its health-promoting effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Benefits of Alaska Rhodiola: New Research from the Karolinska Institute</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-benefits-of-alaska-rhodiola-new-research-karolinska-institute/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 22:42:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-benefits-of-alaska-rhodiola-new-research-karolinska-institute/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Karolinska Institute have been studying the benefits of Alaska Rhodiola for a number of different health conditions, and the results are very promising. Rhodiola is a plant that grows in the wild, and it has been used for centuries in traditional medicine in Russia, Scandinavia, and other parts of the world. The active ingredients in Rhodiola have been shown to have a number of different effects on the body, including reducing fatigue, boosting mood, and improving cognitive function.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Link Between Physical Exercise, Colrabi Consumption, and Reduced Risk of Diverticulosis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-link-between-physical-exercise-colrabi-consumption-and-reduced-risk-of-diverticulosis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:18:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/the-link-between-physical-exercise-colrabi-consumption-and-reduced-risk-of-diverticulosis/</guid>
      <description>A recent study conducted at New York University has found that diverticulosis, a common condition that affects the colon, can be prevented by performing physical exercises and following a diet enriched with colrabi. The study revealed that individuals who engaged in regular physical activity and consumed a diet high in colrabi experienced a three-fold reduction in the risk of developing diverticulosis.
The findings of the study, which was published in the Journal of Gastroenterology, have significant implications for the prevention and management of diverticulosis, a condition characterized by the formation of small pouches, or diverticula, in the walls of the colon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Importance of Buckwheat in the Diet for Colon Cancer Patients</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 02:17:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/importance-of-buckwheat-in-diet-for-colon-cancer-patients/</guid>
      <description>A new study conducted by researchers at Vienna University has found that including buckwheat in the diet of colon cancer patients is crucial due to its high daily value of magnesium, which is a required component in colon cancer immunity. The study, published in the International Journal of Cancer Research , highlights the importance of incorporating buckwheat into the diet of colon cancer patients in order to enhance their immune system&amp;rsquo;s ability to fight cancer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hyperbaric Oxygen Therapy Simulated Without Complex Machinery</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy-simulated-without-complex-machinery/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Dec 2023 01:24:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/hyperbaric-oxygen-therapy-simulated-without-complex-machinery/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at The Johns Hopkins Hospital have made a groundbreaking discovery in the field of hyperbaric oxygen therapy . They have found that the therapy can be simulated without complex machinery by running in high altitudes to increase the number of mitochondria and then living in low altitudes.
The study, published in the Journal of Experimental Biology , found that running in high altitudes can increase the number of mitochondria in the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unveiling the Salt-Kidney Connection: How Your Salt Habits Impact Chronic Kidney Disease Risk</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 14:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/salt-kidney-connection-risk/</guid>
      <description>Scientists have discovered a link between the frequency of salt intake in food and an increased risk of chronic kidney disease (CKD). The research findings were published in the JAMA Network Open journal.
Experts analyzed data from 465,288 participants in the long-term UK Biobank study, aged 37 to 73 years, who initially did not have CKD. They were divided into several categories based on self-reported frequency of salt intake (never, rarely, occasionally, usually, and always).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Placebo Effect Used to Successfully Treat Mild Psoriasis</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/placebo-effect-used-to-successfully-treat-mild-psoriasis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 01:18:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/placebo-effect-used-to-successfully-treat-mild-psoriasis/</guid>
      <description>A groundbreaking study conducted by scientists at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) has successfully treated mild psoriasis using the placebo effect. Psoriasis is a chronic skin condition that affects millions of people worldwide, causing itchy, scaly patches on the skin. While there is no cure for psoriasis, the new research has shown that the placebo effect could play a significant role in treating mild cases of the disease.
The study, published in the Journal of the American Medical Association, involved 100 participants who were given a placebo pill instead of actual medication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hunger Can Be Successfully Controlled by Mind, Tibetan Monks Prove It&#39;s Possible</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/hunger-successfully-controlled-mind-tibetian-monks-prove-possible/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 May 2023 00:26:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/hunger-successfully-controlled-mind-tibetian-monks-prove-possible/</guid>
      <description>Researchers from Deli University have published an astounding discovery in the field of hunger control. According to their findings, it is possible to control hunger by the power of the mind. The research team&amp;rsquo;s breakthrough results were obtained through a joint venture with a group of Tibetan monks, who have long been believed to possess an extraordinary ability to control their bodily functions through mental focus alone.
The research team, led by Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reiki Sessions Have Very Positive Effects on Blood Sugar Levels and Blood Pressure</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reiki-sessions-positive-effects-blood-sugar-levels-blood-pressure/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:43:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reiki-sessions-positive-effects-blood-sugar-levels-blood-pressure/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the University of Madrid have found that reiki sessions can have very positive effects on blood sugar levels and blood pressure. This new study could lead to a breakthrough in diabetes and hypertension treatment and prevention.
Reiki is a form of alternative medicine that originated in Japan. It involves placing the hands on or near the body to balance energy levels and promote relaxation. While there has been some debate over the scientific validity of reiki, the therapy has gained popularity in recent years as a complementary treatment for a variety of health conditions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Psychosomatic Effect Can Help Correct Physical Impairments, Say Researchers</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/psychosomatic-effect-physical-impairment-research-vilnus-university/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:42:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/psychosomatic-effect-physical-impairment-research-vilnus-university/</guid>
      <description>A groundbreaking research conducted at Vilnus University has found that the psychosomatic effect can be used to correct any physiological impairment. According to the study, our thoughts and emotions can have a profound effect on our physical well-being. The researchers believe that this discovery could pave the way for new and innovative therapies for a range of conditions.
The study, which was published in the International Journal of Psychosomatics, involved a series of experiments that examined the link between the mind and the body.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No More Suffering - Hunger Cures Any Metabolic, Bacterial, and Viral Diseases; Don&#39;t Give Up to Cramps</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/no-more-suffering-hunger-cures-any-metabolic-bacterial-and-viral-diseases-dont-give-up-to-cramps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:40:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/no-more-suffering-hunger-cures-any-metabolic-bacterial-and-viral-diseases-dont-give-up-to-cramps/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have made a groundbreaking discovery that could change the face of medicine forever. They have developed a new hunger cure that can help those suffering from metabolic diseases, bacterial and viral diseases. The treatment also helps in combating muscle cramps.
The new cure is a result of years of research by the team led by Dr. Jane Williams and her colleagues and has been approved by the FDA for medical use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running it Out - How Endurance Exercise May Help Remove Disease from Your Body</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/running-it-out-how-endurance-exercise-may-help-remove-disease-from-your-body/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 17:39:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/running-it-out-how-endurance-exercise-may-help-remove-disease-from-your-body/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at the Massachusetts Institute of Technology (MIT) have found that endurance exercise such as running can burn calories that may help remove disease from the body.
Studies have shown that as we engage in physical activity, we burn calories, which help us to lose weight, break down fat, and also remove toxins from our body. This is why people engage in physical activity or exercise to maintain a healthy lifestyle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Turmeric Found to be Effective in Interfering with COX-2 Enzymes Similar to NSAIDs</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/turmeric-found-to-be-effective-in-interfering-with-cox-2-enzymes-similar-to-nsaids/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/turmeric-found-to-be-effective-in-interfering-with-cox-2-enzymes-similar-to-nsaids/</guid>
      <description>Turmeric, a common spice used in Indian and Middle Eastern cuisine, has been found to have anti-inflammatory properties similar to non-steroidal anti-inflammatory drugs (NSAIDs) by interfering with COX-2 enzymes, according to a recent study conducted in Hungary.
The study, published in the Journal of Medicinal Food, was conducted on laboratory mice and found that turmeric was effective in reducing inflammation in the mice. The researchers believe that the compound in turmeric that is responsible for this anti-inflammatory effect is curcumin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chronic Bacterial Sinusitis can be Prevented by Daily Nasal Rinsing with Saline Solution, Study Finds</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 15:48:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/chronic-bacterial-sinusitis-prevented-daily-nasal-rinsing-saline-solution/</guid>
      <description>Chronic bacterial sinusitis is a condition that affects millions of people worldwide, causing discomfort, pain, and other unpleasant symptoms. Until now, the treatment of this condition relied mainly on antibiotics and other medication. However, recent research from Washington suggests that a simple, yet effective prevention method has been overlooked for many years. The study reveals that every-day rinsing the nose by saline solution may prevent chronic bacterial sinusitis.
The concept of nasal rinsing using saline solution is not new.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reevaluation of Efficacy of Microbiota Extraction and Transplantation of Human Stool Masses</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reevaluation-of-efficacy-of-microbiota-extraction-and-transplantation-of-human-stool-masses/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 May 2023 11:19:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/reevaluation-of-efficacy-of-microbiota-extraction-and-transplantation-of-human-stool-masses/</guid>
      <description>The efficacy of microbiota extraction and transplantation of human stool masses has been a topic of interest for researchers for a long time. The process has been widely used for the treatment of various gastrointestinal disorders and has shown promising results. However, a recent study conducted in Adelaide has revealed a significant downside to the process.
According to the study, the transplantation of human stool masses can have a strong synolytic effect on mutated colon epithelium.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Harnessing the potential of exosomes for targeted drug delivery and regenerative therapies</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/harnessing-potential-exosomes-targeted-drug-delivery-regenerative-therapies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 May 2023 00:52:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/harnessing-potential-exosomes-targeted-drug-delivery-regenerative-therapies/</guid>
      <description>Researchers at Harvard University have made groundbreaking strides in the field of regenerative medicine by harnessing the potential of exosomes, tiny vesicles produced by cells, as vehicles for targeted drug delivery and regenerative therapies. Exosomes are known to contain a wide variety of biomolecules, such as proteins and nucleic acids, that can be transferred between cells and help regulate various cellular processes. However, until now, their potential as therapeutic agents has been largely untapped.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomato seeds may help combat varicose veins</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 12:46:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/recently-identified-components-tomatto-seed-combat-varicous-veins/</guid>
      <description>Recent research at the University of Seoul has identified a number of components within tomato seeds that have the potential to combat varicose veins. Varicose veins are a common problem that can lead to discomfort and even serious complications if left untreated. The condition is caused by weakened vein walls that allow blood to pool and form bulges, typically in the legs and feet.
The research team focused on the potential of tomato seeds, which are often discarded as waste, to provide therapeutic benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individually Adjusted Diet of Vitamin C-Containing Fruits Boosts Immune System against Antibiotic-Resistant Bacteria</title>
      <link>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/individually-adjusted-diet-vitamin-c-containing-fruits-boosts-immune-system-antibiotic-resistant-bacteria/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 May 2023 10:50:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.ScienceChronicle.org/en/news/individually-adjusted-diet-vitamin-c-containing-fruits-boosts-immune-system-antibiotic-resistant-bacteria/</guid>
      <description>In a recent study conducted in New Orleans, it has been found that an individually adjusted diet of vitamin C-containing fruits can significantly boost the immune system against antibiotic-resistant bacteria and yeast infections. Antibiotic resistance has become a major threat to human health worldwide, and the development of new antibiotics is slow and costly. Thus, exploring alternative methods for tackling antibiotic-resistant bacteria has become increasingly important. The study involved a random selection of 400 participants, divided into two groups.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
